<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>TryHackMe - &quot;HTB with walkthroughs&quot;</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tryhackme-htb-with-walkthroughs/17979</link>
    <description>I came across this in the sponsored section for the [upcoming xmas CTF](https://ctftime.org/event/926).
It&#39;s a breed between HTB and a walkthrough, splitting difficult tasks up into byte sized chunks. If you get stuck at one bit, it usually has a very descriptive task or a good hint that allows you to research into the subject and then continue on. Definitely a more linear path but a great learning experience in my opinion.
I&#39;ve learned a lot from the small amount of time I&#39;ve spent on there so I thought I&#39;d share the link with all of you guys and see what you guys think about it.

[https://tryhackme.com/](https://tryhackme.com/)

Plus, if you get stuck on a challenge and can&#39;t find the solution, you can ask for help in their discord channel and usually you receive it in a very short amount of time, definitely a great community for beginners who want to get into pentesting.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 22:14:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Pentesting</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tryhackme-htb-with-walkthroughs/17979.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>TryHackMe - &quot;HTB with walkthroughs&quot;</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[c0wm1lk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>After a bit more exploring I see they also have normal CTF problems, so it’s not all HTB styled but from what I’ve seen most of it is.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tryhackme-htb-with-walkthroughs/17979/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tryhackme-htb-with-walkthroughs/17979/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 22:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-17979-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tryhackme-htb-with-walkthroughs/17979.rss">TryHackMe - &quot;HTB with walkthroughs&quot;</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>TryHackMe - &quot;HTB with walkthroughs&quot;</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[c0wm1lk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I came across this in the sponsored section for the <a href="https://ctftime.org/event/926" rel="nofollow noopener">upcoming xmas CTF</a>.<br>
It’s a breed between HTB and a walkthrough, splitting difficult tasks up into byte sized chunks. If you get stuck at one bit, it usually has a very descriptive task or a good hint that allows you to research into the subject and then continue on. Definitely a more linear path but a great learning experience in my opinion.<br>
I’ve learned a lot from the small amount of time I’ve spent on there so I thought I’d share the link with all of you guys and see what you guys think about it.</p>
<p><a href="https://tryhackme.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://tryhackme.com/</a></p>
<p>Plus, if you get stuck on a challenge and can’t find the solution, you can ask for help in their discord channel and usually you receive it in a very short amount of time, definitely a great community for beginners who want to get into pentesting.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tryhackme-htb-with-walkthroughs/17979/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tryhackme-htb-with-walkthroughs/17979/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 21:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-17979-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tryhackme-htb-with-walkthroughs/17979.rss">TryHackMe - &quot;HTB with walkthroughs&quot;</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
