<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099</link>
    <description>I went to Defcon 2 years ago and had some interesting mixed feelings about the event. 

I’m not looking to slag off the event or my time there and equally not to try and convince others to go, I’m just keen to find out if I did the event in the correct way or didn’t fully embrace it.

Rather than writing a review that you can easily google let me provide my pros and cons. 


Pros:

Thousands of hackers/sec peeps in one place.
Interesting talks like the 101 track. 
Cool swag-  all of the goodies and hoodies I could ever want. (Cash only).
Cool venders from music to tech and swag (cash and card). 
Meet bloggers that I follow online (mubix) 
It’s in Vegas.. there is so much to see and do!!


Cons:

It should be called que con.. there was about 20 thousand people there.

The talks were good but you can’t get to all the ones you want to due to que’s everywhere. I met someone on the second day who said he don’t go to any and just watched them on youtube..

Vegas, It’s an expensive trip! 10 dollars per bottle of Budweiser! Plus hotel, plus flights I must have spent over £2k (GBP).

So the interesting people.. I didn’t meet anyone unfriendly but due to the amount of people I actually felt a bit on my own, I had little idea what I was meant to be doing.  Again I was told everyone feels this way the first time..

This year the event is over three locations.. I feel like I would be lost even more now. 

So have you guys been, what do you think of the event? 

Other than BSIDES  what events would you recommend?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 07:00:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Social</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-25</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for sharing your thoughts on this.</p>
<p>I didn’t go this year, but I think I will give it a go again next year.</p>
<p>Will just have to make more of an effort in the villages and maybe take part in a CTF.</p>
<p>Where did you spend most of your time in the end?</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/24</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 07:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-24</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mtx]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I went to DC this year as a first-timer and it was incredible for me. I stayed pretty fluid in my planning which allowed for interesting things to happen. Listened to some talks, was blown away by the villages, and most important met so many seriously cool people that I am making a point to keep in touch with. The parties were pretty lit and it’s a lot of fun to chat with my new friends about what parts I’m waiting on being shipped so that I can solder this and that onto my badge, etc etc. I hope to go each year now and eventually branch out to the other cons. There’s a lot that can happen at Defcon good and bad – if you put your neck out there and act polite, there are a lot of people who will help you, teach you, party with you and just hangout for a bit between whatever else you’re doing that day.</p>
<p>It is expensive . Pregame and don’t waste food worked for me. I wonder if you/OP went this year.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/23</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 22:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-23</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[yeezi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>No worries, I wasn’t implying that you did. I’m only pointing it out because that’s the basic gist of their theme this year.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 14:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-22</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Archangel9]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/yeezi">@yeezi</a> I never said I was pretending that, that is how everything will go. I just answered your question by giving you a possible outcome of what could happen. Never said it will happen. There are infinite possibilities and infinite amount of outcomes that could happen. Time will decide which outcome will happen.  If people from Defcon think pretending is the way to go, let them, it mainly means they are scared. And theoretically, if you think about it, they would pretend to say “this is how it will happen” in order to not lose customer revenue. If they accept the fact and do not pretend, then people will not want to come to Defcon anymore (by realizing it is a sideshow attraction(<a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/fxbg">@fxbg</a>)). So… in short, Defcon is stuck in a business stalemate right now.<br>
-Archangel</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 03:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-21</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[yeezi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>That’s all fine, I just don’t see the value in pretending that’s the way anything is going to go.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/20</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 16:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-20</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Archangel9]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/yeezi">@yeezi</a>  In short, if we used technology for good, then the human race would be evolving at it’s fastest rate to date. It would be a new revolution. If we continued  to use tech for good on a steady, but gradual increase we could expect most of the world’s problems fixed temporarily. Maybe even permanently, if there were enough minds at work collaborating together, along with having enough resources. Our future generations would benefit from their ancestor’s generations. You could probably achieve world peace (or at least a state of blissfulness), even though it might take a few generations. Everything has its time and place. I think most of us want tech to be used for good, but then realize the harsh truth - that it probably will not be.<br>
-Archangel</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/19</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 01:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-19</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[yeezi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>At the very least, a theme around, “What if we used technology for good?” - a blissful but ignorant question, especially since most of the people attending that conference are generally on the same page about how the powers that be are absolutely not using it (and never really will) for good.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/18</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-18</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[coffeina]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I have never been to this event. Maybe in the future I will be able to go there. This is because I would like to meet people and make many contacts with the industry. For now, I not even work in it, but in the future for sure.</p>
<p>As for the event itself, it is quite commercialized, but it is the case with every event that I was not only in the cybersecurity industry.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/17</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 07:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-17</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Archangel9]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/fxbg">@fxbg</a><br>
Sounds like what happened to most good things. Imagine what our future generations are going to be dealing with - that’s going to be hell.<br>
-Archangel</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 20:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-16</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for your feedback. Absolutely agree with this.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 15:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-15</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[yeezi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This will sound rather cynical, but here we go anyway:</p>
<p>The con itself, as in the people who attend, speak, run workshops, etc. are fantastic for the most part. I went last year and learned a ton that I was able to immediately bring back to my career. If you crave a community of people who probably think like you, enjoy the things you do and just love hacking in general, DEFCON is a great place to spend several days.</p>
<p>That said, DEFCON as an institution feels somewhat commercialized. Standing in the t-shirt lines, facing some degree of aggression from the Goons about where your badge is (God forbid you forget to take it out of your bag and put it on by accident) and only getting access to SkyTalks if you paid a premium (during which they ask for donations) definitely gives it a surface feel of being more of a business than a gathering around an ideology. I fully understand that they need to make money to keep the thing going and that if everyone walked in and participated without paying, it would die. But there’s something about it that just seems corporate.</p>
<p>All in all, it’s a lot of fun and is mostly what you make it. You don’t have to go to talks. In fact, if I went again, I would spend most of my time in villages and doing challenges - the talks can be found online later.</p>
<p>As a final note, I won’t be there this year for unrelated reasons, but the theme of this year is also an odd departure from the typical dystopian atmosphere that I like (and believe is increasingly becoming our reality). Personal preference, nothing more.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 14:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-14</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[fxbg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Defcon is still good, but because of the “villages” there are tons of shitty presentations and speakers now and sometimes the topics aren’t even about computer security at all. it has turned into a side show attraction instead of being a main attraction.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/13</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 14:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-13</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Very true.</p>
<p>I think if I was to go again I would just make more of an effort and get more involved.</p>
<p>The lockpick village was very cool…</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/12</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 12:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-12</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Archangel9]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/w4k3y">@W4K3Y</a> I have not gone to Defcon yet, plannng to go this year. In answer to your question though…<img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/thinking.png?v=9" title=":thinking:" class="emoji" alt=":thinking:"> Other than attending the  Defcon competitions, I would say looking into the Villages. Maybe workshops too if you want to start strengthening your weaknesses. It all depends on the person. Just remember: Knowledge is Power.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/11</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 14:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-11</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ghost]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve never been, but I’d love to go. I’ve never been to any hacking conventions, actually.</p>
<p>I’d like to not have government officials rummaging through my things though, but considering the last time I entered the United States, I don’t think that’d be possible.</p>
<p>ghost_</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/10</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 11:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-10</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Totally get this.</p>
<p>But to stay on track is there any Events that you believe are a must attend?</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/9</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 10:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-9</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Archangel9]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/w4k3y">@W4K3Y</a> Honestly, you got to get used to it. We are living in a cruel world. If you have not already, I suggest you take the red pill and see how deep the rabbit hole goes. The governments just follow orders. 2 good questions you should think about are:  “Who controls the government?” and “Who does it benefit?”.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/8</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 03:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-8</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yeah this is true.  Its just the fact they think its acceptable.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/7</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 11:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-7</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Archangel9]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/w4k3y">@W4K3Y</a><br>
That is why I always carry spares. Maybe carry a bunch of large paperclips with you, next time you go? Either that or bobby pins. <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> They can’t take the picks away, if they are not made. Plus I think we all know that they have much more to worry about than lock picks. <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p>
<p>-Archangel</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 22:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-6</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Well this just came across my Twitter (how timely)…</p>
<p>Hotel security guards are “raiding” rooms and<br>
Searching private belongings and confiscating lockpics.</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/e/e0794adf886ce3f8f5df40dc5a6e270259dd8905.png" class="site-icon" width="352" height="352">
      <a href="https://www.secjuice.com/defcon-hotel-security-fiasco/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc" title="05:45PM - 12 August 2018">Secjuice – 12 Aug 18</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:666/500;"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/0/0c6128c6e2e5072a138aa964e1be6efae4628985_2_666x500.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="666" height="500" srcset="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/0/0c6128c6e2e5072a138aa964e1be6efae4628985_2_666x500.jpeg, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/0/0c6128c6e2e5072a138aa964e1be6efae4628985.jpeg 1.5x, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/0/0c6128c6e2e5072a138aa964e1be6efae4628985.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/0/0c6128c6e2e5072a138aa964e1be6efae4628985_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.secjuice.com/defcon-hotel-security-fiasco/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Vegas - Where Thugs Come Into Your Room And Search Your Stuff</a></h3>

<p>Hotel thugs at DEFCON tried to burst into your room and photograph your things? You aren't alone, its happened to lots of DEFCON attendees.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/5</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 10:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-5</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yeah definitely!  Also it’s an excuse to get some exercise as it’s about a mile wall to leave your own hotel!</p>
<p>I’m getting the impression not many people I think forum attend many events:grinning:.</p>
<p>*Chuckled at Defcon was cancelled… <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/joy.png?v=9" title=":joy:" class="emoji" alt=":joy:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 20:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-4</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0xf00f77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Would love to attend defcon sometime, shame it gets cancelled every year <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<p>I generally watch the talks I am interested in, honestly Vegas in itself is an experience that gets a bit better with exposure and knowing where to stay. It’s very easy for Vegas itself to be quite overwhelming and costly.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 13:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-3</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dtm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Never been to any cons yet but I hear that you don’t go to Defcon for the talks.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 11:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I went to Defcon 2 years ago and had some interesting mixed feelings about the event.</p>
<p>I’m not looking to slag off the event or my time there and equally not to try and convince others to go, I’m just keen to find out if I did the event in the correct way or didn’t fully embrace it.</p>
<p>Rather than writing a review that you can easily google let me provide my pros and cons.</p>
<p>Pros:</p>
<p>Thousands of hackers/sec peeps in one place.<br>
Interesting talks like the 101 track.<br>
Cool swag-  all of the goodies and hoodies I could ever want. (Cash only).<br>
Cool venders from music to tech and swag (cash and card).<br>
Meet bloggers that I follow online (mubix)<br>
It’s in Vegas… there is so much to see and do!!</p>
<p>Cons:</p>
<p>It should be called que con… there was about 20 thousand people there.</p>
<p>The talks were good but you can’t get to all the ones you want to due to que’s everywhere. I met someone on the second day who said he don’t go to any and just watched them on youtube…</p>
<p>Vegas, It’s an expensive trip! 10 dollars per bottle of Budweiser! Plus hotel, plus flights I must have spent over £2k (GBP).</p>
<p>So the interesting people… I didn’t meet anyone unfriendly but due to the amount of people I actually felt a bit on my own, I had little idea what I was meant to be doing.  Again I was told everyone feels this way the first time…</p>
<p>This year the event is over three locations… I feel like I would be lost even more now.</p>
<p>So have you guys been, what do you think of the event?</p>
<p>Other than BSIDES  what events would you recommend?</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 10:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15099-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
