<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>About Anti-Fraud APP</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584</link>
    <description>
Recently, I&#39;ve observed an interesting phenomenon: even if you haven&#39;t downloaded a particular app and are using an Apple device within a sandbox environment, there&#39;s still the possibility of your website visits being detected, leading to some form of interaction. The good news, however, is that without downloading the app and while operating within the Apple ecosystem, they lack complete access to your information.

I&#39;m intrigued by the methods they employ. Is it through network operations, possibly orchestrated by the internet service provider? Or do they leverage automated processes, such as robots? I don&#39;t have any specific intentions or actions in mind regarding this matter. Instead, I approach this topic from an academic standpoint and as a professional, motivated by a commitment to privacy preservation.

sincere

HgTrojan</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 12:48:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>About Anti-Fraud APP</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 12:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-38584-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584.rss">About Anti-Fraud APP</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>About Anti-Fraud APP</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[HgTrojan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Recently, I’ve observed an interesting phenomenon: even if you haven’t downloaded a particular app and are using an Apple device within a sandbox environment, there’s still the possibility of your website visits being detected, leading to some form of interaction. The good news, however, is that without downloading the app and while operating within the Apple ecosystem, they lack complete access to your information.</p>
<p>I’m intrigued by the methods they employ. Is it through network operations, possibly orchestrated by the internet service provider? Or do they leverage automated processes, such as robots? I don’t have any specific intentions or actions in mind regarding this matter. Instead, I approach this topic from an academic standpoint and as a professional, motivated by a commitment to privacy preservation.</p>
<p>sincere</p>
<p>HgTrojan</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 12:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-38584-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584.rss">About Anti-Fraud APP</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
