<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Is there a way to un-obfuscate intentionally hidden text on websites?</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/is-there-a-way-to-un-obfuscate-intentionally-hidden-text-on-websites/20484</link>
    <description>hello first time posting here, i don&#39;t know much about hacking at all but i have a question regarding intentionally obfuscated text and if there is a way to reveal it. 
I follow a certain popular online multiplayer PC game and follow the development closely, the developers have a public-facing commits page that shows all commits in their scm (Plastic not Git). however some of these commits that get posted are obfuscated using random unicode, block elements specifically. theyre obviously intentionally hidden for a reason, but im curious if there is a way to un-obfuscate or see them another way somehow. ive tried the basic stuff like inspect element to no avail as im sure you guessed. if anyone knows of a way or can help in any form it&#39;d be very appreciated, thanks. :slight_smile:</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 23:09:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/is-there-a-way-to-un-obfuscate-intentionally-hidden-text-on-websites/20484.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Is there a way to un-obfuscate intentionally hidden text on websites?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/is-there-a-way-to-un-obfuscate-intentionally-hidden-text-on-websites/20484/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/is-there-a-way-to-un-obfuscate-intentionally-hidden-text-on-websites/20484/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 23:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-20484-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/is-there-a-way-to-un-obfuscate-intentionally-hidden-text-on-websites/20484.rss">Is there a way to un-obfuscate intentionally hidden text on websites?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is there a way to un-obfuscate intentionally hidden text on websites?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[chacealex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>hello first time posting here, i don’t know much about hacking at all but i have a question regarding intentionally obfuscated text and if there is a way to reveal it.<br>
I follow a certain popular online multiplayer PC game and follow the development closely, the developers have a public-facing commits page that shows all commits in their scm (Plastic not Git). however some of these commits that get posted are obfuscated using random unicode, block elements specifically. theyre obviously intentionally hidden for a reason, but im curious if there is a way to un-obfuscate or see them another way somehow. ive tried the basic stuff like inspect element to no avail as im sure you guessed. if anyone knows of a way or can help in any form it’d be very appreciated, thanks. <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/is-there-a-way-to-un-obfuscate-intentionally-hidden-text-on-websites/20484/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/is-there-a-way-to-un-obfuscate-intentionally-hidden-text-on-websites/20484/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 23:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-20484-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/is-there-a-way-to-un-obfuscate-intentionally-hidden-text-on-websites/20484.rss">Is there a way to un-obfuscate intentionally hidden text on websites?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
