<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kali live boot on macbook M1</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/kali-live-boot-on-macbook-m1/37623</link>
    <description>Hey fam, I&#39;ve been searching around but found nothing.
I&#39;ve tried to live boot Kali on my Macbook Pro (Intel i9), I did it but the trackpad, keyboard and wifi didn&#39;t worked. I read something about needing to install some drivers but how I&#39;ll use terminal, internet or anything without typing. I don&#39;t have a cable keyboard. I could get it If it was the only problem. I can only use the cursor with my dongle mouse.

I&#39;m getting back to M1 chip so the problem will be the same I&#39;m sure.

Do y&#39;all have any solution for runnin Kali live boot on M1 without tons of adapters (ext keyboard, mouse, wifi dongle)? I just want to plug and play.
Thank y&#39;all!!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 01:42:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Linux</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/kali-live-boot-on-macbook-m1/37623.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Kali live boot on macbook M1</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/kali-live-boot-on-macbook-m1/37623/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/kali-live-boot-on-macbook-m1/37623/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 01:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-37623-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/kali-live-boot-on-macbook-m1/37623.rss">Kali live boot on macbook M1</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Kali live boot on macbook M1</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0xbeep]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey fam, I’ve been searching around but found nothing.<br>
I’ve tried to live boot Kali on my Macbook Pro (Intel i9), I did it but the trackpad, keyboard and wifi didn’t worked. I read something about needing to install some drivers but how I’ll use terminal, internet or anything without typing. I don’t have a cable keyboard. I could get it If it was the only problem. I can only use the cursor with my dongle mouse.</p>
<p>I’m getting back to M1 chip so the problem will be the same I’m sure.</p>
<p>Do y’all have any solution for runnin Kali live boot on M1 without tons of adapters (ext keyboard, mouse, wifi dongle)? I just want to plug and play.<br>
Thank y’all!!</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/kali-live-boot-on-macbook-m1/37623/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/kali-live-boot-on-macbook-m1/37623/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 01:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-37623-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/kali-live-boot-on-macbook-m1/37623.rss">Kali live boot on macbook M1</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
