<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Shameless self-promotion: Ops tools for hackers</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/shameless-self-promotion-ops-tools-for-hackers/2187</link>
    <description>Hello fellow 0x00sec-ers! 

I just had a good talk with @pry0cc about doing some posts within my specialty, operations. I firmly believe that a strong foundation in operations is essential for any aspiring hacker, as you need to understand the systems you&#39;re breaking. To that end, I will be cross-posting articles I write on my own blog here with a special focus on using ops tools for evil. 

This first article (in what _might_ be a series) is less evil, still fun. I used our very own pet chatbot, MissMoneyPenney, to demonstrate two really cool tools, Consul and consul-template. Check it out, let me know your thoughts, and tell me how you might want to use something like Consul and consul-template for bad things.

http://blog.fraq.io/tech/consul-template/</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 15:04:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Operations</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/shameless-self-promotion-ops-tools-for-hackers/2187.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Shameless self-promotion: Ops tools for hackers</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[fraq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello fellow 0x00sec-ers!</p>
<p>I just had a good talk with <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/pry0cc">@pry0cc</a> about doing some posts within my specialty, operations. I firmly believe that a strong foundation in operations is essential for any aspiring hacker, as you need to understand the systems you’re breaking. To that end, I will be cross-posting articles I write on my own blog here with a special focus on using ops tools for evil.</p>
<p>This first article (in what <em>might</em> be a series) is less evil, still fun. I used our very own pet chatbot, MissMoneyPenney, to demonstrate two really cool tools, Consul and consul-template. Check it out, let me know your thoughts, and tell me how you might want to use something like Consul and consul-template for bad things.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.fraq.io/tech/consul-template/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://blog.fraq.io/tech/consul-template/</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/shameless-self-promotion-ops-tools-for-hackers/2187/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/shameless-self-promotion-ops-tools-for-hackers/2187/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 15:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-2187-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/shameless-self-promotion-ops-tools-for-hackers/2187.rss">Shameless self-promotion: Ops tools for hackers</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
