<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Looking for advice</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/looking-for-advice/27661</link>
    <description>im looking for advice anyways, long story short, im in  the midst of a career change im 26.  How do i break into software dev or security effectively i have made a couple of projects. but i need real world experience, i have a  good foundation of computers and programming so wondering what others did in order to let their career take off.... give or take i just want to get out of my job ASAP . I have a manual labour job ATM,  I&#39;m not looking for handouts more so constructive criticisms of what i should do if i need a job in IT. if it helps im accepted for cs next year in oct.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 05:26:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/looking-for-advice/27661.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Looking for advice</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/looking-for-advice/27661/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/looking-for-advice/27661/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 05:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-27661-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/looking-for-advice/27661.rss">Looking for advice</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for advice</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoGraphi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>im looking for advice anyways, long story short, im in  the midst of a career change im 26.  How do i break into software dev or security effectively i have made a couple of projects. but i need real world experience, i have a  good foundation of computers and programming so wondering what others did in order to let their career take off… give or take i just want to get out of my job ASAP . I have a manual labour job ATM,  I’m not looking for handouts more so constructive criticisms of what i should do if i need a job in IT. if it helps im accepted for cs next year in oct.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/looking-for-advice/27661/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/looking-for-advice/27661/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 05:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-27661-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/looking-for-advice/27661.rss">Looking for advice</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
