<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacking an old freebsd</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/hacking-an-old-freebsd/30113</link>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m new to this site, and this is my first question.
I started hacking recently, and I started roaming around in some servers. One of those is an old freebsd server ( FreeBSD 9.0). I got in and escalated my privileges to root, and now I&#39;m stuck.
Thing is, the default pkg manager is not working, for how outdated the os version is (2013). Updating it isn&#39;t an option because i might break some dependencies and the sysadmin might notice my activities.
So I&#39;m stuck with a basic install, without nmap or anything else.
Then I tried transferring some packages to it, and compiling them to no avail, as the os hasn&#39;t the required dependencies (e.g. compiling nmap, directly from the github source).
I thought of pivoting with a meterpreter shell, but the system has problems running elf files even using &#39;&#39;brandelf -t linux ...&#39;&#39; . I tried pivoting again with an ssh dynamic port forwarding (carefully setting up freebsd to accept it) but the socks4 proxy doesn&#39;t work, for some obscure reason.
Then I used sshuttle, but again the os is missing some dipendencies.

And now I find myself unable to pivot to the other intranet machines.
Someone knows how to help me in pivoting from this server?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 18:50:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/hacking-an-old-freebsd/30113.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hacking an old freebsd</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/hacking-an-old-freebsd/30113/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/hacking-an-old-freebsd/30113/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 18:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-30113-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/hacking-an-old-freebsd/30113.rss">Hacking an old freebsd</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking an old freebsd</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[fugna]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, I’m new to this site, and this is my first question.<br>
I started hacking recently, and I started roaming around in some servers. One of those is an old freebsd server ( FreeBSD 9.0). I got in and escalated my privileges to root, and now I’m stuck.<br>
Thing is, the default pkg manager is not working, for how outdated the os version is (2013). Updating it isn’t an option because i might break some dependencies and the sysadmin might notice my activities.<br>
So I’m stuck with a basic install, without nmap or anything else.<br>
Then I tried transferring some packages to it, and compiling them to no avail, as the os hasn’t the required dependencies (e.g. compiling nmap, directly from the github source).<br>
I thought of pivoting with a meterpreter shell, but the system has problems running elf files even using ‘‘brandelf -t linux …’’ . I tried pivoting again with an ssh dynamic port forwarding (carefully setting up freebsd to accept it) but the socks4 proxy doesn’t work, for some obscure reason.<br>
Then I used sshuttle, but again the os is missing some dipendencies.</p>
<p>And now I find myself unable to pivot to the other intranet machines.<br>
Someone knows how to help me in pivoting from this server?</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/hacking-an-old-freebsd/30113/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/hacking-an-old-freebsd/30113/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 18:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-30113-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/hacking-an-old-freebsd/30113.rss">Hacking an old freebsd</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
