<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XORCry - a simple python ransomware</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148</link>
    <description>------------------

Before we start here is the full code if you want to check it yourself [Xorcry](https://github.com/amaitou/Xorcry/blob/main/xorcry.py)

# Xorcry

Xorcry is open-source ransomware written in python3 to explain how actually ransomware or a crypter with a given cryptography algorithm works.

# Why?

as a curious person, I really love to understand how things get to work deeply, and one of the questions that I&#39;ve been asking for a long time was how does the ransomware work? after a lot of disappointing research to give my question a clear answer, I started diving into cryptography algorithms and malware understanding, so without any further ado let&#39;s leave this boring introduction aside a bit and go with the cool part.

## How Does Xorcry Work?

first of all, you must make sure that I did this tool only for educational purposes, secondly, if you are a cryptographer you will find this write-up boring you.

there are a lot of cryptography algorithms you can use to make ransomware but I&#39;m not going to explain them for the reason that I didn&#39;t use any known crypto algorithm, in fact, what I  did is reading files as binary and xor them with a given key and this is what called **xor cipher**, but wait, I said **xor cipher** hmmm what is this? well, this will be our next topic.

## Xor Cipher

I&#39;ll assume that you have a background in Logic gates and what are they, but if you don&#39;t I  want you to take a deep look at this
article from Wikipedia :

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logic_gate

well as you noticed  In the **xor** operation, the output is true when the inputs differ. In other words, the **xor** operation means either one but not both or none.

Below you can find the principles of **xor** (^ denotes the **xor** operation):

```
0 ^ 0 = 0
0 ^ 1 = 1
1 ^ 0 = 1
1 ^ 1 = 0
```

**xor** cipher employs the **xor** logical operation in order to encrypt data. First, a random key is generated or chosen by you. Then, the **xor** operation is performed using the key so that encrypted data is created. In order to decrypt, the same key should be used and the **xor** operation should be run again.

**xor** operation uses the same key for both encryption and decryption operations. That is why it is known as symmetric encryption.

## Code Explaining

before covering the code explanation, I&#39;ll assume again that you have the basics of the programming language Python in order to understand The rest of the code because I will cover only the most important function which is :

```python
def encrypt(self , f) :
		&#39;&#39;&#39; If the file&#39;s extension is one of the lists declared above then start XoRing &#39;&#39;&#39;
		if self.check_ex(f) :
			try :
				with open(f , mode = &quot;rb&quot;) as _file :
					rd = bytearray(_file.read())
				for n , v in enumerate(rd) :
					rd[n] = v ^ self.key
				with open(f , mode = &quot;wb&quot;) as _nf :
					_nf.write(rd)
				&#39;&#39;&#39; This exception is especially for file permissions &#39;&#39;&#39;
			except :
				pass
```

the first line I will talk about is the operation of reading the file we want to encrypt in binary mode and declaring a variable where we will put the binary data as a list using the built-in function _bytearray()_, I found this article useful for those who want to understand how does the *bytearray()* work :

https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/python-bytearray-function/

after that, there is a for loop to edit the list by performing the **xor** operation for each element in the list with the given key and finally rewrite the file we have opened previously with the new encrypted data.

## Contact Me

For Any Questions, You Can Find Me on This Platform:

* [Twitter][_1]
* [Instagram][_2]

[_1]: https://twitter.com/amait0u
[_2]: https://www.instagram.com/amait0u

# Disclaimer
This program must be used for legal purposes! I am not responsible for anything you do with it.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 11:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Malware</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>XORCry - a simple python ransomware</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 121 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 08:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-31148-9</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148.rss">XORCry - a simple python ransomware</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>XORCry - a simple python ransomware</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[trakeq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I, as a programmer with 0 experience and myself from Russia, was shocked at how ingenious it was, great respect for the person who created this topic and explained how it works, to be honest, I didn’t know about this at all)</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/8</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-31148-8</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148.rss">XORCry - a simple python ransomware</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>XORCry - a simple python ransomware</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[LambdaCalculus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="AmineLelouche" data-post="1" data-topic="31148">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img loading="lazy" alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://0x00sec.org/user_avatar/0x00sec.org/aminelelouche/40/13956_2.png" class="avatar"> AmineLelouche:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>as a curious person, I really love to understand how things get to work deeply, and one of the questions that I’ve been asking for a long time was how does the ransomware work?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Oh yeah, that’s how Richard Feynman believes people learn best; he is credited with stating that “what I cannot create, I do not understand.” I looked through the source code, and I like it <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/smiley.png?v=12" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"> — it’s short and simple, how software should be made.</p>
<p>So I’m looking at your encryption method:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-python">	def encrypt(self , f) :

		''' If the file's extension is one of the list declared above then start XoRing '''

		if self.check_ex(f) :

			try :
				with open(f , mode = "rb") as _file :
					rd = bytearray(_file.read())
				for n , v in enumerate(rd) :
					rd[n] = v ^ self.key
				with open(f , mode = "wb") as _nf :
					_nf.write(rd)

				''' This exception is especially for file permissions '''

			except :
				pass
</code></pre>
<p>And like you said (and as the title of your malware implies), it’s using a basic XOR cipher to encrypt files on the filesystem; fun stuff. I think what you could do to improve it (if you want) is try to make a pseudo-<a href="https://youtu.be/FlIG3TvQCBQ" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">one time pad</a> to encrypt each file.</p>
<p>So I would approach it by using a calculus series to generate an irrational number. Here’s an example:</p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/1/8/183233cd4e204ad52ff7e7513ea2afcf7cc8176e.png" alt="equation" data-base62-sha1="3s314CSa51UtsKwdbKGg6t1fRJY" width="328" height="78"></p>
<p>and then set the function’s “k” to generate a number large enough where its number of digits match the filesize (in bytes ofc <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=12" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"> ). Then you can split the number into individual digits and XOR each byte with its corresponding digit (this may take up a lot of computing power lol). If you need to decrypt, you can just XOR again for each byte to the function’s corresponding digit place.</p>
<p>Just my silly, unsolicited advices if you want to add to Python ransomware <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=12" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"> — also if I didn’t explain it well I’m sorry; will be happy to clarify it if you want! <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/smiley.png?v=12" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/5</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 17:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-31148-5</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148.rss">XORCry - a simple python ransomware</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>XORCry - a simple python ransomware</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[AmineLelouche]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I know that, that’s why I wrote that “simple” word within the title of the article buddy <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=12" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 20:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-31148-4</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148.rss">XORCry - a simple python ransomware</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>XORCry - a simple python ransomware</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[c0z]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yeah I know right? I’ll bet he doesn’t know that there’s only 256 possible ways to decrypt the data given the ciphertext.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 14:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-31148-3</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148.rss">XORCry - a simple python ransomware</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>XORCry - a simple python ransomware</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ok_ko]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Dang thats amazing I never heard of Xor Cipher let alone ever thought of using logic gates for encryption</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 05:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-31148-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148.rss">XORCry - a simple python ransomware</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>XORCry - a simple python ransomware</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[AmineLelouche]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <hr>
<p>Before we start here is the full code if you want to check it yourself <a href="https://github.com/amaitou/Xorcry/blob/main/xorcry.py" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Xorcry</a></p>
<h1>
<a name="xorcry-1" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#xorcry-1"></a>Xorcry</h1>
<p>Xorcry is open-source ransomware written in python3 to explain how actually ransomware or a crypter with a given cryptography algorithm works.</p>
<h1>
<a name="why-2" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#why-2"></a>Why?</h1>
<p>as a curious person, I really love to understand how things get to work deeply, and one of the questions that I’ve been asking for a long time was how does the ransomware work? after a lot of disappointing research to give my question a clear answer, I started diving into cryptography algorithms and malware understanding, so without any further ado let’s leave this boring introduction aside a bit and go with the cool part.</p>
<h2>
<a name="how-does-xorcry-work-3" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#how-does-xorcry-work-3"></a>How Does Xorcry Work?</h2>
<p>first of all, you must make sure that I did this tool only for educational purposes, secondly, if you are a cryptographer you will find this write-up boring you.</p>
<p>there are a lot of cryptography algorithms you can use to make ransomware but I’m not going to explain them for the reason that I didn’t use any known crypto algorithm, in fact, what I  did is reading files as binary and xor them with a given key and this is what called <strong>xor cipher</strong>, but wait, I said <strong>xor cipher</strong> hmmm what is this? well, this will be our next topic.</p>
<h2>
<a name="xor-cipher-4" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#xor-cipher-4"></a>Xor Cipher</h2>
<p>I’ll assume that you have a background in Logic gates and what are they, but if you don’t I  want you to take a deep look at this<br>
article from Wikipedia :</p>
<aside class="onebox wikipedia" data-onebox-src="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logic_gate">
  <header class="source">

      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logic_gate" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">en.wikipedia.org</a>
  </header>

  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:220/183;"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/6/1/61fc611633ed143c1bb0782106919635e4a559bc.png" class="thumbnail" width="220" height="183"></div>

<h3><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logic_gate" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Logic gate</a></h3>

<p>A logic gate is an idealized or physical device implementing a Boolean function, a logical operation performed on one or more binary inputs that produces a single binary output. Depending on the context, the term may refer to an ideal logic gate, one that has for instance zero rise time and unlimited fan-out, or it may refer to a non-ideal physical device (see Ideal and real op-amps for comparison).
 Logic gates are primarily implemented using diodes or transistors acting as electronic switches, ...</p>

  </article>

  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>

  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>well as you noticed  In the <strong>xor</strong> operation, the output is true when the inputs differ. In other words, the <strong>xor</strong> operation means either one but not both or none.</p>
<p>Below you can find the principles of <strong>xor</strong> (^ denotes the <strong>xor</strong> operation):</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">0 ^ 0 = 0
0 ^ 1 = 1
1 ^ 0 = 1
1 ^ 1 = 0
</code></pre>
<p><strong>xor</strong> cipher employs the <strong>xor</strong> logical operation in order to encrypt data. First, a random key is generated or chosen by you. Then, the <strong>xor</strong> operation is performed using the key so that encrypted data is created. In order to decrypt, the same key should be used and the <strong>xor</strong> operation should be run again.</p>
<p><strong>xor</strong> operation uses the same key for both encryption and decryption operations. That is why it is known as symmetric encryption.</p>
<h2>
<a name="code-explaining-5" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#code-explaining-5"></a>Code Explaining</h2>
<p>before covering the code explanation, I’ll assume again that you have the basics of the programming language Python in order to understand The rest of the code because I will cover only the most important function which is :</p>
<pre><code class="lang-python">def encrypt(self , f) :
		''' If the file's extension is one of the lists declared above then start XoRing '''
		if self.check_ex(f) :
			try :
				with open(f , mode = "rb") as _file :
					rd = bytearray(_file.read())
				for n , v in enumerate(rd) :
					rd[n] = v ^ self.key
				with open(f , mode = "wb") as _nf :
					_nf.write(rd)
				''' This exception is especially for file permissions '''
			except :
				pass
</code></pre>
<p>the first line I will talk about is the operation of reading the file we want to encrypt in binary mode and declaring a variable where we will put the binary data as a list using the built-in function <em>bytearray()</em>, I found this article useful for those who want to understand how does the <em>bytearray()</em> work :</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric" data-onebox-src="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/python-bytearray-function/">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/a/0/a01616f468667fe9662cea046a0953b694ef48fb.png" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">

      <a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/python-bytearray-function/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc" title="12:00AM - 30 July 2018">GeeksforGeeks – 30 Jul 18</a>
  </header>

  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/c/d/cd01aa8f465e6ee997f12201c3368600efd6a6ed.png" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="200" height="200">

<h3><a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/python-bytearray-function/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Python | bytearray() function - GeeksforGeeks</a></h3>

  <p>A Computer Science portal for geeks. It contains well written, well thought and well explained computer science and programming articles, quizzes and practice/competitive programming/company interview Questions.</p>


  </article>

  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>

  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>after that, there is a for loop to edit the list by performing the <strong>xor</strong> operation for each element in the list with the given key and finally rewrite the file we have opened previously with the new encrypted data.</p>
<h2>
<a name="contact-me-6" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#contact-me-6"></a>Contact Me</h2>
<p>For Any Questions, You Can Find Me on This Platform:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/amait0u" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/amait0u" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Instagram</a></li>
</ul>
<h1>
<a name="disclaimer-7" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#disclaimer-7"></a>Disclaimer</h1>
<p>This program must be used for legal purposes! I am not responsible for anything you do with it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 16:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-31148-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/xorcry-a-simple-python-ransomware/31148.rss">XORCry - a simple python ransomware</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
