<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Questions - 0x00sec - The Home of the Hacker</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/c/support/52</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Questions&#39; category Asking questions or not knowing something is not a bad thing on 0x00sec, in fact its something very critical to learning. However, &lt;strong&gt;asking in the correct way is very important&lt;/strong&gt;. Posts like &quot;Plz help me hax my sk00l pls&quot; are considered spammy, and will be &lt;strong&gt;aggresively&lt;/strong&gt; deleted. Please realise that nobody here owes you anything, it is up to you to gain respect and ask correctly. You do not deserve help, however people here are happy to help. </description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 19:27:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/c/support/52.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Web pentesting noob qustion</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[ibada]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Beginner Guides</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>if want to find vuln in somewebsite what are the Steps u do ?</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/web-pentesting-noob-qustion/40303">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/web-pentesting-noob-qustion/40303</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 19:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-40303</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/web-pentesting-noob-qustion/40303.rss">Web pentesting noob qustion</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>From full stack web developer to hacker?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pylot]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h1><a name="transitioning-1" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#transitioning-1"></a>Transitioning</h1>
<p>I want to transition more into cyber security, I am currently a professional full stack developer thats fairly proficient in a lot of different web technologies. I recently got a degree in cyber security and want to get more into it.</p>
<p>I played around with common exploits like XSRF, SSRF, CSRF, XSS, SQLI, USQLI, LFI, Directory Traversal, HTTP Polution, and a few other attacks on my private network and have a fairly good understand of how these all work.</p>
<p>I downloaded a weba pp that is purpesefully vulnerable and what able to execute just about every attack vector on my list, but now I am not sure what to do. I’d like to get more into bug bounties, and find some security related issues on sites, to get paid for that. But I’m not quite sure where to start, I’ll find a site, and test for these attack points, but rarely find anything.</p>
<p>I tried dorking but even sites that seem to have some secrity issues, I can’t manage to get much out of them too. I’d love advice on how to get better, or how to actually succesfully pen-test a site with permission ofc.</p>
<p>I have the development side down, and I feel like that is a great start, but I want to grow and become just as proficient in cyber security as i am with development here.</p>
<p>Thanks everyone!!!</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/from-full-stack-web-developer-to-hacker/40063">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/from-full-stack-web-developer-to-hacker/40063</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 23:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-40063</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/from-full-stack-web-developer-to-hacker/40063.rss">From full stack web developer to hacker?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How can it be determined whether a device in the local network is UP or not?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[bob_marley]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>How can it be determined whether a device in the local network is UP or not?</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-can-it-be-determined-whether-a-device-in-the-local-network-is-up-or-not/39457">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-can-it-be-determined-whether-a-device-in-the-local-network-is-up-or-not/39457</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 18:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-39457</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-can-it-be-determined-whether-a-device-in-the-local-network-is-up-or-not/39457.rss">How can it be determined whether a device in the local network is UP or not?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>SYN/ACK response to all ports freezes. What is the reason for this?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[bob_marley]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>SYN/ACK response to all ports freezes. What is the reason for this?</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/syn-ack-response-to-all-ports-freezes-what-is-the-reason-for-this/39456">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/syn-ack-response-to-all-ports-freezes-what-is-the-reason-for-this/39456</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 17:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-39456</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/syn-ack-response-to-all-ports-freezes-what-is-the-reason-for-this/39456.rss">SYN/ACK response to all ports freezes. What is the reason for this?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How botnet was used to make supercomputer?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Boyliam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>How botnet was used to make supercomputer?</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-botnet-was-used-to-make-supercomputer/39013">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-botnet-was-used-to-make-supercomputer/39013</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 12:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-39013</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-botnet-was-used-to-make-supercomputer/39013.rss">How botnet was used to make supercomputer?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Shaking Table; Raspberry || Arduino || ESP32 etc. which one?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[intelligenzia]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I am a graduate student in Structural &amp; Earthquake Engineering. My research area is vibration control. I mean structural control systems like active and passive damping systems.</p>
<p>I want to do a shaking table which takes the earthquake acceleration datas from a txt file.<br>
Then it will shake the table with earhquake datas i mean it will animate the earthquake on the table.<br>
This was the first stage.</p>
<p>At the second stage I want to contruct two miniatur buildings and put them on the shaking table.<br>
The 1st building model has a passive damping system like seismic isolators.<br>
The 2nd building model has an active damping system so i need sensors which is going to give me the displacements of storeys and this sensors will send the values to the computer. And computer algorithm will activate the controlling elements which will produce forces against the earthquake to make our building stand healthly.</p>
<p>So what do i need to use. Raspberry Pi or arduino or RaspPico or ESP32 oe ESP8266. Which one do you prefer?</p>
<p>I need to say that I know Python. Which libraries do you prefer.</p>
<p>Thanks for help.</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/shaking-table-raspberry-arduino-esp32-etc-which-one/38897">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/shaking-table-raspberry-arduino-esp32-etc-which-one/38897</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-38897</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/shaking-table-raspberry-arduino-esp32-etc-which-one/38897.rss">Shaking Table; Raspberry || Arduino || ESP32 etc. which one?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Web race condition: Single Packet Attack</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[taoehutoahutwocor]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So I am currently learning about web-based race conditions and I am kinda stuck.</p>
<p>So my understanding is, that multiple incomplete HTTP packets are sent to the server and THEN they are completed by a single tcp packet containing the rest of the inital HTTP requests(Nagle algo)</p>
<p>I can comprehend, that the HTTP packet with the rest of the first HTTP packet are somehow combined again before/when/after reaching the server(via sending a mapping with it or smth idk)</p>
<p>What I don’t understand:</p>
<p>Why aren’t the inital (30 or so) HTTP requests processed by the server before the rest of the HTTP requests arrive? How are they combined together again? Or are they combined before reaching the server?</p>
<p>I understand, that END_STREAM will be set and the last byte is removed before sending most of the data in the first step, but how does the server know? Why does it care and not just HTTP 500 me or smth?</p>
<p>Any help is apprechiated!</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/web-race-condition-single-packet-attack/38661">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/web-race-condition-single-packet-attack/38661</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-38661</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/web-race-condition-single-packet-attack/38661.rss">Web race condition: Single Packet Attack</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About Anti-Fraud APP</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[HgTrojan]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Recently, I’ve observed an interesting phenomenon: even if you haven’t downloaded a particular app and are using an Apple device within a sandbox environment, there’s still the possibility of your website visits being detected, leading to some form of interaction. The good news, however, is that without downloading the app and while operating within the Apple ecosystem, they lack complete access to your information.</p>
<p>I’m intrigued by the methods they employ. Is it through network operations, possibly orchestrated by the internet service provider? Or do they leverage automated processes, such as robots? I don’t have any specific intentions or actions in mind regarding this matter. Instead, I approach this topic from an academic standpoint and as a professional, motivated by a commitment to privacy preservation.</p>
<p>sincere</p>
<p>HgTrojan</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 12:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-38584</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/about-anti-fraud-app/38584.rss">About Anti-Fraud APP</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Attack vector for Bluetooth connection with Flipper Zero</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[xxx]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Some attacks for devices which may be sent some prompt through bluetooth causing some phones to fail due to <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/wall-of-flippers-detects-flipper-zero-bluetooth-spam-attacks" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">BLE Spam</a>.  In this instance of attack, a device with bluetooth on has no choice but to receive the prompt over and over.</p>
<p>The Flipper Zero, for example, has the following options:</p>
<ul>
<li>to control a device like a mouse</li>
<li>slideshow control device</li>
<li>send BadUSB keystrokes through bluetooth</li>
</ul>
<p>But before these types of attacks, there must be a bluetooth connection first made.  Is there an attack vector used to connect the bluetooth to perform these attacks?</p>
<p>What are some vectors of attack (if at all) for Flipper Zero or bluetooth in general?</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/attack-vector-for-bluetooth-connection-with-flipper-zero/38553">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/attack-vector-for-bluetooth-connection-with-flipper-zero/38553</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 09:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-38553</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/attack-vector-for-bluetooth-connection-with-flipper-zero/38553.rss">Attack vector for Bluetooth connection with Flipper Zero</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Ethical Hacking - Extreme Noob - Need Guidance (Where to correctly start?)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[RookieEthicalHacker]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Beginner Guides</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><em>Hello World!</em><br>
You will read a lot of stupid questions from this rookie here ^^<br>
After one week of research I have decided that I want to become an Ethical Hacker!</p>
<ul>
<li>I have absolute zero knowledge when it comes to coding in any language, understanding ethical<br>
hacking properly and its tools for each different area in our digital world.<br>
I have been googling a ton, using ChatGPT for many, many questions and I always ended up in a<br>
rabbit hole because there is so much to know about and learn and I have no understanding on<br>
how it all works and where I should start so it becomes overwhelming.</li>
<li><strong>Where do I start? What do I want to achieve?</strong><br>
Well, in my mind I have this picture of helping the ones that no one else is seeing, that are left alone.<br>
I dream about helping the ones that can not help themselves in a difficult position because of higher powers.</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Example:</strong></em> (The Iranian government censur and filter their network for its civilian. During a protest about Jina Mahsa Amini, the girl who got killed by a government morale-police because she was not wearing her hijab/headscarf properly according to them.<br>
Protest began and the government shot down its own network so that people can not upload/share what is happening during the protest.)<br>
So, what happened was some ethical hacker hacked the street cameras and recorded the incidents that happened on the streets and uploaded on the net to the world to see.</p>
<p><em><strong>Example:</strong></em> Lets say a friend of mine owns an animal store and has a website for the store.<br>
The website gets hacked by someone and no one is able to visit the site or the website is showing something else.</p>
<ol>
<li><em><strong>QUESTION:</strong></em> If I knew how to correctly ethically hack those two above, would I need same IT knowledge and tools? Or would I need totally different knowledge/materials for one and each?</li>
<li><em><strong>QUESTION:</strong></em> If I worked for my local Police Department would that then require some other coding language, IT knowledge and other tools if they for example want me to ethical hack someones mobile-phone who is suspicious for being a spy and is a threat according to the government?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>You see, I am trying to understand a bigger picture in this and build a wider perspective around my head while moving towards being an Ethical Hacker.</li>
<li>Also I am trying to move towards my goal in an efficient way rather than trying to learn everything at the same time or maybe learning wrong areas that is not very necessary for an absolute beginner.<br>
That is the main reason I came to this reddit channel in hope to be guided at least the smallest.<br>
Hopefully I can join a local university and expand my knowledge, but until then self learning is in progress.</li>
<li><em><strong>GUIDANCE:</strong></em> I need you guys to guide me understand the very basic fundamentals to begin with.<br>
With that I mean <strong>What books/video/website/App</strong> would you recommend me to start with and in which area? (I do not mind books with hundreds of pages).<br>
Maybe recommend a book that you wish was available when you was a beginner starting Ethical Hacking. Share me your beginner experience.<br>
Do I need to learn about IT/computer and its history first?<br>
Do I need to learn about coding first?<br>
Imagine that I time traveled from 1500’s and have no clue on from where I should start, but somehow I knew that I want to become an ethical hacker x).</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any other questions feel free to ask!<br>
Thank you very much all to all of you in advance and greetings from this cold and snowy Sweden!</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/ethical-hacking-extreme-noob-need-guidance-where-to-correctly-start/38248">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/ethical-hacking-extreme-noob-need-guidance-where-to-correctly-start/38248</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-38248</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/ethical-hacking-extreme-noob-need-guidance-where-to-correctly-start/38248.rss">Ethical Hacking - Extreme Noob - Need Guidance (Where to correctly start?)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Can someone help a beginner pls</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[znev0909]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>so im a beginner in the cyber world and i always liked to be a hacker so i would really need someone who could guide me or tell me what to do to start my journey pls.<br>
thanks for the support</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/can-someone-help-a-beginner-pls/38158">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/can-someone-help-a-beginner-pls/38158</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-38158</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/can-someone-help-a-beginner-pls/38158.rss">Can someone help a beginner pls</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>I was wondering if anyone would like to give their thoughts on a PHP vulnerability Scanner?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[phpio]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Heyo everyone!</p>
<p>I was wondering if any of you would like to give your feedback on this security scanner my team and i have finished working on recently?</p>
<p>It’s basically a programme that scans PHP code and suggests how to change it if it spots an issue and it’s currently in beta.</p>
<p>Obviously who is better to find out if something actually does its job than a second (or more) pair of eyes that are trained for this sort of thing.</p>
<p>I’m not a cybersecurity specialist so i come to you lads, lasses and the rest – help us out please?</p>
<p>I’d really appreciate it if you could check it out <a href="https://phpsecure.net/landing" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">here</a> and leave any feedback you may have in the comments to this post!</p>
<p>Massive cheers!</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/i-was-wondering-if-anyone-would-like-to-give-their-thoughts-on-a-php-vulnerability-scanner/37932">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/i-was-wondering-if-anyone-would-like-to-give-their-thoughts-on-a-php-vulnerability-scanner/37932</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37932</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/i-was-wondering-if-anyone-would-like-to-give-their-thoughts-on-a-php-vulnerability-scanner/37932.rss">I was wondering if anyone would like to give their thoughts on a PHP vulnerability Scanner?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>SQL injection: wich ones are the best?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[nicolay1996]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>hi everybody im starting to dive into web hacking and hacking in general and into this kind of forums too. i only have discovered some sql injections but i am wondering where can i found all of them in their diferent types. Thanks in advance to anyone who can help <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/+1.png?v=12" title=":+1:" class="emoji" alt=":+1:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/sql-injection-wich-ones-are-the-best/37825">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/sql-injection-wich-ones-are-the-best/37825</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 08:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37825</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/sql-injection-wich-ones-are-the-best/37825.rss">SQL injection: wich ones are the best?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>HOW do you solve CTF challenges?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[vienna]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Beginner here,<br>
I have listened to the advice of some in this forum of starting doing the OverTheWire CTF.<br>
Being tackled each level with a new, completely unknown challenge enhances my knowledge a ton!</p>
<p>Though, what should I do when I get stuck? And I mean, truly stuck - for days.<br>
What do you do then? do you get the answer and move on to not waste much time? Or do you have some sort of timing for these situations?</p>
<p>I don’t want to always check for the answers. Is ‘never-checking’ possible? do you recommended it?<br>
I’d love to hear your feedback on this one.</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-you-solve-ctf-challenges/37746">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-you-solve-ctf-challenges/37746</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 07:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37746</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-you-solve-ctf-challenges/37746.rss">HOW do you solve CTF challenges?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How do you recon a website?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[GuessWHO]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This is how I would recon a website. I would gather subdomains, and directories of a website. Gathering subdomains is not a problem since there are tools or search engines to gather info about subdomains. A problem rises when I want to gather the directories of a website.</p>
<p>I have been thinking about using automated tools and user-directed tools to gather the dirs of the website. But automated-tools simply brute-force the dirs of a website which would send thousands of http requests and I think this is easily traceable and risky. But without automated tools, I wouldn’t be able to gather enough number of directories.</p>
<p>I would like to hear how you usually carry out recon of a website to get some insights:D</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-you-recon-a-website/37698">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-you-recon-a-website/37698</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 22:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37698</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-you-recon-a-website/37698.rss">How do you recon a website?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>.Webp hidden Json</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Lorakai]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Beginner Guides</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I had a quick question, doing a hacking challenge to find a flag hidden in a picture. Pretty easy right? Yeah, not so much as it turns out the picture isn’t a .mpeg . jpeg or anything like that but instead is a .Webp file which contains a hidden json. So question is, how would I go about obtaining the flag? The first part of the challenge was extremely easy as it was just the picture below<br>
</p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/5/6/56149ae20d4d54f03d2aaadec90189259b43df7b.webp" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/chvcVrF18xqVCDSbRlMWipnjf8n.webp?dl=1" title="0_QQddVYwBMORnqepp" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/5/6/56149ae20d4d54f03d2aaadec90189259b43df7b_2_690x99.webp" alt="0_QQddVYwBMORnqepp" data-base62-sha1="chvcVrF18xqVCDSbRlMWipnjf8n" width="690" height="99" srcset="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/5/6/56149ae20d4d54f03d2aaadec90189259b43df7b_2_690x99.webp, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/5/6/56149ae20d4d54f03d2aaadec90189259b43df7b_2_1035x148.webp 1.5x, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/5/6/56149ae20d4d54f03d2aaadec90189259b43df7b.webp 2x" data-dominant-color="3D5A3D"></a></div><br>
It’s not a normal/typical looking picture so my thoughts were it was sort of like a barcode so I analyzed the different color(s)/shade(s) and converted it to hex which provided me with the following:<p></p>
<p>Gl@54G$v#4$uPn4Tm@4h</p>
<p>This is NOT the flag, as flag format will be flag{foundFlagHere}. So I popped the into my terminal and typed file nameOfFile which showed it was a webP file. I was still not sure what to do, however I noticed that when I went to “View downloads” (on my phone) I noticed that unlike the typical picture which usually shows the actual picture you downloaded I noticed this one was different as it showed up as the picture below.<br>
</p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/6/0/60b0b626fcf827714b9ab183f5b558f4fe83799f.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/dNmrgSzPnd3ckEdQIRKzA80YC9V.png?dl=1" title="Screenshot_20231027-185035" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/6/0/60b0b626fcf827714b9ab183f5b558f4fe83799f_2_512x500.png" alt="Screenshot_20231027-185035" data-base62-sha1="dNmrgSzPnd3ckEdQIRKzA80YC9V" width="512" height="500" srcset="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/6/0/60b0b626fcf827714b9ab183f5b558f4fe83799f_2_512x500.png, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/6/0/60b0b626fcf827714b9ab183f5b558f4fe83799f.png 1.5x, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/6/0/60b0b626fcf827714b9ab183f5b558f4fe83799f.png 2x" data-dominant-color="30236C"></a></div><br>
So, obviously something else is going on with that picture. After some time spent thinking and tinkering I came to the conclusion that the picture actually contains a hidden json file.<br>
Long story short, somehow I have to take the key I obtained earlier (Gl@54G$v#4$uPn4Tm@4h) and enter it in, either the picture somehow or json (I converted the Webp picture to json). So, how would I obtain the actual key in a webP file?<p></p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/webp-hidden-json/37609">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/webp-hidden-json/37609</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 22:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37609</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/webp-hidden-json/37609.rss">.Webp hidden Json</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Operation Triangulation, my iPhone was actually hacked</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[RTM]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>One midnight several days ago, I scratched my iPhone on the bedtable, trying to check the time, but I found my iPhone is hot and the WiFi is turned on. It’s weird because I always turn the WiFi off before I go to sleep. At that time, I thought up that my iPhone keeps freezing from time to time these days. All of a sudden, it occurred to me that my iPhone got hacked? The symptoms are highly similar to those which are exposed related to the Operation Triangulation campaign, which targets iOS devices by US intelligence service and is revealed by Kaspersky. Then, I captured the network traffic to and from my iPhone, intending to check if there are malwares running on it. I analyzed the trace files and found some weird things and some weird IP addresses. Hoooooooly shit! It turned out that my iPhone get hacked!<br>
Here is something that you may want to know about Operation Triangulation.<br>
5 June, 2023, Eugene Kaspersky, CEO of Kaspersky, said in a blog post, that iOS devices of Kaspersky employees were attacked. The attacked devices were implanted with a spyware, which steals private data stored on the iOS devices and then transfers the data to remote servers controlled by the attackers. The data includes microphone recordings, photos from instant message apps, geolocation and other information. Kaspersky posts a series of reports on the official website, which provide an in-depth analysis of the Operation Triangular campaign. It says that the attacker uses zero-click exploits via the iMessage platform, thereby stealthily implanting a spyware. The attacker sends victims an invisible iMessage with a malicious attachment, which, using a number of vulnerabilities in the iOS operating system, is executed on a device and installs a spyware. The deployment of the spyware is completely hidden and requires no action from the user. By default, the iMessage function is turned on. As of June 2023, the exploit works on devices running iOS 15.7 and earlier versions. It’s not impossible that the attack will be carried out on iOS future versions. It is reported that the attack campaign has compromised thousands of iPhones devices in Russia, including those of foreign diplomats.<br>
As to the attacker, the Kaspersky report says that it’s related to the Equation Group, which is under the US National Security Agency (NSA). The Equation Group is described as one of the most sophisticated cyberattack groups in the world, operating alongside the creators of Stuxnet and Flame. It can be verified with The Shadow Brokers breach and Snowden revelation.<br>
Due to the close characteristic of iOS, users cannot connect iPhone directly to a computer and scan it. Users have to connect iPhone to a computer, backup the iPhone data to the computer, and then scan the backup data with the tool provided by Kaspersky Lab. During the scanning, if Trojans are detected, it shows DETECTED; for suspicious Trojan files, it shows SUSPICION; if no suspicious files are detected in the backup data, it shows “No traces of compromise were identified”.<br>
If it’s detected that your iPhone is attacked, first reset your iPhone to factory settings, and set it as a new phone. Do not recover it using backup data because the implant spyware might be resumed from the backup. Last year, Apple offers advanced data protection for iCloud, which limits some functionalities if enabled, but the security is enhanced. One of the limits is that the iMessage attachment download will be disabled, which can protect it from such attack. Secondly, update your iOS to latest version.<br>
Here are the IP addresses that you may check on your network<br>
182.55.68.247	<br>
192.0.145.246	<br>
78.156.114.254<br>
80.48.144.33<br>
85.163.125.41	<br>
85.204.56.152	<br>
113.53.30.80<br>
Hope this post help you.</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/operation-triangulation-my-iphone-was-actually-hacked/37577">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/operation-triangulation-my-iphone-was-actually-hacked/37577</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 03:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37577</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/operation-triangulation-my-iphone-was-actually-hacked/37577.rss">Operation Triangulation, my iPhone was actually hacked</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Computer Keyboard layout</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[KlyntarX]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Beginner Guides</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone,<br>
I’m KlyntarX <em>I’m not really into telling my real name</em> I’m 13 years old and I really like learning <em>You can say I’m a huge nerd</em> I came to Sweden for studies and I got myself a new keyboard. Back in my country, I had a 135 wpm where the keyboard layout was the regular QWERTY keyboard layout. This question is not related to hacking or penetration testing or anything I just want to ask How can I improve my typing speed if I have to change the layout? Can you guys tell me the most effective way to improve my typing speed to the same level as before? I know there is like 1 million YouTube videos that cover this topic but I don’t really think that’s the most effective way to keep a consistent typing speed.</p>
<p>by KlyntarX</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 15:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37330</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330.rss">Computer Keyboard layout</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How to write malware using golang</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[yamatosaki]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I see that in malicious software, very few people write golang, how can they write a bot that collects data from the browser and gets IG’s access token?</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-write-malware-using-golang/37125">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-write-malware-using-golang/37125</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 09:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37125</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-write-malware-using-golang/37125.rss">How to write malware using golang</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How do I run a program step by step?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Hack3rcon]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Beginner Guides</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello,<br>
How to run an .exe file step by step and see what happens at each step of execution? For example, what files the program creates or deletes and…</p>
<p>Any idea welcomed.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-i-run-a-program-step-by-step/36908">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-i-run-a-program-step-by-step/36908</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 19:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-36908</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-do-i-run-a-program-step-by-step/36908.rss">How do I run a program step by step?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Scanning for IP addresses of targets</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[EskimoJones]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Beginner Guides</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m new to hacking and I keep hearing about how white hat hackers and black hat hackers are able to penetrate company and government networks. The part of this process I don’t really know is how black hat hackers and white hat hackers are able to find the IP addresses of the machines in these networks on the internet when they are first attempting to penetrate these networks without the use of social engineering. It would be really helpful if I could have any information on the techniques used to identify the IP addresses hackers want to target on the internet.</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/scanning-for-ip-addresses-of-targets/36792">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/scanning-for-ip-addresses-of-targets/36792</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 18:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-36792</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/scanning-for-ip-addresses-of-targets/36792.rss">Scanning for IP addresses of targets</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>A few questions as a newbie - Can I learn?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Aviixx]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Dear 0x00sec community,</p>
<p>I have a few questions regarding ‘ethical hacking’.</p>
<p>before I do start asking away, I first want to state that my interpretation of ‘ethical hacking’ is hacking for humanity, not hacking for corporations, businesses or anything alike. Please feel free to correct me on this, for example if ‘ethical hacking’ has a whole different meaning.</p>
<p>With that out of the way, here are my questions;</p>
<p>} Q.1<br>
-STUDENT WEB DEV-<br>
I am a student in web development, and I just started. I have little to no experience with HTML, CSS, Java or anything related to web development.</p>
<p>I thusfar know how some HTML, I know how to use CSS a little but know nothing about JS.</p>
<p>For anyone has studied web development or anything that would be (remotely) alike, is there a way for me to finish this study and kind of ‘reverse’ the things I learnt for humanity’s good?</p>
<p>For example, if I learn how to protect a website, can I also use that information to find out if I can attack a website a certain way?</p>
<p>} Q.2<br>
-WHERE TO START-<br>
As I stated in Q.1, I want to learn how to hack websites using any language that exists, but where do I start?</p>
<p>Ofcourse I’ve seen a lot of topics on here, but I understand almost nothing except for the few posts that pass by about regular discussions regarding social stuff. Where does a complete noob start with learning how to hack?</p>
<p>–</p>
<p>These were all my questions. If possible, please answer in the easiest-to-understand terms, as I am totally inexperienced.</p>
<p>best regards,</p>
<p>Aviixx -</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/a-few-questions-as-a-newbie-can-i-learn/36783">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/a-few-questions-as-a-newbie-can-i-learn/36783</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 01:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-36783</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/a-few-questions-as-a-newbie-can-i-learn/36783.rss">A few questions as a newbie - Can I learn?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How to hide yourself?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[lolorek22]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Questions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi,</p>
<p>I was wondering how to hide yourself on Kali Linux? Hacking is fun, but we should remember about our safety. Is there any tools that can help hide yourself?</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-hide-yourself/36590">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-hide-yourself/36590</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 11:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-36590</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-hide-yourself/36590.rss">How to hide yourself?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What bookmarks or sites do you guys use that help with your hacking?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[slimyslipper]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Beginner Guides</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey just wondering what bookmarks you guys have on your browser that help you with your hacking, im still noob level and have been for several years, but i know a couple things. Im trying to build the best online resuource portal  i found a great collection at  <a href="https://github.com/kargisimos/offensive-bookmarks" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub - kargisimos/offensive-bookmarks: A collection of bookmarks for penetration testers, bug bounty hunters, malware developers, reverse engineers and anyone who is just interested in infosec topics.</a></p>
<p>lots of stuff there in that html file but i just find it seems incomplete.</p>
<p>theres also <a href="https://github.com/vitalysim/Awesome-Hacking-Resources" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub - vitalysim/Awesome-Hacking-Resources: A collection of hacking / penetration testing resources to make you better!</a> wich doesn’t a html file for bookmarks but plenty of good links and resources to study up on.</p>
<p>but yeh just wondering what kind of resources and sites are you guys goto?</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/what-bookmarks-or-sites-do-you-guys-use-that-help-with-your-hacking/36510">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/what-bookmarks-or-sites-do-you-guys-use-that-help-with-your-hacking/36510</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 04:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-36510</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/what-bookmarks-or-sites-do-you-guys-use-that-help-with-your-hacking/36510.rss">What bookmarks or sites do you guys use that help with your hacking?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Remote hack windows 10</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Mr5Robot]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Beginner Guides</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, I hope you are doing okay.<br>
I have a question please, I am new to hacking, and I learned a few stuff on TryHackMe, I learned how to exploit and run a “malware” one windows 7 just by using the IP adress of the windows 7 and finding a vulnerability. But I was unable to do the same on my second windows 10 pro PC, do you have tips please ?</p>
<p>Thank you in advance</p>
<p>Mr5Robot</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/remote-hack-windows-10/36387">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/remote-hack-windows-10/36387</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 23:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-36387</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/remote-hack-windows-10/36387.rss">Remote hack windows 10</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
