<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>How to connect to IRC using Hexchat and Anonsurf</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-anonsurf/7887</link>
    <description>Hi all, f0rg here with another tutorial. Since most of us frequent IRC, lately some if not all the Tor exit nodes have been banned. I&#39;m not claiming that this works 100% of the time, but it should work most of the time. 

Anyways, This is my work around of their ban of Tor exit nodes because lately my current way of [&#39;How to Connect to IRC using Hexchat and Tor&#39;](https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-tor/6866) doesn&#39;t work 100% of the time... I&#39;ve decided to write this for those like me, who have been having trouble of connecting to IRC with Tor enabled lately because of what I stated above.

With that outta the way, lets have some fun. I don&#39;t want to go into detail what Anonsurf is, if you want to know, it&#39;s basically Tor except simplified for ParrotSec OS which is a Debian based distro running MATE as it&#39;s default Desktop Environment. Of course, thanks to github and the internet, anonsurf is available to all distros. Alright, lets begin.

In a terminal, type:

```
git clone https://github.com/parrotsec/anonsurf
```

Simple enough, I know, but we need all the scripts for this to work. Now, we must edit the torrc file. I&#39;m assuming you have Tor installed, but if not, type in a terminal:

```
sudo apt install tor
```

Now with tor installed, we must type:

```
sudo nano -w /etc/tor/torrc
```

This&#39;ll open up the torrc file with nano. Add these following lines:

```
VirtualAddrNetwork 10.192.0.0/10
AutomapHostsOnResolve 1
TransPort 9040
DNSPort 53
```

Now simply run anonsurf.sh as sudo like so:

``` 
sudo ./anonsurf.sh start
```

To stop anonsurf. Type:

``` 
sduo ./anonsurf.sh stop
```

Connect to IRC as you&#39;d normally do. 

Simple enough... of course ParrotSec OS has this by default with a nice-ish interface to work with aka buttons that&#39;ll do this without opening a terminal.

Anyways, that&#39;s enough said for now. I hope this helps those that are having issues connecting to IRC anonymously (aka tor). 

With all that being said, ~Cheers!

--Techno Forg--</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 01:39:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Social</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-anonsurf/7887.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>How to connect to IRC using Hexchat and Anonsurf</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-anonsurf/7887/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-anonsurf/7887/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 01:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-7887-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-anonsurf/7887.rss">How to connect to IRC using Hexchat and Anonsurf</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How to connect to IRC using Hexchat and Anonsurf</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Techno_Forg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all, f0rg here with another tutorial. Since most of us frequent IRC, lately some if not all the Tor exit nodes have been banned. I’m not claiming that this works 100% of the time, but it should work most of the time.</p>
<p>Anyways, This is my work around of their ban of Tor exit nodes because lately my current way of <a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-tor/6866">‘How to Connect to IRC using Hexchat and Tor’</a> doesn’t work 100% of the time… I’ve decided to write this for those like me, who have been having trouble of connecting to IRC with Tor enabled lately because of what I stated above.</p>
<p>With that outta the way, lets have some fun. I don’t want to go into detail what Anonsurf is, if you want to know, it’s basically Tor except simplified for ParrotSec OS which is a Debian based distro running MATE as it’s default Desktop Environment. Of course, thanks to github and the internet, anonsurf is available to all distros. Alright, lets begin.</p>
<p>In a terminal, type:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">git clone https://github.com/parrotsec/anonsurf
</code></pre>
<p>Simple enough, I know, but we need all the scripts for this to work. Now, we must edit the torrc file. I’m assuming you have Tor installed, but if not, type in a terminal:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">sudo apt install tor
</code></pre>
<p>Now with tor installed, we must type:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">sudo nano -w /etc/tor/torrc
</code></pre>
<p>This’ll open up the torrc file with nano. Add these following lines:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">VirtualAddrNetwork 10.192.0.0/10
AutomapHostsOnResolve 1
TransPort 9040
DNSPort 53
</code></pre>
<p>Now simply run anonsurf.sh as sudo like so:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">sudo ./anonsurf.sh start
</code></pre>
<p>To stop anonsurf. Type:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">sduo ./anonsurf.sh stop
</code></pre>
<p>Connect to IRC as you’d normally do.</p>
<p>Simple enough… of course ParrotSec OS has this by default with a nice-ish interface to work with aka buttons that’ll do this without opening a terminal.</p>
<p>Anyways, that’s enough said for now. I hope this helps those that are having issues connecting to IRC anonymously (aka tor).</p>
<p>With all that being said, ~Cheers!</p>
<p>–Techno Forg–</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-anonsurf/7887/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-anonsurf/7887/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 01:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-7887-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-connect-to-irc-using-hexchat-and-anonsurf/7887.rss">How to connect to IRC using Hexchat and Anonsurf</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
