<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration - 0x00sec - The Home of the Hacker</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/c/social/inspiration/45</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Inspiration&#39; category A place for stories. Tell the community a story so that all sorts of members can be inspired by your struggles, and the determination that brought you here.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 13:13:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/c/social/inspiration/45.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>If you Want to get good at Malware Development</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[digitalXmage]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This is just for the people which lack passion, and maybe have a skewed view of Malware, And hacking. This has just been my experience, And You have to delve into this stuff <strong>with the right mindset I feel</strong>. I’m no crazy Hacker, Or malware developer, But <strong>I’m learning</strong>. And I have learnt A lot. And Have Learnt A lot about Trojans and ELF binary files(A never ending fun endeavor)</p>
<p>It’s Very simple actually. You need to have the urge to learn more about how a computer works, and really enjoy learning the low information of how a computer works, It will gravitate to you writing low level applications, learning more about the operating system, the Linux API, especially C, and also assembler are both important and provide different ways of learning about computers. And writing Assembly is really great. And then combining the both in writing Both C and embedded/Inline assembler, <strong>It’s Like C is the Knife, And Assembly is the Gun. Combine With Data structures and Algorithm knowledge, I think are all powerful tools. For Creating efficient programs</strong></p>
<p>Assembler is great, It gets rid of all the levels of abstraction of the computer that A lot of languages have(Not bad, But not useful if you want to learn how a computer works), and you WILL learn how a computer works. How memory works, How the CPU works etc. And C is great When you learn the concepts in assembler, Will help your C programming.</p>
<p>Read Books, You can pirate books from this website: <a href="https://www.pdfdrive.com/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">pdfdrive</a></p>
<p>Books are way better than tutorials, because unlike tutorials, Authors are paid lots of money to write these computer textbooks, It’s their job, they’re are gonna make sure they invest the time to research and learn and write that textbook to the best of their ability. And what’s great Even books a decade ago are still useful, Because Low level never really changes and For whatever legacy stuff you learn, Emulators , Virtual machines are great for that.) And The best ones Are written by University professors IMO, But there are many great authors Who are just great programmers and share the knowledge. (Not to Say tutorials are bad, Use, and learn from both).</p>
<p>And also theoretical knowledge and Practical knowledge is important, so it’s good to read up on the theory and apply the theory into practice through projects. For instance I’ve been learning a lot about the ELF Binary in Linux, As well as delving into embedded programming for micro controllers.</p>
<p>This knowledge of the system will help with malware development, and If you already have a strong interest in low level programming, Then you’ll learn a lot, if you’re determined enough to learn.</p>
<p>What I’m saying is you gotta trust the process, You have to enjoy every part a long the way,Each step in the learning you need to <strong>enjoy and write applications that you are proud off</strong>. If you don’t enjoy it, you won’t be good at it. At all.</p>
<p>This has been my current roadmap(journey so far):</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Learn C and Linux API and write fun user space Terminal applications. (Did loads of projects before going to step 2, Still do). Get Better at C, memory management, Getting Good at debugging (GDB)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Learn and read up on Computer Theory, learn  a CPU instruction set(arm assembler), Bytes, bit shifting, how arithmetic work,Logical Operations ,CPU, CPU registers, Memory etc. etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Learn and Read up on computer Malware, And Learn to Read other people’s code and learning from other people’s source code, Learn the theory and Creating projects Using that Learnt Knowledge. <strong>(Incredibly important skill in an Area of learning advanced topics with not much practical resources online)</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Currently Learning embedded micro controller programming, To learn more about computers and writing programs on bare metal(No operating system) etc etc.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This is What I’ve done so far. If it helps people who are unsure about What it takes to learn Hacking , and This stuff to the source code, binary level. And honestly <strong>You gotta enjoy the process more than the outcome</strong>, especially in this Area. Most of the stuff you learn, especially at the beginning, Will be minimal and always be caught by anti virus measures. But you should still be proud when you do something as significant such as embedded a basic payload into an Elf binary and printing some text to the screen.</p>
<p><strong>Enjoy the process More than the Result.</strong> As What Seems insignificant to others, Is A big step for myself, In learning and understanding a new concept, which may of taken months of learning, and Writing a lot of lines of code for some small result.</p>
<p>As well of having a strong interest in Low level programming, Regardless Of hacking and writing Malware.</p>
<p>I just feel A good mindset is important,  and A bit of self reflection, Which has helped me at least.</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 13:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-23466</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466.rss">If you Want to get good at Malware Development</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>CONGRATULATIONS! Everyone give a heads up to one of our members rek&#39;in flare-on</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[nugget]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Everyone give a big hands up, thump up, sexual massage or big lovin to our resident matey boy <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/leeky">@Leeky</a> for REKIN flare-on check his scores!</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/1/10205a08c31c338b571874fa56b192b25dc04456.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/2iEX4f2WJrvCONEtJheeev81RyK.png?dl=1" title="ef3090676d0c76993e98ca1c3504629b" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/1/10205a08c31c338b571874fa56b192b25dc04456.png" alt="ef3090676d0c76993e98ca1c3504629b" data-base62-sha1="2iEX4f2WJrvCONEtJheeev81RyK" width="498" height="500"></a></div><p></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Leeky&gt; 250 hours over 2 months! I have never been so sore but it was worth it in the end, even if it did end up so sticky<br>
Leeky&gt; Luckily my anus was totally fine!</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>– Quotes may have happened in real life or in nuggets head, no one is ever really sure</em></p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/congratulations-everyone-give-a-heads-up-to-one-of-our-members-rekin-flare-on/8646">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/congratulations-everyone-give-a-heads-up-to-one-of-our-members-rekin-flare-on/8646</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 15:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-8646</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/congratulations-everyone-give-a-heads-up-to-one-of-our-members-rekin-flare-on/8646.rss">CONGRATULATIONS! Everyone give a heads up to one of our members rek&#39;in flare-on</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Your most inspiring hacking books</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[rosavelvet]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey good peeps,</p>
<p>I would like to start a thread on your favorite hacking books. Ones you read recently and taught you one or two new tricks, or ones that you read a decade ago and literally changed your way of thinking about hacking!!<br>
I realize there are a lot of “how to hack facebook” shenanigans going on here, so hopefully such a thread will help set people on the right path to hacking…<br>
Allow me to start first :</p>
<p><strong>Books of old that shaped my hacking career (a bit outdated now but still great):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The Art of Intrusion - The Real Stories Behind the Exploits of Hackers, Intruders and Deceivers , Kevin Mitnick</li>
<li>Counter Hack Reloaded - A Step-by-Step Guide to Computer Attacks and Effective Defenses, Ed Skoudis</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Books that rocked my life recently:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2uWh1Up" rel="nofollow noopener">How to Hack Like a Legend - A hacker’s tale breaking into a secretive offshore company , Sparc Flow</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Art-Memory-Forensics-Detecting-Malware/dp/1118825098/?tag=0x00sec03-20" rel="nofollow noopener">The Art of Memory Forensics - Detecting Malware and Threats in Windows, Linux, and Mac Memory</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Your turn <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/your-most-inspiring-hacking-books/7367">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/your-most-inspiring-hacking-books/7367</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 17:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-7367</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/your-most-inspiring-hacking-books/7367.rss">Your most inspiring hacking books</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Show off your setup! V2</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi 0x00’ers!</p>
<p>If you had seen the last ‘show off your setup’ thread, <a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/show-off-your-setup/1345" class="inline-onebox">Show off your setup!</a></p>
<p>You’ll notice it was a huge success, and there was a tonne of beautiful systems and setups. Since it was a little while ago and a lot of people have already renewed their existing setup, got new hardware, jumped ship to Linux or MacOS (or even, <em>gasp</em>, windows), it would be so awesome to see what everybody is rocking and what works for everybody.</p>
<p>We have about 30 days until this thread auto locks, so let’s try and see as many of your setups as possible! If you run Linux, Windows, MacOS, the whole community is really anxious to see what you got working for you, no matter how humble or extravagant, how little or how big, even just posting a screenshot would be awesome to see the wallpapers and things people are using on a daily basis.</p>
<p>I’m so excited to see what you guys come up with!</p>
            <p><small>118 posts - 50 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/show-off-your-setup-v2/6846">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/show-off-your-setup-v2/6846</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 10:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-6846</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/show-off-your-setup-v2/6846.rss">Show off your setup! V2</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Shared thoughts after 6+ years in Pentesting</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[maderas]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello everyone.</p>
<p>I have made some minor edits since first posting this as to further clarify a couple of points.</p>
<p>I joined this community a while ago; I have/had been a lurker for even longer.  A huge part of what made the hacker community what it was (and what it is here) involves a willingness to share knowledge (without spoonfeeding).</p>
<p>I would feel remiss if I gained so much from so many of you and did not give something back on occasion.</p>
<p>What follows are anecdotes, opinions and observations I can share after almost 7 years working professionally in the InfoSec/Netsec field.</p>
<p>Most of my work in this sphere has been anchored in Penetration Testing. Even when my official designation was Network Security Analyst, I spent most of those 3 years in engagements against PCI environments utilized for subcontracting  work from Comcast, Verizon, Time Warner, Sprint and AT&amp;T (to name a few of my former employers clients).</p>
<p>Currently, I manage the Cybersecurity Lab of an International company that employees over 200,000 employees. Most of my work in my current position involves Penetration Testing (every type imaginable, including focused blackbox testing against embedded devices and the network/control structures surrounding them).</p>
<p>I am also a lead point of contact for our international teams during remediation and triage of major security threats, incidents and breaches.</p>
<p>For example, I was the my company’s head analyst for the recent Shamoon 2.0 attacks (W32.DisttrackB/W97M.Downloader) last February, as well as the recent Wannacry outbreak.</p>
<p>I also serve in a Security Engineer capacity, as I am regularly asked to evaluate facets of our products and provide feedback and opinions on the security ramifications involved.</p>
<p>I am extremely busy and wanted to give back what I have taken thus far, so this is going to be long…</p>
<p>Here goes nothing:</p>
<ol>
<li>I am completely self taught (meaning I acquired no college/formal education to get where I am).</li>
</ol>
<p>That being said, a solid Computer Science degree is invaluable as a base (I would generally avoid Cybersecurity degrees and go for CS ), and even the degree itself will open doors into this business.</p>
<p>Also, I work alongside high-level engineers (CS and Electrical Engineering PhDs); what they can do in a short period of time once they take an interest in InfoSec/NetSec is frightening.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>That leads me to this: to be great at anything (including InfoSec/NetSec), I believe that your pursuit must become a sort of lifestyle. Between work and further study/skills building (as well as time I invest in InfoSec/NetSec activities such as my daily reading), I easily invest 80+ hours per week in this pursuit.</li>
</ol>
<p>And I love just about every minute of it. There is a huge need for InfoSec/NetSec professionals,which I feel is going to lead to a flood of low knowledge, low passion, low skill hiring.</p>
<p>Anyone trying to get into this industry for the cash alone is going to have a rude awakening: there are probably lower pressure, lower work hour ways to earn the same money doing something that actually interests you…</p>
<p>Also, those of us really invested in these arts can pretty easily spot our own.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Learn to study, and learn to love the act of studying. Much of this job is continual study; eventually, when presented with an issue youare ignorant of, you will feel confident in knowing that you can find the answers you need.</li>
</ol>
<p>Break the issue into small, manageable pieces (goals really), and put the pieces together until you can view the whole answer.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Most of my success in this industry has been due to a willingness to work hard, persevere and never give up. Ever. Most of this job is the creative solving of problems that do not or may not have any easy answer (or any answer at all…yet).</li>
</ol>
<p>You have to build a no retreat, no surrender, obsessive need to conquer problems.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>I specialize in network penetration, though I have become fairly well rounded. To me, network penetration is the art of acquiring advantages.</li>
</ol>
<p>During an engagement, I am always looking to acquire advantages. I study and train to better recognize and maximize the resources within an environment that allow me to gain those advantages.</p>
<p>Gaining these advantages are more a product of knowledge and experience then an application of tools.</p>
<ol start="6">
<li>I am also looking to be efficient; the best penetration tests replicate real world attacks. In that vein, each action you take raises the probability that you will be detected.</li>
</ol>
<p>For hackers and freedom fighters engaged in illegal activity,you may want to consider the latter a bit. Once you make ingress and launch any manner of offensive action, you have escalated the legal ramifications  of your trespass by multiple magnitudes.</p>
<p>Also remember  that the probability of you getting caught and prosecuted is never 0.00%: you have to be prepared, you have to be careful, you have to be patient and you have to prepare contingencies.</p>
<ol start="7">
<li>I use a measurement/assessment of risk vs. reward to make each action within the network as efficient as possible; by percentages,losing a queen to take a rook is generally a loser’s bet.</li>
</ol>
<p>The best way I’ve learned to temper a careful approach is with an old sales slogan (“ Always be closing the deal”, which I modified to “Always be advancing your position(s)”).</p>
<ol start="7">
<li>I try as much as possible to engage a target as a stalking, ambush predator: I move carefully and try to use the environment  to hide myself as I seek to  exploit the target/objectives lack of awareness.</li>
</ol>
<p>I work to remain patient and identify/quantify  as many of the variables of the current                 environment/situation as possible.</p>
<p>Sometimes the best decision you can make is to slow down  or hold your current position for a bit; watching Tcpdump or Wireshark while thinking on a better move is still advancing your<br>
position.</p>
<ol start="8">
<li>To lower the probability of detection (whenever possible) I attempt to attack, enumerate or probe from an obfuscated position.</li>
</ol>
<p>Configuring  your attack host/node  for the highest probability of situational anonymity (using tunneling, proxies, encapsulation ,etc.) is infinitely useful in pentesting, hacking and/or general<br>
security/privacy.</p>
<p>Mastering the manipulation of proxy, tunneling and encapsulation protocols (which involves a deep understanding of networking/TCP/UDP) almost lends you quasi-magical invisibility and teleportation powers when involved in network penetration.</p>
<p>Obfuscation itself is one of 10,000 reasons why experience/knowledge in the disciplines of networking, OS and programming  combined with security research are such huge advantages (and another reason why if you take up this path you may never stop learning).</p>
<ol start="9">
<li>
<p>Learn to use every tool you can, but more importantly, learn why the tool works. If you work in/at exploitation long enough, the principles governing the tools will help you exploit a box someday,regardless of whether you use that particular tool to get the wanted/needed result…</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Knowledge/experience over tool use is especially important today: regardless of what many sites say, you will not find many enterprise/corporate networks today (as a professional penetration tester at least) where there are gross configurations/deployments leading to an easy, out of the box (deploy tool== Meterpreter) exploitation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When training for a fight, professional mixed martial artists put themselves in the worst possible positions so they react properly when the fight is underway.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Eventually, training/practicing your exploitation/research techniques the same way will be a huge boon in engagements, POCs (or in the wild). I especially like to round difficulty up during research; it is difficult for someone else to minimize your findings if you have added (and circumvented) greater security measures than the norm (rather than having reduced them).</p>
<ol start="11">
<li>Most of my exploitation of networks in the last couple years have been a process of discovering network misconfigurations and weaknesses (especially in Windows firewall, Programs and Features, LGPO/GPO policies and/or IE/Internet Options within Window Domains/Networks) or information leaks that I locate online or through DNS enumeration that ultimately leads to my gaining access to a host.</li>
</ol>
<p>From there, remote exploitation (toward post exploitation/privilege escalation/pivoting) will often occur This is largely when knowledge of things such as Powershell (leveraged by itself or tools like Powersploit/CrackMapExec/PsExec/Empire) become invaluable (in Windows networks).</p>
<p>I have actually been finding easier remote exploits when attacking Linux/Unix boxes in enterprise networks (finding Solaris with Apache Tomcat during enumeration still springs hope eternal in my human breast).</p>
<p>Many (actually, maybe all) of these companies are/were new at deploying Unix/Linux boxes in their networks and were making some serious mistakes with deployment.</p>
<ol start="12">
<li>Enumeration is the most important part of an engagement to me. You should get used to enumeration without automated tools; I love Nmap, but many times it is not feasible  to usewithin the customer’s network (network overhead issues, the chance of detection<br>
by IIDS, the chance of breaking PLCs or other embedded devices, etc.).</li>
</ol>
<p>In cases where you are on the customer’s network, tools like Wireshark, Tcpdump, knowledge of networking protocols/ports and banner grabbing are your friends.</p>
<ol start="13">
<li>For those engagements where you first need to gain access to the network, you definitely have more room for running some louder tools:</li>
</ol>
<p>I love Fierce (and DNS enumeration in general) as it often presents my way in.</p>
<p>Google dorking is still also an incredible tool, as is Firefox with the right set of extensions (Hackbar, Tamperdata, Wappalyzer, BuiltWIth, Uppity, IP Address and DOmain Information, etc,.).</p>
<p>Who loves Dirbuster in these cirumstances? This carbon/caffeine based lifeform right here.</p>
<p>Whether you are pentesting, bughunting  or hacking/freedom fighting, a paid Shodan subscription will($50) is worth every cent. The capacity to make exacting, accurate searches for greater than five pages has helped me in more engagements/bughunts than I can remember.</p>
<ol start="14">
<li>When I am explaining why a config/setting/LGPO /GPO (etc.) is a security risk to a client or my fellow employees,  I like to explain that many of the advantages I look for in my environment are most often advantages that are needlessly provided to me.</li>
</ol>
<p>If it does not break key functionality or seriously impede efficiency/development time, than it is in their best interest to deny me as many advantages as possible, even when the advantages appear as if they are minutia.</p>
<p>When dealing with a client or non-security fellow employees,you should work to create a relationship of mutual help and teamwork.</p>
<p>I am not there to rub their noses in there crap; I am there to help improve their security so the company can prosper. This is partially a customer service gig where solutions (remediation/counter measures) are more beneficial to the customer than the exploitation itself.</p>
<p>Whenever possible, I like to end the post-exploitation/penetration test conversation/meeting/presentation with the attitude that I am here to help fix these issues , how can WE best close these gaps? How can I help make your (or our) company safer, so that we can become<br>
more prosperous?</p>
<ol start="15">
<li>I personally despise Microsoft (and many proprietary products/companies) on many levels, but when it comes to work, I am platform agnostic. Whatever tool is needed to complete the mission is the tool I am going to employ.</li>
</ol>
<p>However, whenever possible without jeopardizing the mission, I am going to employ an Open Source/Unix/Linux-centric solution.</p>
<p>I work hard to show my company the value in Open Source. The way to show that value isn’t to be the super Unix/Linux/GPL neckbeard who constantly bemoans proprietary software./platforms.</p>
<p>The best way (for me), is to show how effective the strategy involving the Open Source tool is. Then, in my report, I explain the business hook of using Open Source (if the tool is free for commercial use).</p>
<p>I am sensitive to companies taking Open Source tools and turning them into something  proprietary.</p>
<p>However, if I can make my company (which is both huge and almost universally recognized as ethical, which is rare) see the value in Open Source, I know they will  eventually  incorporate Open Source into the support packages for their products (which they have while keeping the tools ad the license in tact).</p>
<p>This than spreads the value of Open Source to smallercompanies who see it being trusted by a much larger company.</p>
<ol start="16">
<li>I have tens of thousands of dollars worth of licenses atmy disposal. However, I will never use tools like Nexpose, Nessus, Canvas orMetasploit Pro unless the project, client, or a governing body specificallyrequire them.</li>
</ol>
<p>I believe these tools develop poor habits. Obviously, if a project such as evaluating an entire domain of IP/hosts for vulnerabilities is my task, I am going to use Nessus. However, (whenever a time/project permits, which they most often do) I am going to evaluate the findings (and search for other vulnerabilities) manually.</p>
<ol start="17">
<li>The ultimate goal should be reliance on nothing more than a Linux/Unix Terminal, some manner of network access and a programming language. One of my favorite exploitation tools is my Nexus 7 2013 flo tablet (running a modified version of Nethunter) and a Bluetooth folio keyboard ( I got the idea from n-o-d-e, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hqG8ivP0RkQ" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hqG8ivP0RkQ</a>) as the final product is a netbook that fits in a jacket pocket).</li>
</ol>
<p>I have exploited some seriously huge clients with thislittle rig (for ingress and a quick root shell, WPS on network/enterpriseprinters and knowledge PCL/PJL/Postscript are often your friend).</p>
<p>I have also exploited other customers with a cheap UMX smartphone with 5 gigs of storage, 1<br>
gb of memory and  GNUroot Debian (Guest Wifi access from the parking lot or an onsite public restroom, human nature, and Responder.py  analyze mode, followed by WPAD, LLMNR and NetBios poisoning with NTLMv1 and LM authorization downgradefor the win).</p>
<ol start="18">
<li>During  (red team, onsite, etc.) engagements, even when the ultimate target of the engagement is located on  a hardwired network with heavy segmentation/compartmentalization (such as the conduit/zone based layouts that are general best practice in Industrial sectors), it is always worthgaining a host/node with corporate WIFI access.</li>
</ol>
<p>One thing WIFI access provides is reach: an Administrator’s (or other privileged user’s) dedicated workstation may be out of reach, but his other devices (if in scope) may be connected to Corp. WIFI for reasons such as saving data on a plan.</p>
<p>Also, WIFI allows me attacks of opportunity even when I am doing other things. Running Responder.py on a misconfigured network’s WIFI while I am elsewise engaged is gaining me advantages (maybe clear text creds, maybe hashes, maybe NTLMv1 and LM hashes) at little cost to my time or attention.</p>
<p>When I employ this, I like to spoof the poisoning machines hostname/mac address to something familiar on the network. If you see a bunch of hosts named “Apple” during your recon, and all of those hosts are not online, spoof the hostname/MAC to match one of the Apple machines (this will not withstand close scrutiny, but will often suffice with a little work).</p>
<p>It always helps to watch and take note on the norms of the network traffic and protocols. Try to match this as much as possible (this will likely help you avoid IDS/IPS, firewall rules, etc.) and whatever traffic would seriously stand out, try to tunnel or encapsulate with normal network traffic/protocols.</p>
<ol start="19">
<li>This leads to two other points:</li>
</ol>
<p>A) Be prepared for the majority of people within a company who do not care about, or will minimize security issues. Do not get frustrated; I find that showing the parties involved what they stand to lose as a company from a vuln to be more effective than focusing on the vuln itself.</p>
<p>B) This is where the Nexus and cheap smartphone come into play: taking the client’s domain with a laptop may scare up some results, but showing s customer that an attacker could cost them tens of millions with a $20 dollar smartphone or a $100 dollar tablet (from the parking lot) works wonders.</p>
<p>C) I have an interest in learning to exploit everything and anything. This has served me well during network penetration tests, as many targets will defend their DCs, file servers and hosts, but not pay much attention to the printers and IoT devices within the network.</p>
<p>D) To this end, learn to work with uncommon protocols. UPnP. NTLDNA and SSDP have been serving me well for the last couple years. Many file servers (and company smartphones/tablets when they are in scope) keep the UPnP door (and associated protocols) wide open. I once grabbed SNMP and other default network appliance creds from a fileserver through UPnP.</p>
<ol start="20">
<li>If you are going to pay for certs with your own cash, I recommend the OSCP. Yes, some of the machines/exploits are outdated. You won’t find many of the SMB remote exploits used for the course in the wild very often anymore (unless an Admin  leaves a test server up, which happens occasionally).</li>
</ol>
<p>However, the overall experience, breakdown on enumeration methodology, self reliance and mindset the entire experience teaches you are invaluable.</p>
<p>I have seen some sites peddling garbage certs with no industry recognition. Save your money for the OSCP; its profile in the industry is high and growing. Certs are no replacement for experience, but starting out with a IT/CS related degree or some general IT experience (even Helpdesk work) along with the OSCP will get you hired somewhere.</p>
<ol start="21">
<li>For persistence, I prefer adding innocuous user accounts/Remote Desktop accounts.</li>
</ol>
<p>If I am going to add some manner of privileged user account early to mid engagement, I usually try to add a more low profile account (if I have the option) such as Server Operator; these type of accounts allow privileged access you can build from, but generally are not watched with the scrutiny of an Administrator account.</p>
<p>When I do create Administrator accounts (I try to wait until I begin my endgame), I will try to match the naming convention to similar accounts in within the network. if a</p>
<p>For example, if the Administrator accounts within the network are named  USsupervisor, I will name the added account something like USupervisor. If I know the clear text password of the account I have mimicked, I will use the same password.</p>
<ol start="22">
<li>
<p>Keep good notes during the engagement; too much information is better than to little information. Captured PCAPS of network traffic are great for examination during down time between engagements.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you are a hacker, freedom fighter, or someone generally concerned about max privacy, this series of articles and configurations are for you:<br>
<a href="https://www.ivpn.net/blog/privacy-guides/advanced-privacy-and-anonymity-part-1" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.ivpn.net/blog/privacy-guides/advanced-privacy-and-anonymity-part-1</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>My favorite distro is Backbox; it starts out with a solid set of tools ninus the obscure bloat (and so far I have been able to add  anything Kali has to Backbox). You can use Backbox’s “Anonymous” option for a full transparent Tor proxy, Macchanger and host name changer and set RAM to overwrite on exit.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>I also  keep Portable Virtualbox on a USB drive with a Kali Linux image…</p>
<p>You could follow some of the advice here: <a href="http://www.torforum.org/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=18320" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.torforum.org/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=18320</a></p>
<p>And here: <a href="http://www.torforum.org/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=18320" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.torforum.org/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=18320</a></p>
<p>The articles above could help you  create an encrypted USB with a Whonix gateway and Kali Linux workstation (you could probably exchange Kali OS in the Whonix Workstation  for any Debian/Debian like OS).</p>
<p>This configuration is disposable and concealable, and will run all of the Kali Workstation’s (or other Debian/Debian like OS)  through Tor. You could also create multiple other Vanilla Whonix Workstations/Gateways on the USB to create a type of local jumpbox sequencea to tunnel between/through SSH and/or VPN them before final Kali workstation.</p>
<p>(Note: This is just a gut feeling, but  for your own OpSec/security/anonymity, you are probably best replacing the Kali workstation with another Debian/Debian like distro. I have tried Katoolin in the Whonix Workstation,  but I find that Katoolin often breaks i).</p>
<ol start="25">
<li>A VPS with your  pentest tools installed is a valuable commodity; I call mine DeathStar, and I can call down some thunder from my Nexus 7 2013 flo (and a prepaid Wireless hotspot) from pretty much anywhere.</li>
</ol>
<p>There are some providers who do not give a damn about the traffic leaving your VM as long as you are using a VPN and  a DMCA does not come their way.</p>
<p>For hackers and freedom fighters, get your VPS from a country outside 14 Eyes countries (providers in Eastern European/former Soviet Block countries can be both dirt cheap and extremely honorable; just do your research and have tolerance for the occasional technical issue).</p>
<p>You could pay with laundered/tumbled Bitcoin; even better are those providers who except gift cards (much like some VPN providers do)as payment.</p>
<p>Have another party buy the gift cards a good distance away from you; you can find some of these  providers who take gift cards  on Low End Box. The VPS can be a valuable addition to the encrypted USB above (as you now have a host/node to catch your reverse shells without sacrificing Tor) when combined with SSH or IPsec (such as Strongswan, which is in the<br>
Debian repos).</p>
<ol start="26">
<li>Again, this post was long because I am busy, and Iwanted to make the contribution I felt I owed this site since shortly after it began. If you have technical questions concerning  (or any questions in general), please post them as comments and I will definitely get you back an answer.</li>
</ol>
            <p><small>25 posts - 14 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/shared-thoughts-after-6-years-in-pentesting/2492">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/shared-thoughts-after-6-years-in-pentesting/2492</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 09:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-2492</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/shared-thoughts-after-6-years-in-pentesting/2492.rss">Shared thoughts after 6+ years in Pentesting</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What&#39;s in a Red Team?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[sprtn]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h2>What’s in a Red Team?</h2>
<p>If you’re interested in information security, you’ve probably heard “penetration testing” and “red teaming” used interchangeably. However, for those of us actually doing red teaming, they’re not necessarily the same. So what do they mean?</p>
<hr>
<h3>Penetration Testing</h3>
<p>Penetration testing refers to various forms of simulating attacks on systems, networks, and facilities. Some types of penetration testing include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Web application pentesting: Assessing web applications to find vulnerabilities or other flaws.</li>
<li>Network pentesting: Assessing the security of a network, through various means. This can mean internal or external network testing.</li>
<li>Physical pentesting: Assessing the physical security of a facility. Can include lock picking, spoofing/cloning RFID badges, jumping fences, and many other things.</li>
</ul>
<p>Each of these types of penetration testing can be performed in some different contexts. In some cases, a pentester performs the test with no prior knowledge of the target environment. This is called a “black box” pentest. In other cases, the tester will be given information about the environment. This type of test is called a “white box” pentest. There is also “gray box” pentesting, which is in between the two. Additionally, black box pentesting is generally performed without informing the defensive staff. White box testing is usually performed with the knowledge of defenders.</p>
<p>So where does red teaming fit in?</p>
<hr>
<h3>Red Teaming</h3>
<p>Red teaming is a type of pentesting, but it’s different than a normal pentest in several ways. The most important aspect, in my opinion, is that a red team engagement should be adversarial. “Adversarial” means a couple different things to me:</p>
<p>First, red teaming should represent a real threat. Red teams should strive to attack organizations in the same way that real attackers are operating. By adapting TTPs ( Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures) from real attackers, red teams can show how an organization will fare against a real attack.</p>
<p>Second, red teaming should test the organization’s defenders. I find that it’s most valuable when the red team operates without the knowledge of the defenders; so that the defenders are forced to respond just like they would with a real attacker.</p>
<p>Lastly, a red team engagement works best when you remove scope restrictions, and allow the red team to assess the organization in whole. Attackers aren’t given restrictions when attacking an organization; red teams should be given as much leeway as possible, within the limits of the law.</p>
<h3>Why Red Team?</h3>
<p>Why would an organization have a pentest, as opposed to a red team exercise? When should an organization have a red team exercise?</p>
<p>A pentest is a good way for a company to take a look at the risks that they face. It can give a good assessment of the overall technical security of the organization, and can give the organization an idea of how effective their technical controls are at preventing common attacks.</p>
<p>A red team exercise is focused on one thing: demonstrating how attackers would attack the organization. A red team exercise won’t find every vulnerability that exists, and red teams are only interested in finding vulnerabilities that advance them towards the goal.</p>
<p>Normally, an organization should have penetration tests done for a couple years before moving to red teaming. Red teaming is most effective when an organization has a mature security practice, along with a solid defensive team that can learn from the red team’s findings.</p>
<hr>
<p>I hope that gives you folks a bit of background into why red teaming is important, and how it differs from ordinary pentesting. Stay tuned for some war stories about my experience doing both pentesting and red teaming!</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/whats-in-a-red-team/1797">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/whats-in-a-red-team/1797</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 02:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-1797</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/whats-in-a-red-team/1797.rss">What&#39;s in a Red Team?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How NOT to Write a Security Blog</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[dtm]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So I was browsing the net like you do and I came across this security blog.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/5/54181be8824eed7d8a5d56e4f46f86db5dae6067.PNG" width="690" height="270"></p>
<p>Looks interesting. Let’s check it out.</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>What’s this?</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/0/0455cdcd96f6cc1bf70908dc81aa02374a562d8c.PNG" width="690" height="392"></p>
<h1>u fokin’ w0t m8te?</h1>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/956dd16303e1432debc9bfd61fccb171cd4f0c50.PNG" width="690" height="144"></p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/0/0a8323af66b92e8f5311a21005c121cfa1b4ff2b.PNG" width="690" height="158"></p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/6/6f54daa2577655c12ac58cbc943f939842ed5ed2.PNG" width="690" height="420"></p>
<h1>ill bash yer fookin ead in, i sweah on me mum</h1>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/8/8b2a86e3337bac4171f4c3cbb73c68ba833e7795.PNG" width="451" height="73"></p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 7 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-not-to-write-a-security-blog/1367">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-not-to-write-a-security-blog/1367</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 06:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-1367</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-not-to-write-a-security-blog/1367.rss">How NOT to Write a Security Blog</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>DEFCON 16: Toying with Barcodes</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[EnergyWolf]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I really enjoyed this Defcon talk, because it’s about something that we all see and use everyday, but probably take for granted. And yet, there is a whole world of interesting vulnerabilities and potential for exploitation attached. It’s a good reminder to look for the stuff that hides in plain sight.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qT_gwl1drhc">DEFCON 16: Toying with Barcodes</a></p>

            <p><small>6 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/defcon-16-toying-with-barcodes/906">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/defcon-16-toying-with-barcodes/906</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 16:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-906</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/defcon-16-toying-with-barcodes/906.rss">DEFCON 16: Toying with Barcodes</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>5 Things to learn from Mr. Robot (TV Series)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Webster]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello everybody, this is Webster.</p>
<p>First of all, my favorite TV Series Mr. Robot is back with season 2, and It gets better and better with S02E03 being the best of them all. In this article, we’ll talk about Things you can learn about InfoSec from Mr. Robot TV Series.</p>
<p>If you don’t know about Mr. Robot, then you are living in a world full of Illusions. Mr. Robot is an American drama–thriller television series created by Sam Esmail. It stars Rami Malek as Elliot Alderson, a cybersecurity engineer and hacker who suffers from social anxiety disorder and clinical depression.</p>
<p>Elliot is recruited by an insurrectionary anarchist known as “Mr. Robot”, played by Christian Slater, to join a group of hacktivists. The group aims to cancel all debts by attacking the large corporation E Corp.</p>
<p>This show takes technical realism to levels unprecedented for Hollywood. Without further ado, here are five information security lessons from season 1 of Mr. Robot.</p>
<p><strong>1. A Hacker can compromise your phone in seconds, and you’ll never even know it:</strong> Hackers don’t need to steal your phone — that would be too obvious, and would only give them access to your data from the past.</p>
<p>Instead, they can gain control of your phone using spyware. They can do this in minutes, and you’ll never even know.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/1X/32652b2117c2b333dad094ec5948dcbd986d2f05.jpeg" width="654" height="366"></p>
<p>In Mr. Robot, one of the characters (<strong>Tyrell Wellick</strong>) installs a root kit on someone’s phone in less time than it takes to shower. Using Flexispy — a widely-used Android spyware tool — the character “roots” the phone — putting it in superuser mode — and then hides the normal superuser icon to obscure the fact that the phone has been tampered with.</p>
<p>From now on, Tyrell is able to monitor all of that phone’s digital and audio communications.</p>
<p><strong>2.Don’t Accept CD or USB drives from strangers:</strong> Emerging from the subway, a boombox-blasting rapper offers you a free copy of his newest album.</p>
<p>Now, you wouldn’t take candy from some guy in bellbottom jeans and stick it in your mouth. Don’t take a CD from some guy in a flat-bill cap and stick it in your computer!</p>
<p>To be fair, you would still need to execute a file. In Mr. Robot, hackers use an alluring filename like “Free iTunes Gift Card.exe” to dupe the victim into double-clicking it. This installs a Remote Access Trojan (RAT), effectively giving the attacker access to files and even webcams. Creepy.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/1X/caa48ee3967b8cd1db046fde837e7cd99b53294d.jpeg" width="654" height="355"></p>
<p><strong>3.Hide Things in Plain Sight:</strong> Sometimes the best place to hide things is right out in the open. Who would think twice about that binder of old rock albums on your floor?</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/1X/8085098193ce7ffe407e052d6bbd7ca7e7005583.jpeg" width="654" height="363"></p>
<p>What looks like a normal CD — that even plays their album scrawled on it with a sharpie—actually contains an extra layer of data stashed within.</p>
<p>Removed from any network access, the only way to read the data on these CDs would be to physically enter the premise and get a hold of them. You’d then for at least long enough to spin up an optical drive and dump their contents.</p>
<p><strong>4.If you aren’t using Bluetooth, then Turn It Off:</strong> If an attacker discovers an open bluetooth connection on your device, they could connect their own keyboard to it and start inputing commands.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/1X/7e31939a6a8b5c3e34f18080ea665effb15d90cb.jpeg" width="654" height="412"></p>
<p>Yes, it is possible to open up a terminal with a series of hotkeys in both Windows and OS X, and from there type in malicious commands. As a bonus, turning off Bluetooth when you’re out and about will reduce your battery consumption.</p>
<p><strong>5.You are your own greatest vulnerability:</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Do you know where the weakest link in any Security System is? It’s you, with your shitty passwords and how you share every part of your life online from Geo-tagging everything you do, to a photo you post of your new ATM Card.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Throughout Mr. Robot, the most common exploit is good old social engineering — manipulating people into doing what you want.</p>
<p>Here are some red flags to look out for when interacting with strangers:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>A phone call that jumps straight into “I just need to ask you some security questions first” — many services use the same security questions, and these could also be used to speed up a brute-force attempt to guess your password.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A stranger approaches you with an all-too-plausible story and asks to use your phone — this is an easy way to get your phone number or other identifying information.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Your own vanity, laziness, love of family, or fear of germs — these are all vulnerabilities that an attacker can take advantage of. If a stranger seems to be winding you up emotionally for no reason, they may be more than just a mean person. They may be an attacker.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>That’s it for now. I hope you like the article (which I am sure you will if you are a Mr. Robot fan).</p>
<p><span class="hashtag-raw">#Peace</span>!</p>
<p>Post originally written at: <a href="https://www.techbible.org/2016/07/5-things-learn-mr-robot-tv-series/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://www.techbible.org/2016/07/5-things-learn-mr-robot-tv-series/</a></p>
            <p><small>9 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/5-things-to-learn-from-mr-robot-tv-series/803">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/5-things-to-learn-from-mr-robot-tv-series/803</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 13:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-803</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/5-things-to-learn-from-mr-robot-tv-series/803.rss">5 Things to learn from Mr. Robot (TV Series)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Happy sysadmin day &#39;16! =)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[ivlb]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://pitstop.manageengine.com/sysadminday/2016.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Videos and memes are worth a petabyte of words =)</a></p>
<p>Happy sysadmin day to all troopers out there, may the Murphy not be with you!</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-sysadmin-day-16/784">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-sysadmin-day-16/784</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 11:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-784</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-sysadmin-day-16/784.rss">Happy sysadmin day &#39;16! =)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>I&#39;m officially here!</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[spylegion]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello fellas! I’m happy to announce that I have free time and will be more active here! Also, I want to share my experience and my journey:</p>
<p>Everything started five years ago. I was searching forums to learn C++ and C#, but stopped for a while to go on vacation. Upon returning from that trip, I was very motivated to learn about how “cheats” work, how to perform a DDoS, and about botnets, along with many other things.</p>
<p>I will not promote any site. I had one <em>booter</em> and I was one of those people who thought, “whoa, I can DDoS everything.” I guess I was a script kiddie, but I <em><strong>never</strong></em> acted like one.</p>
<p>After that, I discovered that hacking is more complicated than inputting, “IP : , Time : , Method” and pressing enter to take down everything.</p>
<p>It took me 1-2 years to realize lot of things and how they work. Also, I have met many cool people like <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/pry0cc">@pry0cc</a>, <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/oaktree">@oaktree</a>, <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/anon79434934">@anon79434934</a>, and <span class="mention">@unh0lys0da</span>, and I’m glad I joined this awesome community!</p>
<p>And guys, never stop dreaming because one day, they will become true. In the next few days, I will share something that I learned. Expect me!</p>
<p>Sincerely,<br>
spylegion (a.k.a., shammy)</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/im-officially-here/617">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/im-officially-here/617</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 17:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-617</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/im-officially-here/617.rss">I&#39;m officially here!</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Activating Turboboost, are you skidding me?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IoTh1nkN0t]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve noticed something over the years: you should never trust your doctor blindly.<br>
In fact, don’t trust anyone merely because they are an “expert” or a “professional.”</p>
<p>There is this idea that certain things can only be understood with a degree.<br>
It’s funny, the misconception that a degree defines understanding.<br>
See what’s going on here? or where I’m going with this?</p>
<p>Too often I see a very cool article to which everyone replies,<br>
“Nice article, but it’s too advanced for me.”</p>
<p>Really? Did you do any research?<br>
Or did you just see some weird syntax and/or some unfamiliar words?</p>
<p>Let go of this humbleness / insecurity / no-can-do mentality. You can do far more than you think.<br>
I try to leave some clues in my articles, saying that it just takes some reading and research,  <em>not</em> a Nobel Prize, to grasp the concepts.</p>
<p>Just make an effort; it will be worth it.</p>
<p>I’ll start a series on how to self-educate.</p>
<p><span class="mention">@unh0lys0da</span></p>
            <p><small>10 posts - 7 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/activating-turboboost-are-you-skidding-me/590">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/activating-turboboost-are-you-skidding-me/590</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 12:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-590</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/activating-turboboost-are-you-skidding-me/590.rss">Activating Turboboost, are you skidding me?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What do you love about InfoSec?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The Infomation Security Community is an awesome community, and ones like ours really rock. The one factor in my opinion that really drives the community is the people. Tinkering and Hacking, taking things apart to see how they work, is in our nature, and a community that operates and thinks like that works really well together.</p>
<p>In my opinion, the thought of hundreds of people coming together from different cultures and locations and sharing knowledge with each other, makes me really think about how amazing a platform like the internet has helped to educate and build a new generation of indepedent thinkers and fixers. My passion for this community is great, even though this place is only just getting started.</p>
<p>I couldn’t post this without first asking you, the community, this very important question.</p>
<h1>What do <em>you</em> love about InfoSec?</h1>
<p>I look forward to seeing your responses!</p>
            <p><small>16 posts - 11 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-love-about-infosec/542">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-love-about-infosec/542</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 20:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-542</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-love-about-infosec/542.rss">What do you love about InfoSec?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the Inspiration category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[oaktree]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A place for stories. Tell the community a story so that all sorts of members can be inspired by your struggles, and the determination that brought you here.</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/about-the-inspiration-category/528">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/about-the-inspiration-category/528</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-528</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/about-the-inspiration-category/528.rss">About the Inspiration category</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Advice for Computer Science College Students</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[_py]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p></p><aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://i0.wp.com/www.joelonsoftware.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/11969842.jpg?fit=32%2C32&amp;ssl=1" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2005/01/02/advice-for-computer-science-college-students/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc" title="12:15AM - 02 January 2005">Joel on Software – 2 Jan 05</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://i0.wp.com/www.joelonsoftware.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/11969842.jpg?fit=400%2C400&amp;ssl=1" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h3><a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2005/01/02/advice-for-computer-science-college-students/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Advice for Computer Science College Students</a></h3>

<p>Despite the fact that it was only a year or two ago that I was blubbering about how rich Windows GUI clients were the wave of the future, college students nonetheless do occasionally email me askin…</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<br>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://s1.wp.com/i/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://blog.cobaltstrike.com/2012/12/26/computer-science-undergrad-to-offensive-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc" title="06:44PM - 26 December 2012">Strategic Cyber LLC – 26 Dec 12</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/427a827e1b53c708ab0698ed1fac2195d6c45b98.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="" height="">

<h3><a href="https://blog.cobaltstrike.com/2012/12/26/computer-science-undergrad-to-offensive-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">How to Milk a Computer Science Education for Offensive Security Skills</a></h3>

<p>Recently, a poster on reddit asked how to get into offensive security as a student studying Computer Science. Before the post was removed, the poster expressed an interest in penetration testing or…</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<p></p>
<p>The above links are an interesting read for those who are/will be Computer Science students.</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/advice-for-computer-science-college-students/257">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/advice-for-computer-science-college-students/257</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 08:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-257</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/advice-for-computer-science-college-students/257.rss">Advice for Computer Science College Students</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
