<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy - 0x00sec - The Home of the Hacker</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/c/social/philosophy/51</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Philosophy&#39; category Philosophy section.&lt;br&gt;Some rules to avoid wars:</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:36:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/c/social/philosophy/51.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Why the most skilled people in this field thinks that our world is a simulation?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Darkvault]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Is coding  a proof that our world is a simulation and our God is a coder. I’m  really  curious and this topic is boggling my mind for a long time with 3D bio printers scientist   are  already building living organs. Very strange that alot of  people  are not serious about this question .</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-25421</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421.rss">Why the most skilled people in this field thinks that our world is a simulation?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Rules or Otherwise Unfavorable Behavior?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[9lives304]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m not here to ruffle any feathers, be blackballed, banned, tar and feathered, shunned, obfuscated, castrated, or otherwise 0x00sec socially persecuted…<br>
(Takes a deep breath)<br>
After regurgitating all of that wit just for y’all, I wanted to see if you have a Marketplace page for selling/buying Software and/or Services that may or may not be of questionable legality?  I ask this formally in advance as to not upset the hierarchy by a 1st day 0x00sec ‘Noob’.<br>
-9lives304</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 14:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-18368</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368.rss">Rules or Otherwise Unfavorable Behavior?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Psyche-reconnaissance journey - How well do you know yourself?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[hunter]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This journey was nothing like I’ve ever experienced before. As I went deeper into my psyche, what I discovered made me feel like someone else was behind the wheel of my life all these years and I was just a mere observer.</p>
<p>I started by exploring the unconscious elements that make up my personality. Habits, personality traits, patterns of behavior, urges and desires. I have to say, if you’re doing something unconsciously, it’s not easy for you to realize that you’re doing it. Imagine that you’re trying to find something you didn’t even know existed. I was lucky, my girlfriend has extreme awareness of her surroundings, and she helped me realize things about myself that I hadn’t noticed before.</p>
<p>I discovered all the elements that I could put together and say, “Yeah, that looks pretty much like me”. None of these elements were the result of my conscious choices. Each of them was caused by wounds inflicted on my subconscious by some experience during my lifetime.</p>
<p>For example, computers have been pulling me in for as long as I can remember. According to the stories my mother told me, in the old days when I didn’t even know what a computer was, every time we walked past a computer store, I pointed my finger and said, “Mom, I want this”. No doubt this is the kind of story that one would call “this kid is born with a talent for computers”. To be honest, that’s what I thought until recently. But at the end of my journey, I faced a different truth.</p>
<p>Now it was time to discover the cause of all this. This mission proved to be far more difficult than the first one. I had to search through all the experiences from the days of my life that I barely remembered and find the ones that had an impact on my soul. I finally discovered all my experiences associated with these elements.</p>
<p>That was it. Now I knew all the elements that made up my personality. I knew which traumas in my subconscious caused these elements. And I knew exactly which events and circumstances in the early stages of my life caused these traumas. Now I had all the pieces of the puzzle, and I was terrified of what I saw once I assembled the pieces. In Jung’s own words, I was meeting with my own “shadow”.</p>
<p>I wanted to dedicate this unfinished story to you on my 1st anniversary on 0x00sec. Of course, time passed quickly <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/psyche-reconnaissance-journey-how-well-do-you-know-yourself/10316">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/psyche-reconnaissance-journey-how-well-do-you-know-yourself/10316</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 03:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-10316</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/psyche-reconnaissance-journey-how-well-do-you-know-yourself/10316.rss">Psyche-reconnaissance journey - How well do you know yourself?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>We, the ones who rule the world</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Thirsty-Robot]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>We, the Ones who Rule the World: A new manifest by Thirsty-Robot</h1>
<br>
We all know that the world has changed. Things aren’t the same as they were 20 years ago. And mostly in a field of study so vast as computer science or security. New individual are coming to the field every day; “How are websites made?”, “Why do I have internet”, the questions we’ve all asked, and the ones that other generations will ask too. Computers have grow smaller, thinner, more complex, and even amusing. New generations don’t have the tools to explore this, not because they don’t want to, but because companies don’t let them. If you have an Iphone, go ahead and look at it, do you see any screws, do you even see a lid that can be open, besides the SD and SIM compartment? The answer is a big well-deserved NO. It’s almost as it was planned.
<p>The world has changed and not for good. Everything is connected, everyone can know who you are on a simple Facebook or Google search (assuming that you use this services). Yes, you can change the default configuration, but how is a kid going to know this if he has never seen how his father opens the cover of his phone to get the battery out. For the new generations it just works and that’s it. New generation are not aware of how their data is being manipulated, how every stroke, every character they type is monitored, they were borned in a giant role-play of 1984.</p>
<p>We as hackers need to change this. We need to share with new generations, we need to make open-source projects “meta”. We, more than most individuals have the potential to change the modern world. We understand how it works, we understand on what it is based. As you read this, your government is maybe fighting a hacker, or other global powers on the internet. Computers are everything. There is not Illuminati, there is not “giant see it all eye”, there is only us. The guy who helped the teacher with her or his computer, the guy who made a pirate radio for fun, the guy who eats books on every subject, the guy that it’s full of curiosity, the guy that wanted to hack his favorite game to buy an item.</p>
<p>We are the ones that created the systems which makes our lives so easy. We are the cool guys now, we are not weird anymore, we have a voice, we are something. Correction we are everything.</p>
<p>We, are the ones who rule the world, let’s show them…</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/we-the-ones-who-rule-the-world/7171">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/we-the-ones-who-rule-the-world/7171</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 05:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-7171</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/we-the-ones-who-rule-the-world/7171.rss">We, the ones who rule the world</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Are our lives a simulation? (Meaning of life debate)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Derfloink]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Hello my burning listener</h1>
 I've been long time away from this platform and I'd like to discuss about the meaning of life. Are we in a simulation, is there even a reason that we live or is this all the plan of a(n allmighty ) Beeing?<h1>My opinion</h1>
I'm one of these guys that think we're in a simulation, but the afterlife all these religions are talking about can be more or less true. After your death you may wake up  and you're back in your "real" life. Or you will be thrown back to life in another body, like budhists and hinduists think. The point is that we can't prove that were in a simulation. It's impossible as proving that there is a god. But I can say one thing: Nothing can be allmighty. If it's allmighty it could make a rock that's even to heavy for itself and can throw it away (which should be impossible because it would break rule nr. 1). But if it's a simulation the question is still not solved. Because what's 'real' lifes meaning? The question no one has the answer for because there is no absolute answer.
<p>Thank you for reading until now. Share your opinion about that topic and hopefully my english has become a little bit better <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=9" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
            <p><small>16 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/are-our-lives-a-simulation-meaning-of-life-debate/5786">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/are-our-lives-a-simulation-meaning-of-life-debate/5786</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 11:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-5786</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/are-our-lives-a-simulation-meaning-of-life-debate/5786.rss">Are our lives a simulation? (Meaning of life debate)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Malware by definition</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[REal0day]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>Malware</strong>: <em>Malware, or malicious software, is any program or file that is harmful to a computer user. Malware includes computer viruses, worms, Trojan horses and spyware. These malicious programs can perform a variety of functions, including stealing, encrypting or deleting sensitive data, altering or hijacking core computing functions and monitoring users’ computer activity without their permission.</em> -<a href="http://searchsecurity.techtarget.com/definition/malware" rel="nofollow noopener"> source</a></p>
<p>What about malware that is not harmful to a user, but is also not installed by the intent of the user? Outside of legalspace, Is it still malware? If it’s not malicious, but someone installs it, is it still malware?</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/malware-by-definition/4417">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/malware-by-definition/4417</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-4417</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/malware-by-definition/4417.rss">Malware by definition</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Computer Hacking and Ethics - Thoughts on computer crime from 1985</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[besa]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I came by an article today from 1985 (find it here: <a href="https://people.eecs.berkeley.edu/~bh/hackers.html" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Computer Hacking and Ethics by Brian Harvey University of California, Berkeley</a>).</p>
<p>Here’s the few paragraphs that stuck with me:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In the context of computer systems, there is a similar dichotomy. There are some career criminals who steal by electronic means. This small group poses a large problem for society, but it’s not a new one. Thieves are thieves. Just as banks use special armored cars, they must also develop special armored computer systems. But the rest of us don’t use armored cars for routine transportation, and we don’t need armored computer systems for routine communication either. (Of course there is a large middle ground between heavy security and no security at all. My purpose here is not to decide exactly what security measures are appropriate for any particular computer system. Instead, I just want to make it clear that, while in this paper I’m not trying to address the problem of professional criminals, I’m not trying to deny that there is such a problem either.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To bring forward some modern day context, in my country/state joyriding can carry <a href="https://www.armstronglegal.com.au/criminal-law/offences/stealing/joy-riding" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">up to 5 years in prison</a>, while the hacking equivilent is <a href="https://www.armstronglegal.com.au/criminal-law/offences/computer/restricted-data" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">up to 2 years in prison</a>.</p>
<p>Maybe things have improved? I don’t know. If memory serves me people usually get charged with way more computer offence than should actually be applicable (though this is wholly conjecture on my part without any more research)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is also a middle ground between the young person who happens to break unimportant rules in the innocent exercise of intellectual curiosity and the hardened criminal. Consider the hypothetical case of a young man whose girlfriend moves to Australia for a year, and so he builds himself a blue box (a device used to place long distance telephone calls without paying for them) and uses it to chat with her for an hour every other day. This is not intellectual curiosity, nor is it a deliberate, long-term choice of a life of crime. Instead, this hypothetical adolescent, probably normally honest, has stepped over a line without really noticing it, because his mind is focused on something else. It would be inappropriate, I think, to pat him on the head and tell him how clever he is, and equally inappropriate to throw him in prison. What we must do is call his attention to the inconsistency between his activities and, most likely, his own moral standards.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Advocating for lighter sentences for nonviolent crime is a good thing in my opinion. An interesting hypothetical the author introduced, the distinction between a one-off crime and a choice to live through crime is one usually left up to the discretion judge and/or jury here.</p>
<p>Anyway, though you guys might like a short read.</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/computer-hacking-and-ethics-thoughts-on-computer-crime-from-1985/2205">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/computer-hacking-and-ethics-thoughts-on-computer-crime-from-1985/2205</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 02:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-2205</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/computer-hacking-and-ethics-thoughts-on-computer-crime-from-1985/2205.rss">Computer Hacking and Ethics - Thoughts on computer crime from 1985</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Let&#39;s hack impostor syndrome: A discussion</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[fraq]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Let’s talk impostor syndrome. Some of us know what it is, but I bet all of us are dealing with it at some level.</p>
<p>Just so we’re all on the same page, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">here’s</a> a good working definition of impostor syndrome:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Impostor syndrome (also known as impostor phenomenon or fraud syndrome) is a concept describing high-achieving individuals who are marked by an inability to internalize their accomplishments and a persistent fear of being exposed as a “fraud”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Among our community, we are typically very driven people. We try hard, knowledge is hard-won, and we challenge ourselves daily. Yet somehow, many of us feel like we are in a place where others will discover that we are a fraud. That we haven’t rightfully earned the position we are in.</p>
<p>With that, let’s open up the discussion: How do you see it in our community? In yourself? How do you deal with it?</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/lets-hack-impostor-syndrome-a-discussion/2003">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/lets-hack-impostor-syndrome-a-discussion/2003</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 23:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-2003</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/lets-hack-impostor-syndrome-a-discussion/2003.rss">Let&#39;s hack impostor syndrome: A discussion</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Books and Philosophy</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cal0X]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello,</p>
<p>I am a bookworm and proud of it. It’s my strong opinion that books form a person’s psychology and a connection to the realm outside our imagination. I’d like to know what genre of books do you appreciate?</p>
<p>Please avoid the technical books as much as possible since the whole point of this discussion is to know your other side and the spectrum of philosophies.</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/books-and-philosophy/1433">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/books-and-philosophy/1433</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 13:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-1433</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/books-and-philosophy/1433.rss">Books and Philosophy</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Question for all</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Valentine]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I have a question for all,</p>
<p>Why do people Hack?</p>
<p>Is it that  people like to cause trouble? Is it because of money and fame? Or is it darker?</p>
<p>My answer to this question is:</p>
<p>People hack because they want to feel a connection, they want to feel a sense of worth that they can’t seem to find within people. A computer is a living being… it has a heart, a brain, bones, even if it’s man made. People hack because they can get back at those that hurt them in the past. Without a connection to anything we are nothing more then just a machine. That’s why I believe people hack because there’s a sense of belonging…</p>
<p>What’s your opinion?</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/question-for-all/985">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/question-for-all/985</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 13:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-985</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/question-for-all/985.rss">Question for all</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Is Hacking a Superpower? Intellectual Discussion</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I recently have just finished watching “The Internet’s own Boy”; a film about Aaron Swartz. He alone has achieved a lot in terms of politics and ‘hacking’ society before his tragic suicide.</p>
<p>During the Documentary he and his brothers speak of Programming being a super power, as they are able to achieve super-human things with the help of a computer and some code. This got me thinking, and brings me on to my point and question:</p>
<h3><a name="p-4447-is-hacking-a-superpower-1" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-4447-is-hacking-a-superpower-1"></a>Is Hacking a Superpower?</h3>
<p>The ability to manipulate computers, code and other virtual things is regarded fairly trivial, but when these systems interact and control real life things, they have real life consequences. When viewing this abstractly I begin to think, that surely hacking can be considered a form of superpower, and one that can be learned.</p>
<p>What are your thoughts, and at what point do you think it is regarded an extension of human ability?</p>
<p>Edit: In Pop-culture and games like Watchdogs it is treated as if it were a super power.</p>
<h2><a name="p-4447-the-internets-own-boy-2" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-4447-the-internets-own-boy-2"></a>The Internets Own Boy</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9vz06QO3UkQ">The Internet's Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz | full movie (2014)</a></p>

            <p><small>24 posts - 10 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/is-hacking-a-superpower-intellectual-discussion/895">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/is-hacking-a-superpower-intellectual-discussion/895</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 12:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-895</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/is-hacking-a-superpower-intellectual-discussion/895.rss">Is Hacking a Superpower? Intellectual Discussion</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Read this first, 2 simple rules</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IoTh1nkN0t]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Philosophy section.<br>
Some rules to avoid wars:</p>
<ul>
<li>No political debates (to prevent shitstorms)</li>
<li>Keep it cool, everyone has a right to their opinion</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/read-this-first-2-simple-rules/830">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/read-this-first-2-simple-rules/830</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 13:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-830</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/read-this-first-2-simple-rules/830.rss">Read this first, 2 simple rules</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Illusion of Control: Intellectual Discussion</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Merozey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Today I wanted to share something with you that has been on my mind, it doesn’t really collide with hacking or infosec in general, but still it is fairly relevant. And yes, this topic has definitely been pulled from Mr. Robot as Elliott has talked about all the time, and it’s been on my mind lately, so why not discuss it with you guys too.</p>
<hr>
<p>**</p>
<p><strong>THE ILLUSION OF CONTROL</strong></p>
<p>**</p>
<p>So the dilemma here really is the fact that we as humans believe and perceive that we have control of our lives, careers, relationships friendships and so on. And that when we fail in our endeavors, it’s a part of the process, in which it makes us feel at ease knowing that we can recover from that occurrence, and we’ll be fine. Which is where i’d say the illusion of having control comes in, because what if we exactly didn’t have control in the first place, and could of continued with our ‘path’, and yet failed, hence the illusion of control.</p>
<p>Then, I would also counter-argue that perspective, saying that the illusion of us having control is the definition of human imperfection, that we’re never supposed to have control, and that’s what makes us unique, and the entire process of achieving our goal worth the fight.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Elliott’s view:</strong></p>
<p>Elliott’s view is that, we are <strong>being</strong> controlled by this 1% that he talked about in Season 1. But, what if that’s false, and they only have an impact on the flow of economy, and the media/advertisements have an impact on our perception. And we can decide the rest, so to say.</p>
<p>I hope you have some interesting responses.</p>
            <p><small>27 posts - 11 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/the-illusion-of-control-intellectual-discussion/817">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/the-illusion-of-control-intellectual-discussion/817</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 22:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-817</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/the-illusion-of-control-intellectual-discussion/817.rss">The Illusion of Control: Intellectual Discussion</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
