<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584</link>
    <description># Welcome Back!

Here with us today is the one and only @maderas !

Be sure to comment any further questions you have and to vote for our next guest in the Poll at the bottom.

Thanks for stopping by!

### Professional Career and Advice
 
**1. For starters, can you tell us a bit about yourself and your current role/job/work?**

I am a guy who believes that InfoSec/Hacking is my best chance to make the world a better place and leave/make an impact that outlives me.

I’m obsessed with making an impact upon the world; I believe that this art (hacking, by which I also mean Red Teaming/Penetration Testing) presents me with an opportunity to make this world a better place.

I think that to achieve all of the latter, I must endeavor to share all that I learn/experience to help this game evolve.

As the bar rises, those who work toward being the best they can be evolve as well.

I believe that if you are afraid to share everything you know, then you are not working hard enough.

Much of this experience originates from my career. Since January of 2011 I&#39;ve worked as a Penetration Tester/Red Team Operator.

From the beginning, I have focused my skill set on real world, adversarial tactics. This involves a ton of extra study /prep on my part, as I need to track down the work/C2 of BlackHats in the wild study/train until I can emulate their tactics.**

For the last few years (and ever on into the future if I can help it) I’ve endeavored to only work in sectors where I believe I can make an impact that is meaningful to the world at large.

In the past, I&#39;ve worked as the Cybersecurity Penetration Test and Vulnerability Assessment Lab for Schneider Electric and as Senior Red Team Operator/Penetration Tester for National Grid.

Currently, I am between gigs and doing volunteer work for Tutanota (pentesting their next e-mail platform) and running the #CyberpunkisNow project via Twitter, which seeks to create a dialogue between people around the world as to how technology continues to permeate our civilization.

I also release original InfoSec content by my Twitter account, which has grown rapidly and is now reaching millions of screens after only 3 months

**2. How did you first get into the field? (What was your first hack?)**

As long as I can remember, I wanted to be a hacker. I saw a cable news story about The L0pht when I was 12; as a son of Massachusetts, I realized that this was happening in my backyard. I could do this…

As for my first hack, when I was working a customer service gig I used to hack around on the Intranet. The buildings HVAC systems had default creds &amp;amp; the Intranet itself was horribly insecure. I used to bring a live distro of Knoppix STD into work and practice there…nothing really malicious, just exploration.

**3. Can you give a rough map from your beginnings to where you are now?**

As far back as 2006-2007 I was screwing around with Knoppix STD in my former employer’s Intranet (with their permission) after work/on breaks (I was also maintaining AV/AM and that kind of stuff though it wasn&#39;t my or anyone’s job).

By 2009 /2010 I was using Google’s bug bounty program as an excuse to practice vs. their networks/infrastructure; in December 2010/January 2011 I started doing consultant work and officially entered the world of professional InfoSec (where I have been professionally ever since in some form).

**4. What is one of the biggest struggles you overcame? And what’s been the biggest lesson you’ve learned in your career?**

My biggest struggle was also my biggest lesson: learning that in most big businesses, most of your managers/fellow employees arent going to care much about InfoSec. It will almost always take a back seat to profitability.

You have to realize that you yourself are there to help ensure the profitability/prosperity of your employer. Solutions are almost always going to be way more important to them then problems.

**5. Any advice for someone trying to land in a similar role/job?**

Understand the actual basics of Computer Science/Networking/It. You should endeavor to be able to exploit a system/network with the minimal resources possible.

I focused on living of the land from the very beginning of my career/training; it requires that you invest in actually learning things like Windows AD administration &amp;amp; not cutting corners in you training/study, but it is a priceless skill set to have.

Learn defensive skills; spending some time as a Network Analyst is invaluable. Again, the solutions are almost always worth more to the customer/client/employer then the problems.

Make friends with IT &amp;amp; System/Network Administrators if you are working an in-house position. Buy them coffee, talk to them often; there is usually a mutual interest in your and their interests that can result in an incredible skills/knowledge exchange.

You should learn to value all of the skill sets/experience of all the technology employees around you and endeavor to establish relationships based on mutual respect and skills/knowledge exchange.

If one of these employees is a greybeard Unix guru, they will provide insights into Linux/Unix Administration that are priceless (and almost all those I met could/would talk with me for hours, which was incredible).

We all suffer imposter syndrome; not knowing something is ok as long as you endeavor to learn it.

And ICMP/ping doesn’t have a dedicated port; managers running technical interviews love this question.

### Fun, personal stuff

**6. Windows, Mac, or Linux What do you run?**

I run Linux; usually Devuan (Debian without System-D), Qubes or On the job, I am OS agnostic; whatever gets the job done. If possible, I will try to suggest/demonstrate the value of open source, but I am not going to be an obnoxious neckbeard about it.

**7. Programming language(s) of choice?**

Python 2.7, bits and pieces of many other languages. Mainly enough to change/alter code in exploits/tools to get it to do what I need and recognize vulns like deserialization.

**8. Do you use a mechanical keyboard? Is it ortholinear?**

No; I use plain old HP keyboards; I&#39;ve seen some of the mechanical keyboards that have programmable tabs for scripts and stuff and would like to own one some day to build my Master Rig.

**9. Do you have any other hobbies or interests outside of infosec?**

Martial Arts; I’ve had 13 professional fights since 2005 in MMA/Muay Thai/Kickboxing. I&#39;ve competed in kyokushin full contact tournaments as well; I’ve been training in some form of combative since I was 5 (my father was an amateur boxer).

I love reading; I read voraciously. I love film; anime…learning.

I am a huge proponent of self improvement, but not necessarily through self improvement gurus or teachings. I like the classics, like the Tao, Hagakure, The Book Of Rings…and challenging myself.

Challenging myself to know/exceed my limitations probably satisfies my definition of self improvement perfectly.

**10. Any other fun gadgets or hardware at home/the office?**

I&#39;m a huge proponent of the Nexus 7 for Red Teaming/general computing given its power vs cost and ARM architecture; I will have material posted here about ti in 2019.

### Final Stuff

**11. How’d you find 0x00sec?**

The NullByte exodus; I used to number that amongst sources I checked out weekly. I lurked this place forever before joining.

**12. Any other fun fact or detail you’d like to share with the community?**

I admire all of your work; I have infrastructure I&#39;ve built out to keep an eye on things of interest. I don&#39;t know if everyone here knows how rare/beautiful the level of courtesy/talent is here.

**13. Do you have any advice for new, up-and-coming hackers?**

Don&#39;t cut corners; realize tools are just a means of helping to express skills/knowledge that there is no shortcut to ascertain. Your tooling no more makes you a hacker then buying a brush makes you a painter.

**14. Is there anything you’d like to say to the 0x00sec community?**

Thanks for providing a home for me; I went it alone for a long time and realized the upper levels of ability lay in congress with peers. I was right; my skills have grown exponentially in the last 2 years.

**15. Can you give us a HEX for your hat “color”?**

No Hex needed. I&#39;m Gray through and through. I have nothing against BlackHats; we aren&#39;t opponents until a job or circumstance makes us so and then it is only temporary.

I&#39;ve learned more from BlackHats/GrayHats then WhiteHat; most of it was knowledge I had to seek out/cultivate myself, but that is the best kind.

I am an ethical hacker not because it is a convenient term for marketing myself, or because a cert tells me what I am, but because my actions/work are governed by my ethics.

## Thanks for joining! Vote below for our next guest. See you then!
[poll type=regular results=always]
* dtm
* Nitrax
* _py
* Rain
* yuu
* IoTh1nkN0t
* egy
* nugget
* slobber
[/poll]</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 22:27:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Social</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/6</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-10584-6</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584.rss">Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[maderas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thhank you <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/skidd0">@skidd0</a> ; I am looking forward to answering any and all questions the community has for me regarding this.</p>
<p>And a huge thank you to you for these posts. I always look forward to them.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 22:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-10584-5</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584.rss">Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[maderas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>You are most welcome my friend</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 22:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-10584-4</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584.rss">Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[occupi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="skidd0" data-post="1" data-topic="10584">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/user_avatar/d.clarkee.co.uk/skidd0/48/1959_2.png" class="avatar"> skidd0:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>And ICMP/ping doesn’t have a dedicated port; managers running technical interviews love this question.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I love <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/maderas">@maderas</a> for this quote alone. What a wonderful interview, thank you for this!</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-10584-3</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584.rss">Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[skidd0]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>What a cool guy! Thanks for participating <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/maderas">@maderas</a>.  I’m sure we’ll have some extra questions for you popping up down below.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-10584-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584.rss">Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[skidd0]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Welcome Back!</h1>
<p>Here with us today is the one and only <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/maderas">@maderas</a> !</p>
<p>Be sure to comment any further questions you have and to vote for our next guest in the Poll at the bottom.</p>
<p>Thanks for stopping by!</p>
<h3>Professional Career and Advice</h3>
<p><strong>1. For starters, can you tell us a bit about yourself and your current role/job/work?</strong></p>
<p>I am a guy who believes that InfoSec/Hacking is my best chance to make the world a better place and leave/make an impact that outlives me.</p>
<p>I’m obsessed with making an impact upon the world; I believe that this art (hacking, by which I also mean Red Teaming/Penetration Testing) presents me with an opportunity to make this world a better place.</p>
<p>I think that to achieve all of the latter, I must endeavor to share all that I learn/experience to help this game evolve.</p>
<p>As the bar rises, those who work toward being the best they can be evolve as well.</p>
<p>I believe that if you are afraid to share everything you know, then you are not working hard enough.</p>
<p>Much of this experience originates from my career. Since January of 2011 I’ve worked as a Penetration Tester/Red Team Operator.</p>
<p>From the beginning, I have focused my skill set on real world, adversarial tactics. This involves a ton of extra study /prep on my part, as I need to track down the work/C2 of BlackHats in the wild study/train until I can emulate their tactics.**</p>
<p>For the last few years (and ever on into the future if I can help it) I’ve endeavored to only work in sectors where I believe I can make an impact that is meaningful to the world at large.</p>
<p>In the past, I’ve worked as the Cybersecurity Penetration Test and Vulnerability Assessment Lab for Schneider Electric and as Senior Red Team Operator/Penetration Tester for National Grid.</p>
<p>Currently, I am between gigs and doing volunteer work for Tutanota (pentesting their next e-mail platform) and running the <span class="hashtag">#CyberpunkisNow</span> project via Twitter, which seeks to create a dialogue between people around the world as to how technology continues to permeate our civilization.</p>
<p>I also release original InfoSec content by my Twitter account, which has grown rapidly and is now reaching millions of screens after only 3 months</p>
<p><strong>2. How did you first get into the field? (What was your first hack?)</strong></p>
<p>As long as I can remember, I wanted to be a hacker. I saw a cable news story about The L0pht when I was 12; as a son of Massachusetts, I realized that this was happening in my backyard. I could do this…</p>
<p>As for my first hack, when I was working a customer service gig I used to hack around on the Intranet. The buildings HVAC systems had default creds &amp; the Intranet itself was horribly insecure. I used to bring a live distro of Knoppix STD into work and practice there…nothing really malicious, just exploration.</p>
<p><strong>3. Can you give a rough map from your beginnings to where you are now?</strong></p>
<p>As far back as 2006-2007 I was screwing around with Knoppix STD in my former employer’s Intranet (with their permission) after work/on breaks (I was also maintaining AV/AM and that kind of stuff though it wasn’t my or anyone’s job).</p>
<p>By 2009 /2010 I was using Google’s bug bounty program as an excuse to practice vs. their networks/infrastructure; in December 2010/January 2011 I started doing consultant work and officially entered the world of professional InfoSec (where I have been professionally ever since in some form).</p>
<p><strong>4. What is one of the biggest struggles you overcame? And what’s been the biggest lesson you’ve learned in your career?</strong></p>
<p>My biggest struggle was also my biggest lesson: learning that in most big businesses, most of your managers/fellow employees arent going to care much about InfoSec. It will almost always take a back seat to profitability.</p>
<p>You have to realize that you yourself are there to help ensure the profitability/prosperity of your employer. Solutions are almost always going to be way more important to them then problems.</p>
<p><strong>5. Any advice for someone trying to land in a similar role/job?</strong></p>
<p>Understand the actual basics of Computer Science/Networking/It. You should endeavor to be able to exploit a system/network with the minimal resources possible.</p>
<p>I focused on living of the land from the very beginning of my career/training; it requires that you invest in actually learning things like Windows AD administration &amp; not cutting corners in you training/study, but it is a priceless skill set to have.</p>
<p>Learn defensive skills; spending some time as a Network Analyst is invaluable. Again, the solutions are almost always worth more to the customer/client/employer then the problems.</p>
<p>Make friends with IT &amp; System/Network Administrators if you are working an in-house position. Buy them coffee, talk to them often; there is usually a mutual interest in your and their interests that can result in an incredible skills/knowledge exchange.</p>
<p>You should learn to value all of the skill sets/experience of all the technology employees around you and endeavor to establish relationships based on mutual respect and skills/knowledge exchange.</p>
<p>If one of these employees is a greybeard Unix guru, they will provide insights into Linux/Unix Administration that are priceless (and almost all those I met could/would talk with me for hours, which was incredible).</p>
<p>We all suffer imposter syndrome; not knowing something is ok as long as you endeavor to learn it.</p>
<p>And ICMP/ping doesn’t have a dedicated port; managers running technical interviews love this question.</p>
<h3>Fun, personal stuff</h3>
<p><strong>6. Windows, Mac, or Linux What do you run?</strong></p>
<p>I run Linux; usually Devuan (Debian without System-D), Qubes or On the job, I am OS agnostic; whatever gets the job done. If possible, I will try to suggest/demonstrate the value of open source, but I am not going to be an obnoxious neckbeard about it.</p>
<p><strong>7. Programming language(s) of choice?</strong></p>
<p>Python 2.7, bits and pieces of many other languages. Mainly enough to change/alter code in exploits/tools to get it to do what I need and recognize vulns like deserialization.</p>
<p><strong>8. Do you use a mechanical keyboard? Is it ortholinear?</strong></p>
<p>No; I use plain old HP keyboards; I’ve seen some of the mechanical keyboards that have programmable tabs for scripts and stuff and would like to own one some day to build my Master Rig.</p>
<p><strong>9. Do you have any other hobbies or interests outside of infosec?</strong></p>
<p>Martial Arts; I’ve had 13 professional fights since 2005 in MMA/Muay Thai/Kickboxing. I’ve competed in kyokushin full contact tournaments as well; I’ve been training in some form of combative since I was 5 (my father was an amateur boxer).</p>
<p>I love reading; I read voraciously. I love film; anime…learning.</p>
<p>I am a huge proponent of self improvement, but not necessarily through self improvement gurus or teachings. I like the classics, like the Tao, Hagakure, The Book Of Rings…and challenging myself.</p>
<p>Challenging myself to know/exceed my limitations probably satisfies my definition of self improvement perfectly.</p>
<p><strong>10. Any other fun gadgets or hardware at home/the office?</strong></p>
<p>I’m a huge proponent of the Nexus 7 for Red Teaming/general computing given its power vs cost and ARM architecture; I will have material posted here about ti in 2019.</p>
<h3>Final Stuff</h3>
<p><strong>11. How’d you find 0x00sec?</strong></p>
<p>The NullByte exodus; I used to number that amongst sources I checked out weekly. I lurked this place forever before joining.</p>
<p><strong>12. Any other fun fact or detail you’d like to share with the community?</strong></p>
<p>I admire all of your work; I have infrastructure I’ve built out to keep an eye on things of interest. I don’t know if everyone here knows how rare/beautiful the level of courtesy/talent is here.</p>
<p><strong>13. Do you have any advice for new, up-and-coming hackers?</strong></p>
<p>Don’t cut corners; realize tools are just a means of helping to express skills/knowledge that there is no shortcut to ascertain. Your tooling no more makes you a hacker then buying a brush makes you a painter.</p>
<p><strong>14. Is there anything you’d like to say to the 0x00sec community?</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for providing a home for me; I went it alone for a long time and realized the upper levels of ability lay in congress with peers. I was right; my skills have grown exponentially in the last 2 years.</p>
<p><strong>15. Can you give us a HEX for your hat “color”?</strong></p>
<p>No Hex needed. I’m Gray through and through. I have nothing against BlackHats; we aren’t opponents until a job or circumstance makes us so and then it is only temporary.</p>
<p>I’ve learned more from BlackHats/GrayHats then WhiteHat; most of it was knowledge I had to seek out/cultivate myself, but that is the best kind.</p>
<p>I am an ethical hacker not because it is a convenient term for marketing myself, or because a cert tells me what I am, but because my actions/work are governed by my ethics.</p>
<h2>Thanks for joining! Vote below for our next guest. See you then!</h2>
<p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/1">Click to view the poll.</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-10584-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584.rss">Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
