<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>How to create your own Russian bot army</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370</link>
    <description> # How to create your own Russian bot army

![|380x406](upload://hVgYlplvefJMRsJKC8pcL8RvA3q.png)

Today, everywhere we look we hear talks about Russian bots taking over the internet.

From tampering with the US Election to spreading fake news and Pro Russian views on Facebook and Twitter.

I even found out they have [their own Wikipidea page!](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_web_brigades)

This got me really interested in the subject of bots and after many fun experiments i can finally share with you how with little effort, you too can have your own bot army!

What i will go over in this post:

How create a bot that performs actions on a given website

Detecting if a website is vulnerable to bot actions

Bypassing Captchas and Login Security measurements

Recommended Prerequisites:

* Basic understanding of HTML and Javascript
* Basic understanding of HTTP
* Basic development in python

## Disclaimer

I condemn the use of any information in this article for malicious bot activity,

The information in this article is to be used for learning purposes only

***
## The good old bot days

In the good old bot creating days, it was enough to write a simple script that sends HTTP POST and GET requests a website in order to imitate the behavior of a standard user on the website.

Today things are much more complicated, websites use many Javascript scripts on their pages, these scripts are then loaded and executed on the Browser of the user using the website and are used to traverse and communicate with the website properly .

The simple HTTP GET and POST bot scripts won’t work in the current websites because the Javascript code needs to run on a proper browser or else it won’t be executed , this can cause many errors and malfunctions that cripples any bot activity that operates in the old method.

The easy way to counter this problem is to switch from automating HTTP GET and POST requests to automating the browser in itself.

## Selenium: your partner in crime

### What is Selenium?

[Selenium](https://www.selenium.dev/) is a framework for testing web applications.

Selenium allows us to automate actions on browsers with a feature called Selenium WebDriver.

This driver accepts commands from the user and sends them to the browser to be executed.

These commands include:

* Typing keys in text boxes
* Clicking objects and buttons on a webpage
* Surfing to a webpage
* simulating mouse cursor movement and dragging objects
* Many more..

Selenium WebDriver currently supports automation with the following web browsers:

Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Edge, Internet Explorer

### Using Selenium

Selenium is very fun and easy to use, it has a well documented [user guide](https://selenium-python.readthedocs.io/) that explains how to perform many automation actions using any of it’s supported browsers

I will show an example of using Selenium in Python:

![|485x70](upload://a0iWGYdk1Glg0ADNC9A0oMJSHiW.png)

The code above will open a chrome browser and navigate to the link.

We will reach the following webpage:

![|602x344](upload://s11SeHRYwxmAM3zxofhqywxi1El.png)

This website can be used to test mouse actions that are performed by the user.

Interacting with website elements:

Let’s make our bot click the left click button in the mouse testing website.

To perform clicks and keyboards typing with website elements, we must find the element we wish to interact with and then perform our action.

One of the easiest ways to find the element we wish to interact with is by right clicking on the element we wish to interact with and clicking on inspect.

This action will show will open the html element’s code

We will then select copy-&gt;copy xpath to copy the XPath of the element.

XPath is an xml expression that we can use to navigate through different elements on a given webpage

![|602x235](upload://mdr2RnZG8NUMhH8DqbZc26rKfrg.png)

we can then search for this element with Selenium and click it:

![|602x60](upload://rjg3LQOoTUA4iHpruxVXlrOlhJ.png)

It’s possible to chain together many actions on different website elements and create fully automated bot activities .

An example of a behaviour of a comment leaving bot on an E-Commerce website

that only allows members to leave comments:

1.Surf to E-Commerce registration page

2.Click on the registration text boxes to type a fake generated username and password

3.Click on the register button

4.Surf to a product webpage

5.Click on the comment text box and write a comment

Bypassing simple bot detection techniques

Many websites have an array of techniques that can be used to counter bot activity.

One of the easiest ways they can detect bots using Selenium is by looking for fingerprints left by the software.

One example of such fingerprint:

When a web browser is run by Selenium, a property named webdriver is added to the browser’s navigator variable and is set to true.

If we press F12 and write this property in a Selenium controlled browser we will see the following result:

![|413x226](upload://4UPusWYbyA1V4KZSBGEuPLcbNOX.png)

If we preform the same action on a normal user controlled browser, the result will look like this:

![|243x109](upload://82quzdSQRejaBe2dgtBkw5x88mI.png)

Website’s can easily detect this value using Javascript code and realize that the user using the website is in fact a Selenium bot, this might cause the website  to limit the user from pefroming certain actions and it might even cause his account to be blocked account entirely in extreme cases .

An easy fix to counter this problem is to execute the following command which will set this webdriver property to undefined each time a new webpage is loaded.
This will cause the Selenuim controlled browser to appear like in any normal user controlled browser:

![|552x179](upload://nK6sudJaNPvzd8uw2XfW9PsXxn1.png)

Websites might use additional techniques to detect bot detection.

These include:

* Tracking Mouse cursor movements - not moving the cursor on the website might be a red flag for the website
* Comparing Activity - comparing the bot’s activity to that of an average user
* Keystroke Speed - comparing keystroke speed to that of an average user

All of these techniques can be bypassed by programming our bot to act in certain ways that simulate real human behaviour.

We can make the keystrokes slower, add mistakes to our clicks and even just move the mouse around to click different tabs on the website to make it seem like a normal curious user.

With a bit of coding, your bot can become a real boy :)
***

## Spotting ideal websites for bots

If you&#39;re struggling to decide which next website your bot army should invade, it’s important to look out for these points in order to find the website that will allow you the most control over your’e bot users.

### User Registration

Normally, we will want our bots to be registered to our target website.

Registered user’s have additional features and each bot that successfully registered to the website equals more power in your hands over the website.

Secured websites usually have one or more of the following methods to eliminate/mitigate multiple user registrations from the same person. We will go over each method and discuss if and how we can overcome it

### Method 1: Verifying Emails

Websites will often require you to enter an email address when registering with a new account, they will then send a verification mail to the same email address and activate your account only if you pressed the verification link.

This can be bypassed very easily by using one of the following temporary mail websites:

https://temp-mail.org/

https://www.fakemail.net/

https://10minutemail.com/

Each bot that wishes to register can go to one of the temporary mail websites, extract its own temporary mail address and register with it on the target website.

The bot can then go back to the mail website and click the verification link that was sent to mail address, by doing so the account will be registered and activated successfully

### Method 2: Phone numbers

Websites registration sometimes requires a phone number to be entered.

Sometimes this field is only used by the website for ad purposes and entering a fake Mongolian number in the phone number field is enough to bypass this.

Other times, the website will require you to verify your account by entering a code that will be sent to that number.

This is a harder method to bypass as you will need to match a phone number for each bot you wish to register on the website.

It’s possible to use online websites that receive SMS codes and display them in order to automate the process of registering, reading the SMS code that was to the number and entering it on the website for verification.

The following websites are recommended for this purpose:

https://receive-smss.com/

https://sms24.me/

In the next section, we will go over a more advanced method that websites use as a direct countermeasure against bot activity and we will show different methods to combat it.

***
## Bypassing Captchas

Captchas stand for - Completely Automated Public [Turing test](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_test) to tell Computers and Humans Apart.

Captchas are used by various websites to prevent bots from simply logging in or registering to a website easily, they require the user to perform a test that is difficult to predict it’s answer, the reasoning is that humans will pass this test and bots won’t and that will allow the website to protect itself from any bot activity.

### Not all Captchas are created equal

![|348x269](upload://jqZrbea1sV8MoQYa0lvIxlxyG9b.png)

Let’s take the a look at Geetest’s slider captcha,

A popular captcha used by many websites to prevent bots from taking over.

Using Selenium and python image processing, I was able to create a program that can correctly answer the slider captcha about 30% of the time.

30% isn’t perfect but considering that the page can be refreshed and the captcha can be retaken several times, it results in the bot eventually answering the captcha correctly normally under a minute.

Imagine tens of thousands of bots bypassing the slider captcha after 3-4 attempts and registering to a website successfully, this scenario shows how this captcha is not effective against a massive bot activity and can be easily bypassed by any bot master who wishes to flood a website with his bots.

### What about ReCaptcha?

![|492x312](upload://g9KnbWI1LkQqNYNQGyWkZShQP8M.png)

Google’s ReCaptchas is the most popular and well known captcha software,

It’s present on most websites today, it’s extremely difficult to solve and even humans have a hard time answering it sometimes.

A cheap and easy way of bypassing google’s ReCaptchas can be found not by attempting more complicated image processing but actually by harnessing the smartest thing we have besides that - the human brain.

There are multiple services which offer captcha solving solutions for very cheap prices,

Services like AntiCaptcha and 2Captcha have workers who are trained at solving the most difficult captchas at minimum speed,the pricing is between 1$ to 3$ for 1000 ReCaptchas

And it can be used by any bot master to enable his bot army to take over the most Captcha secured websites for a cheap amount..
***

## Conclusions

Today we went over the basics to creating your first bot army,

We examined how old bot armies operated and we talked about the differences in how to operate bots today in modern websites.

We then reviewed and discussed different security measures websites might use upon registration to the website and how some can still be bypassed automatically by bots

Finally, we talked about the most advanced countermeasure against bots - Captchas.

We went over different techniques to overcome Captchas and learned along the way that not all captchas are created equal.

I hope you all enjoyed this article, i’d like to end with a quote from [our friendly internet
quote generating bot](https://inspirobot.me/).

“If you try, you can be the first to prove something that the rest of the world refuses to prove”


### Sources:

ReCaptcha Solving Websites

https://anti-captcha.com/

https://2captcha.com/?from=9669456

Code:

https://github.com/peduajo/geetest-slice-captcha-solver

https://github.com/x24whoamix24/bypass_geetest_slider

https://he.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAPTCHA

https://www.geetest.com/en/demo</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:14:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Programming</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>How to create your own Russian bot army</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 121 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/6</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 23:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-22370-6</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370.rss">How to create your own Russian bot army</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How to create your own Russian bot army</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Snowwolf]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>this is my first robot</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-22370-5</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370.rss">How to create your own Russian bot army</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How to create your own Russian bot army</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[testcase]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Great article, thank you <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 15:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-22370-4</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370.rss">How to create your own Russian bot army</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How to create your own Russian bot army</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[bondbenz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Damn, i do like bots something , they did help me alot until now and now i m looking forward to make a relation between bots and machine learning that would be great and also great share mate.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 02:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-22370-3</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370.rss">How to create your own Russian bot army</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How to create your own Russian bot army</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[c0z]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve always loved the idea of automating web processing technologies like ReCaptcha, login portals, and other similar things. I remember when <a href="https://archive.org/details/pack-ec783cefdee77a5def9a4c1f5b221ebaf8b1950d_201707" rel="nofollow noopener">trollforge</a> was the bleeding edge in open research, among other things. Anyway great post.</p>
<p>*trollforge: it’s an archive because the original url <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AMA/comments/h0ess/i_founded_the_gnaa_ama/" rel="nofollow noopener">gnaa.fr</a> doesn’t exist anymore. The president weev was found to be a white supremiscist. I only am mentioning them here for the research value. They pioneered captcha research.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 23:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-22370-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370.rss">How to create your own Russian bot army</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How to create your own Russian bot army</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[x24whoami24]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>How to create your own Russian bot army</h1>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/7/7d9e5cbade161fd55a5fe1fcff332ccad23e8a7c.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="hVgYlplvefJMRsJKC8pcL8RvA3q" width="380" height="406"></p>
<p>Today, everywhere we look we hear talks about Russian bots taking over the internet.</p>
<p>From tampering with the US Election to spreading fake news and Pro Russian views on Facebook and Twitter.</p>
<p>I even found out they have <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_web_brigades" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">their own Wikipidea page!</a></p>
<p>This got me really interested in the subject of bots and after many fun experiments i can finally share with you how with little effort, you too can have your own bot army!</p>
<p>What i will go over in this post:</p>
<p>How create a bot that performs actions on a given website</p>
<p>Detecting if a website is vulnerable to bot actions</p>
<p>Bypassing Captchas and Login Security measurements</p>
<p>Recommended Prerequisites:</p>
<ul>
<li>Basic understanding of HTML and Javascript</li>
<li>Basic understanding of HTTP</li>
<li>Basic development in python</li>
</ul>
<h2>Disclaimer</h2>
<p>I condemn the use of any information in this article for malicious bot activity,</p>
<p>The information in this article is to be used for learning purposes only</p>
<hr>
<h2>The good old bot days</h2>
<p>In the good old bot creating days, it was enough to write a simple script that sends HTTP POST and GET requests a website in order to imitate the behavior of a standard user on the website.</p>
<p>Today things are much more complicated, websites use many Javascript scripts on their pages, these scripts are then loaded and executed on the Browser of the user using the website and are used to traverse and communicate with the website properly .</p>
<p>The simple HTTP GET and POST bot scripts won’t work in the current websites because the Javascript code needs to run on a proper browser or else it won’t be executed , this can cause many errors and malfunctions that cripples any bot activity that operates in the old method.</p>
<p>The easy way to counter this problem is to switch from automating HTTP GET and POST requests to automating the browser in itself.</p>
<h2>Selenium: your partner in crime</h2>
<h3>What is Selenium?</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.selenium.dev/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Selenium</a> is a framework for testing web applications.</p>
<p>Selenium allows us to automate actions on browsers with a feature called Selenium WebDriver.</p>
<p>This driver accepts commands from the user and sends them to the browser to be executed.</p>
<p>These commands include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Typing keys in text boxes</li>
<li>Clicking objects and buttons on a webpage</li>
<li>Surfing to a webpage</li>
<li>simulating mouse cursor movement and dragging objects</li>
<li>Many more…</li>
</ul>
<p>Selenium WebDriver currently supports automation with the following web browsers:</p>
<p>Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Edge, Internet Explorer</p>
<h3>Using Selenium</h3>
<p>Selenium is very fun and easy to use, it has a well documented <a href="https://selenium-python.readthedocs.io/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">user guide</a> that explains how to perform many automation actions using any of it’s supported browsers</p>
<p>I will show an example of using Selenium in Python:</p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/461e953e239faf2ca7026180e23aaaaf715f9762.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="a0iWGYdk1Glg0ADNC9A0oMJSHiW" width="485" height="70"></p>
<p>The code above will open a chrome browser and navigate to the link.</p>
<p>We will reach the following webpage:</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/c/c45aaf39939e612f45cda8a4ecca988b9bda5ac9.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/s11SeHRYwxmAM3zxofhqywxi1El.png?dl=1" title="" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/c/c45aaf39939e612f45cda8a4ecca988b9bda5ac9_2_602x344.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="s11SeHRYwxmAM3zxofhqywxi1El" width="602" height="344" srcset="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/c/c45aaf39939e612f45cda8a4ecca988b9bda5ac9_2_602x344.png, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/c/c45aaf39939e612f45cda8a4ecca988b9bda5ac9.png 1.5x, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/c/c45aaf39939e612f45cda8a4ecca988b9bda5ac9.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/c/c45aaf39939e612f45cda8a4ecca988b9bda5ac9_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<p>This website can be used to test mouse actions that are performed by the user.</p>
<p>Interacting with website elements:</p>
<p>Let’s make our bot click the left click button in the mouse testing website.</p>
<p>To perform clicks and keyboards typing with website elements, we must find the element we wish to interact with and then perform our action.</p>
<p>One of the easiest ways to find the element we wish to interact with is by right clicking on the element we wish to interact with and clicking on inspect.</p>
<p>This action will show will open the html element’s code</p>
<p>We will then select copy-&gt;copy xpath to copy the XPath of the element.</p>
<p>XPath is an xml expression that we can use to navigate through different elements on a given webpage</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9bb4a61677c88f5fcc999741681daefd611ca2d6.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/mdr2RnZG8NUMhH8DqbZc26rKfrg.png?dl=1" title="" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/9/9bb4a61677c88f5fcc999741681daefd611ca2d6_2_602x235.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="mdr2RnZG8NUMhH8DqbZc26rKfrg" width="602" height="235" srcset="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/9/9bb4a61677c88f5fcc999741681daefd611ca2d6_2_602x235.png, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/9/9bb4a61677c88f5fcc999741681daefd611ca2d6_2_903x352.png 1.5x, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/9/9bb4a61677c88f5fcc999741681daefd611ca2d6_2_1204x470.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/9/9bb4a61677c88f5fcc999741681daefd611ca2d6_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<p>we can then search for this element with Selenium and click it:</p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/0/031652aad9acd4ea2bb95737eb04ba6e0697aa5f.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="rjg3LQOoTUA4iHpruxVXlrOlhJ" width="602" height="60"></p>
<p>It’s possible to chain together many actions on different website elements and create fully automated bot activities .</p>
<p>An example of a behaviour of a comment leaving bot on an E-Commerce website</p>
<p>that only allows members to leave comments:</p>
<p>1.Surf to E-Commerce registration page</p>
<p>2.Click on the registration text boxes to type a fake generated username and password</p>
<p>3.Click on the register button</p>
<p>4.Surf to a product webpage</p>
<p>5.Click on the comment text box and write a comment</p>
<p>Bypassing simple bot detection techniques</p>
<p>Many websites have an array of techniques that can be used to counter bot activity.</p>
<p>One of the easiest ways they can detect bots using Selenium is by looking for fingerprints left by the software.</p>
<p>One example of such fingerprint:</p>
<p>When a web browser is run by Selenium, a property named webdriver is added to the browser’s navigator variable and is set to true.</p>
<p>If we press F12 and write this property in a Selenium controlled browser we will see the following result:</p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/22754606eaf6a34c08c8da304471721656438963.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="4UPusWYbyA1V4KZSBGEuPLcbNOX" width="413" height="226"></p>
<p>If we preform the same action on a normal user controlled browser, the result will look like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/3/3857a244f4c8a3958cb2f0c89db66db69260d3d0.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="82quzdSQRejaBe2dgtBkw5x88mI" width="243" height="109"></p>
<p>Website’s can easily detect this value using Javascript code and realize that the user using the website is in fact a Selenium bot, this might cause the website  to limit the user from pefroming certain actions and it might even cause his account to be blocked account entirely in extreme cases .</p>
<p>An easy fix to counter this problem is to execute the following command which will set this webdriver property to undefined each time a new webpage is loaded.<br>
This will cause the Selenuim controlled browser to appear like in any normal user controlled browser:</p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/a/a6682d742ff517af52f6341adb48cb38109b31df.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="nK6sudJaNPvzd8uw2XfW9PsXxn1" width="552" height="179"></p>
<p>Websites might use additional techniques to detect bot detection.</p>
<p>These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tracking Mouse cursor movements - not moving the cursor on the website might be a red flag for the website</li>
<li>Comparing Activity - comparing the bot’s activity to that of an average user</li>
<li>Keystroke Speed - comparing keystroke speed to that of an average user</li>
</ul>
<p>All of these techniques can be bypassed by programming our bot to act in certain ways that simulate real human behaviour.</p>
<p>We can make the keystrokes slower, add mistakes to our clicks and even just move the mouse around to click different tabs on the website to make it seem like a normal curious user.</p>
<p>With a bit of coding, your bot can become a real boy <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<hr>
<h2>Spotting ideal websites for bots</h2>
<p>If you’re struggling to decide which next website your bot army should invade, it’s important to look out for these points in order to find the website that will allow you the most control over your’e bot users.</p>
<h3>User Registration</h3>
<p>Normally, we will want our bots to be registered to our target website.</p>
<p>Registered user’s have additional features and each bot that successfully registered to the website equals more power in your hands over the website.</p>
<p>Secured websites usually have one or more of the following methods to eliminate/mitigate multiple user registrations from the same person. We will go over each method and discuss if and how we can overcome it</p>
<h3>Method 1: Verifying Emails</h3>
<p>Websites will often require you to enter an email address when registering with a new account, they will then send a verification mail to the same email address and activate your account only if you pressed the verification link.</p>
<p>This can be bypassed very easily by using one of the following temporary mail websites:</p>
<p><a href="https://temp-mail.org/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://temp-mail.org/</a></p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://fdn.r.worldssl.net/img/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="113" height="114">
      <a href="https://www.fakemail.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">FakeMail</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:210/213;"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/f/fa561a209a665c02f175bb74bc5fa77ff18738d7.png" class="thumbnail" width="210" height="213"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.fakemail.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">FakeMail | Disposable Temp Mail</a></h3>

<p>The temp mail address to keep your original email safe. The disposable temporary email platform provides fleeting email addresses.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://10minutemail.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">10minutemail.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="" class="thumbnail" width="" height="">

<h3><a href="https://10minutemail.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">10 Minute Mail - Free Anonymous Temporary email - 10 Minute Mail - Free...</a></h3>



  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>Each bot that wishes to register can go to one of the temporary mail websites, extract its own temporary mail address and register with it on the target website.</p>
<p>The bot can then go back to the mail website and click the verification link that was sent to mail address, by doing so the account will be registered and activated successfully</p>
<h3>Method 2: Phone numbers</h3>
<p>Websites registration sometimes requires a phone number to be entered.</p>
<p>Sometimes this field is only used by the website for ad purposes and entering a fake Mongolian number in the phone number field is enough to bypass this.</p>
<p>Other times, the website will require you to verify your account by entering a code that will be sent to that number.</p>
<p>This is a harder method to bypass as you will need to match a phone number for each bot you wish to register on the website.</p>
<p>It’s possible to use online websites that receive SMS codes and display them in order to automate the process of registering, reading the SMS code that was to the number and entering it on the website for verification.</p>
<p>The following websites are recommended for this purpose:</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://receive-smss.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Receive SMS Online</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="" class="thumbnail" width="" height="">

<h3><a href="https://receive-smss.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Receive SMS online for Free - without any Registration</a></h3>

<p>receive-smss.com is a free website to receive SMS and voice mail online. You can use it from all the countries and for Gmail,Facebook,Linked and more</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cdn.sms24.me/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="236" height="236">
      <a href="https://sms24.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">SMS24.me</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/5/5d02ee201c58e8867d1c0d5c49b224bbdef0750a.png" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="236" height="236">

<h3><a href="https://sms24.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Receive SMS Online | Temporary Phone Numbers</a></h3>

<p>No Registration. Receive SMS online FREE using our disposable/temporary numbers from  USA, Canada, UK, Russia, Ukraine, Israel and other countries. Receive anonymous verification code from around the world.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>In the next section, we will go over a more advanced method that websites use as a direct countermeasure against bot activity and we will show different methods to combat it.</p>
<hr>
<h2>Bypassing Captchas</h2>
<p>Captchas stand for - Completely Automated Public <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_test" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Turing test</a> to tell Computers and Humans Apart.</p>
<p>Captchas are used by various websites to prevent bots from simply logging in or registering to a website easily, they require the user to perform a test that is difficult to predict it’s answer, the reasoning is that humans will pass this test and bots won’t and that will allow the website to protect itself from any bot activity.</p>
<h3>Not all Captchas are created equal</h3>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/8/8836608a5f09f77de49a7bbfe90b7396a2f26081.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="jqZrbea1sV8MoQYa0lvIxlxyG9b" width="348" height="269"></p>
<p>Let’s take the a look at Geetest’s slider captcha,</p>
<p>A popular captcha used by many websites to prevent bots from taking over.</p>
<p>Using Selenium and python image processing, I was able to create a program that can correctly answer the slider captcha about 30% of the time.</p>
<p>30% isn’t perfect but considering that the page can be refreshed and the captcha can be retaken several times, it results in the bot eventually answering the captcha correctly normally under a minute.</p>
<p>Imagine tens of thousands of bots bypassing the slider captcha after 3-4 attempts and registering to a website successfully, this scenario shows how this captcha is not effective against a massive bot activity and can be easily bypassed by any bot master who wishes to flood a website with his bots.</p>
<h3>What about ReCaptcha?</h3>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/7/713cdf8069be3f7ace19f0a5c9fb4761c2f5e7dc.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/g9KnbWI1LkQqNYNQGyWkZShQP8M.png?dl=1" title="" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/7/713cdf8069be3f7ace19f0a5c9fb4761c2f5e7dc_2_492x312.png" alt="" data-base62-sha1="g9KnbWI1LkQqNYNQGyWkZShQP8M" width="492" height="312" srcset="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/7/713cdf8069be3f7ace19f0a5c9fb4761c2f5e7dc_2_492x312.png, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/7/713cdf8069be3f7ace19f0a5c9fb4761c2f5e7dc_2_738x468.png 1.5x, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/7/713cdf8069be3f7ace19f0a5c9fb4761c2f5e7dc.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/7/713cdf8069be3f7ace19f0a5c9fb4761c2f5e7dc_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<p>Google’s ReCaptchas is the most popular and well known captcha software,</p>
<p>It’s present on most websites today, it’s extremely difficult to solve and even humans have a hard time answering it sometimes.</p>
<p>A cheap and easy way of bypassing google’s ReCaptchas can be found not by attempting more complicated image processing but actually by harnessing the smartest thing we have besides that - the human brain.</p>
<p>There are multiple services which offer captcha solving solutions for very cheap prices,</p>
<p>Services like AntiCaptcha and 2Captcha have workers who are trained at solving the most difficult captchas at minimum speed,the pricing is between 1$ to 3$ for 1000 ReCaptchas</p>
<p>And it can be used by any bot master to enable his bot army to take over the most Captcha secured websites for a cheap amount…</p>
<hr>
<h2>Conclusions</h2>
<p>Today we went over the basics to creating your first bot army,</p>
<p>We examined how old bot armies operated and we talked about the differences in how to operate bots today in modern websites.</p>
<p>We then reviewed and discussed different security measures websites might use upon registration to the website and how some can still be bypassed automatically by bots</p>
<p>Finally, we talked about the most advanced countermeasure against bots - Captchas.</p>
<p>We went over different techniques to overcome Captchas and learned along the way that not all captchas are created equal.</p>
<p>I hope you all enjoyed this article, i’d like to end with a quote from <a href="https://inspirobot.me/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">our friendly internet<br>
quote generating bot</a>.</p>
<p>“If you try, you can be the first to prove something that the rest of the world refuses to prove”</p>
<h3>Sources:</h3>
<p>ReCaptcha Solving Websites</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://anti-captcha.com/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://anti-captcha.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">anti-captcha.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/361;"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/9/c/9c4d505c1d599ee781d1d95f92ee2b1cf59bf8b2_2_690x361.png" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="361" srcset="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/9/c/9c4d505c1d599ee781d1d95f92ee2b1cf59bf8b2_2_690x361.png, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/9/c/9c4d505c1d599ee781d1d95f92ee2b1cf59bf8b2_2_1035x541.png 1.5x, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/9/c/9c4d505c1d599ee781d1d95f92ee2b1cf59bf8b2.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/9/c/9c4d505c1d599ee781d1d95f92ee2b1cf59bf8b2_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://anti-captcha.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Anti Captcha: captcha solving service. Bypass reCAPTCHA, FunCaptcha, image...</a></h3>



  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/b/4/b4eb35342f62915a11ee04c78026efc882bfe510.png" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://2captcha.com/?from=9669456" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">2captcha.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:493/353;"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/2/d/2da5e069c3f997d2b75d4fd228ada94fc5635a16.png" class="thumbnail" width="493" height="353"></div>

<h3><a href="https://2captcha.com/?from=9669456" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Online CAPTCHA Solving and Image Recognition Service.</a></h3>



  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>Code:</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://github.com/peduajo/geetest-slice-captcha-solver" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/d034f442e72729c9617a30b5426468e4f9693879.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h3><a href="https://github.com/peduajo/geetest-slice-captcha-solver" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">peduajo/geetest-slice-captcha-solver</a></h3>

<p>Solver for the geetest sliding captcha. Contribute to peduajo/geetest-slice-captcha-solver development by creating an account on GitHub.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://github.com/x24whoamix24/bypass_geetest_slider" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/6/63998b26295261f34c9e0b5334ec0502f106835d.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h3><a href="https://github.com/x24whoamix24/bypass_geetest_slider" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">x24whoamix24/bypass_geetest_slider</a></h3>

<p>Code that bypasses geetest slider captchas using Selenuim and python image processing - x24whoamix24/bypass_geetest_slider</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox wikipedia">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://he.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAPTCHA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">he.wikipedia.org</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:250/69;"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/d3a6fb72018b4127e7c21e5b772acff51b1ddf7e.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="250" height="69"></div>

<h3><a href="https://he.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAPTCHA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">CAPTCHA</a></h3>

<p>CAPTCHA במחשבים הוא מבחן אתגר מענה (challenge-response) שמטרתו להבטיח שהתשובה אינה מופקת באמצעות מחשב. במנגנון מעורב בדרך כלל מחשב המייצר שאלה אקראית, כזו שלאדם קל לענות עליה אך למחשב קשה מאוד. מבחן CAPTCHA בדרך כלל מבקש מהמשתמש להקליד אותיות או מספרים המופיעים בצורה מעוותת על המסך.
 CAPTCHA הוא סוג של מבחן טיורינג, שבו מחשב ממונה על הבדלה בין אדם למחשב, בשונה ממבחן טיורינג הקלאסי בו אדם באמצעות שיחה ושאלות מנסה להבדיל בין מחשב לאדם.
 את השם CAPTCHA טבעו לראשונה לואי פון אהן, מנואל בלום, ניקולאס ...</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.geetest.com/static/imgs/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="128" height="128">
      <a href="https://www.geetest.com/en/demo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">geetest.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="" class="thumbnail" width="" height="">

<h3><a href="https://www.geetest.com/en/demo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GeeTest CAPTCHA | Demo</a></h3>



  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 07:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-22370-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-create-your-own-russian-bot-army/22370.rss">How to create your own Russian bot army</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
