<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>[ARG] The Red Triangle Solving -- Part2</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368</link>
    <description>Hello folks, today I&#39;m going to continue **The Red Triangle** series.
If you haven&#39;t seen the first one yet, you can check it here:  [[ARG] The Red Triangle Solving — Part 1](https://0x00sec.org/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part-1/7272) 

Last time, we have deciphered the Monoalphabetic Substitution symbols from the images and got a link to google drive, that lead us to the next link of the puzzle.
Now that we are all set, let&#39;s jump into it !

# Getting started
Once you open the link, you are prompted with the same symbolic red triangle ,as in the previous one, and underneath you have an interesting image.

![image2|690x350](upload://M5t4ciTxaai2XFtQvzW6drXUFE.png)
Also, on the background is playing an audio file, but this time, you can hear something strange at the beginning. We will get into that later.

I have viewed the source code and found this:
![source|469x339](upload://22ZimZ97kEM46mg3xeVvhN3cX53.png)
**Note:** _*apparently Coeus&#39;s was a Titan in the Greek mythology and represented rational intelligence.*_

Besides that, I found nothing, so I went on and downloaded the image and the audio file.

# The Image
At first glance, I thought that was something hidden in it ,as I thought on the previous one, and started to fire some tools on it, but found nothing... So, I thought maybe it has something to do with the meaning of the structure because I saw a pattern in the image.
I have started researching this kind of pattern and it&#39;s actually the Fibonacci sequence.
Besides that, I found nothing. 
_( If you guys want to have a look at it, contact me and maybe we could find something. I still think it&#39;s a message or some sort of thing in it. )_

# The Audio File
Ok, so this one got my attention since I entered the site, because you can hear in the first part of the song some strange &quot;satanic&quot; like voices. _(or it&#39;s just my mind that hears that. I&#39;M FINE OK!?)_
I popped up audacity ,after installing it, and started playing with the audio. It didn&#39;t seem to be something odd in the first place.
![audacity1|690x173](upload://g52vT0hIVtEyVsXhOaTFxzZK1oi.png)

But take a closer look....

![audacity2|559x300](upload://eQnjBb3040ZBCc0sCoRPYmaExlA.png)
If you listen to it to, in the first 30-40 seconds the song it&#39;s not started yet and those &quot;satanic&quot; voices are actually what we see here, in audacity. Maybe it&#39;s there on purpose.

So... we got something, but what can we do with it....?
I tried to reverse the audio, change its speed, research on hiding messages in audio files, with the hope that something might pop up, but... unfortunately, I got nothing.

In this moment, I started looking again at everything and analyze it more carefully than I have done before. After a few hours I found out that when you reverse it, the voices start to have more sense.
Then just made some speed adjustments, some coffee and finally got something.
Those &quot;satanic&quot; voices were just a robot who tells the next onion link for the puzzle.

_**By the way:**_  _this part was very struggling because the robots voice is really hard to hear and got a hard time getting what the link was. But hey, got it in the end._:face_with_monocle: 

The link was: [spoiler]https://paxt4n6urwx7uiah.onion.link/112417[/spoiler]
_At the moment the links are down, as far as I saw..._

# Conclusion
That was a new territory for me and had a lot of fun solving these puzzles.
Hope you guys loved it as much as I love making those articles and more importantly, I hope that you had fun.
Looking forward to see if you find something in the Fibonacci image and also hope you see in the next one.
Thanks for reading ! :grin:</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 01:39:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Cryptology</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>[ARG] The Red Triangle Solving -- Part2</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 01:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-7368-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368.rss">[ARG] The Red Triangle Solving -- Part2</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[ARG] The Red Triangle Solving -- Part2</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[404Err0r]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello folks, today I’m going to continue <strong>The Red Triangle</strong> series.<br>
If you haven’t seen the first one yet, you can check it here:  <a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part-1/7272">[ARG] The Red Triangle Solving — Part 1</a></p>
<p>Last time, we have deciphered the Monoalphabetic Substitution symbols from the images and got a link to google drive, that lead us to the next link of the puzzle.<br>
Now that we are all set, let’s jump into it !</p>
<h1>Getting started</h1>
<p>Once you open the link, you are prompted with the same symbolic red triangle ,as in the previous one, and underneath you have an interesting image.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/0/056f97291ec61c45b55538ace6043f0f7795efae.png" alt="image2" data-base62-sha1="M5t4ciTxaai2XFtQvzW6drXUFE" width="690" height="350"><br>
Also, on the background is playing an audio file, but this time, you can hear something strange at the beginning. We will get into that later.</p>
<p>I have viewed the source code and found this:<br>
<img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/0/0e5ad59888d74c8efe468ac95f6f03cc5d766e95.png" alt="source" data-base62-sha1="22ZimZ97kEM46mg3xeVvhN3cX53" width="469" height="339"><br>
<strong>Note:</strong> <em><em>apparently Coeus’s was a Titan in the Greek mythology and represented rational intelligence.</em></em></p>
<p>Besides that, I found nothing, so I went on and downloaded the image and the audio file.</p>
<h1>The Image</h1>
<p>At first glance, I thought that was something hidden in it ,as I thought on the previous one, and started to fire some tools on it, but found nothing… So, I thought maybe it has something to do with the meaning of the structure because I saw a pattern in the image.<br>
I have started researching this kind of pattern and it’s actually the Fibonacci sequence.<br>
Besides that, I found nothing.<br>
<em>( If you guys want to have a look at it, contact me and maybe we could find something. I still think it’s a message or some sort of thing in it. )</em></p>
<h1>The Audio File</h1>
<p>Ok, so this one got my attention since I entered the site, because you can hear in the first part of the song some strange “satanic” like voices. <em>(or it’s just my mind that hears that. I’M FINE OK!?)</em><br>
I popped up audacity ,after installing it, and started playing with the audio. It didn’t seem to be something odd in the first place.<br>
<img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/7/70b4a603df2636848d11932330977c26b9ddb7a6.png" alt="audacity1" data-base62-sha1="g52vT0hIVtEyVsXhOaTFxzZK1oi" width="690" height="173"></p>
<p>But take a closer look…</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/6/680a1bfecb93411bd59add4f5d0b2335658013de.png" alt="audacity2" data-base62-sha1="eQnjBb3040ZBCc0sCoRPYmaExlA" width="559" height="300"><br>
If you listen to it to, in the first 30-40 seconds the song it’s not started yet and those “satanic” voices are actually what we see here, in audacity. Maybe it’s there on purpose.</p>
<p>So… we got something, but what can we do with it…?<br>
I tried to reverse the audio, change its speed, research on hiding messages in audio files, with the hope that something might pop up, but… unfortunately, I got nothing.</p>
<p>In this moment, I started looking again at everything and analyze it more carefully than I have done before. After a few hours I found out that when you reverse it, the voices start to have more sense.<br>
Then just made some speed adjustments, some coffee and finally got something.<br>
Those “satanic” voices were just a robot who tells the next onion link for the puzzle.</p>
<p><em><strong>By the way:</strong></em>  <em>this part was very struggling because the robots voice is really hard to hear and got a hard time getting what the link was. But hey, got it in the end.</em><img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/face_with_monocle.png?v=9" title=":face_with_monocle:" class="emoji only-emoji" alt=":face_with_monocle:"></p>
<p>The link was: <span class="spoiler"><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368/1">spoiler</a></span><br>
<em>At the moment the links are down, as far as I saw…</em></p>
<h1>Conclusion</h1>
<p>That was a new territory for me and had a lot of fun solving these puzzles.<br>
Hope you guys loved it as much as I love making those articles and more importantly, I hope that you had fun.<br>
Looking forward to see if you find something in the Fibonacci image and also hope you see in the next one.<br>
Thanks for reading ! <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=9" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 01:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-7368-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/arg-the-red-triangle-solving-part2/7368.rss">[ARG] The Red Triangle Solving -- Part2</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
