<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737</link>
    <description>I&#39;m out of ideas :frowning: . I have physical access to a windows 7 computer and I&#39;m trying to get admin on it. CMD is disabled by network administrator for basic accounts, but using the live boot method of renaming the startup shortcuts (such as magnify or osk) to cmd, I have some level of access using cmd prior to signing in. Although I can use net user commands and it says they were successful, signing into hidden admin account, making an account admin, or changing an admins password doesn&#39;t work. I&#39;ve tried clearing the passwords using chntpw in kali, but no luck. I did find that the hidden admin account is in fact enabled through chntpw, but can&#39;t sign into it. I was recently told to try using mimikatz, but I can&#39;t run it (blocked by administrator). The only thing I can think of now is using Ophcrack and someone create a custom work list (never used Ophcrack) and try to brute force the login. Anywho, I&#39;m curious on others thoughts. Thanks in advance. :helicopter:</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 10:42:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ivlb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Also check out tools for offline password reset / blanking. Sorry for not providing links for the lookup, but haven’t used 'em in a while, so I won’t recommend anything particular.</p>
<p>The method relies on the fact that the password hashes are stored in the SAM store of Windows registry. If you have phys access, you can modify the reg with any registry offline editor (admin tools, freely available) and blank out the entry or set your own hash.<br>
If the default local admin acc is used, it always has the same SID, so it’s easy to recognize.<br>
If you blank out a local entry for a Domain Admins login (cached/offline login has to be enabled, is by default), the computer will revert to a local (user) login only.</p>
<p>NOTE: although this is the same method used by chntpw, the tool itself didn’t always work for me, that’s why I’m posting about the general method.</p>
<p>Good luck!</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 10:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-737-4</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737.rss">Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[idenatin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Cool. I’ll check that you. Thank you.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 05:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-737-3</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737.rss">Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dtm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There are UAC bypasses available to acquire administrative access. What you require is a technique called <em>DLL Hijacking</em> and it is detailed here by our <a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/joe_schmoe">@Joe_Schmoe</a> on <a href="http://null-byte.wonderhowto.com/how-to/bypass-uac-using-dll-hijacking-0168600/">Null Byte - Bypass UAC Using DLL Hijacking</a>.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 04:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-737-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737.rss">Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[idenatin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m out of ideas <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/frowning.png?v=9" title=":frowning:" class="emoji" alt=":frowning:"> . I have physical access to a windows 7 computer and I’m trying to get admin on it. CMD is disabled by network administrator for basic accounts, but using the live boot method of renaming the startup shortcuts (such as magnify or osk) to cmd, I have some level of access using cmd prior to signing in. Although I can use net user commands and it says they were successful, signing into hidden admin account, making an account admin, or changing an admins password doesn’t work. I’ve tried clearing the passwords using chntpw in kali, but no luck. I did find that the hidden admin account is in fact enabled through chntpw, but can’t sign into it. I was recently told to try using mimikatz, but I can’t run it (blocked by administrator). The only thing I can think of now is using Ophcrack and someone create a custom work list (never used Ophcrack) and try to brute force the login. Anywho, I’m curious on others thoughts. Thanks in advance. <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/helicopter.png?v=9" title=":helicopter:" class="emoji" alt=":helicopter:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 01:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-737-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/trouble-getting-into-windows-7-computer/737.rss">Trouble getting into windows 7 computer</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
