<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>WIBattack &amp; Simjacker</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/wibattack-simjacker/19835</link>
    <description>So, this is my first post/question here in the forum. To introduce myself, here is my background: I work with IT, but pentesting, finding and exploiting vulnerabilities is more like a hobby for me. In fact, my biggest achievement in this area was to find out the password of my neighbor&#39;s wifi using aircrack :sweat_smile:. But sometimes I try things more complicated (at least for me). This time, I was searching about a couple of vulnerabilities in SIM cards named [WIBattack and Simjacker](https://www.zdnet.com/article/new-sim-card-attack-disclosed-similar-to-simjacker/). Basically the way how this works it&#39;s that the attacker sends a sms payload to the target containing commands that are runned by Java applets browsers embeded in the SIM card which allows the attacker to get the SIM location, start a call, send a sms, launch internet browser with an URL, etc. I googled it for a while (lot), but as usual for me in this more complicated things, I got stucked and couldn&#39;t find nothing more than the definition of the vulnerability and a superficial description of how it works.
So my humble question is, does anybody have more experience with these vulnerabilities that could share with me so I could advance some more this time?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 17:21:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/wibattack-simjacker/19835.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>WIBattack &amp; Simjacker</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/wibattack-simjacker/19835/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/wibattack-simjacker/19835/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 17:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-19835-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/wibattack-simjacker/19835.rss">WIBattack &amp; Simjacker</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>WIBattack &amp; Simjacker</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rokoho]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So, this is my first post/question here in the forum. To introduce myself, here is my background: I work with IT, but pentesting, finding and exploiting vulnerabilities is more like a hobby for me. In fact, my biggest achievement in this area was to find out the password of my neighbor’s wifi using aircrack <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/sweat_smile.png?v=9" title=":sweat_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":sweat_smile:">. But sometimes I try things more complicated (at least for me). This time, I was searching about a couple of vulnerabilities in SIM cards named <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/new-sim-card-attack-disclosed-similar-to-simjacker/" rel="nofollow noopener">WIBattack and Simjacker</a>. Basically the way how this works it’s that the attacker sends a sms payload to the target containing commands that are runned by Java applets browsers embeded in the SIM card which allows the attacker to get the SIM location, start a call, send a sms, launch internet browser with an URL, etc. I googled it for a while (lot), but as usual for me in this more complicated things, I got stucked and couldn’t find nothing more than the definition of the vulnerability and a superficial description of how it works.<br>
So my humble question is, does anybody have more experience with these vulnerabilities that could share with me so I could advance some more this time?</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/wibattack-simjacker/19835/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/wibattack-simjacker/19835/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 17:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-19835-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/wibattack-simjacker/19835.rss">WIBattack &amp; Simjacker</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
