<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>RATs question. Long break</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rats-question-long-break/11084</link>
    <description>Hey, i&#39;m new to this forum. I used to be into this stuff few years ago, when i was younger, around 15. I&#39;ve stopped after having some problems.
I was looking for some RATs (NjRAT is what i used mainly) but nowadays you can&#39;t trust nowhere. I found NjRAT and LimeRAT on Github. I know Github, obviously, but is it safe ? could be any backdoor ? any site/safe clean download anywhere you guys would know about ?
I used to be on another Hackers forum back in the day, small family. Great times, but they closed up, unfortunately.. these questions were no problem there, so i apologise if my question is against the rules or anything. I saw people talking about RATs on some topics so i figured it&#39;ll be no problem to ask. if it is, again, i aplogise. Please let me know.
Thanks.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:32:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rats-question-long-break/11084.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>RATs question. Long break</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rats-question-long-break/11084/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rats-question-long-break/11084/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 12:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-11084-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rats-question-long-break/11084.rss">RATs question. Long break</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>RATs question. Long break</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[AnUnknownMonster]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey, i’m new to this forum. I used to be into this stuff few years ago, when i was younger, around 15. I’ve stopped after having some problems.<br>
I was looking for some RATs (NjRAT is what i used mainly) but nowadays you can’t trust nowhere. I found NjRAT and LimeRAT on Github. I know Github, obviously, but is it safe ? could be any backdoor ? any site/safe clean download anywhere you guys would know about ?<br>
I used to be on another Hackers forum back in the day, small family. Great times, but they closed up, unfortunately… these questions were no problem there, so i apologise if my question is against the rules or anything. I saw people talking about RATs on some topics so i figured it’ll be no problem to ask. if it is, again, i aplogise. Please let me know.<br>
Thanks.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rats-question-long-break/11084/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rats-question-long-break/11084/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 12:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-11084-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rats-question-long-break/11084.rss">RATs question. Long break</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
