<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>A Simple Open Source Portscanner</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/a-simple-open-source-portscanner/3285</link>
    <description>Hello NullSec, Joker back with another tool that I wrote today. As the title says this is a portscanner that I&#39;ve decided to code to learn more about packets and how they work. This is a very simple program that basically does a SYN scan. Issue is that most systems would block this type of scan and therefore I recommend using nmap for testing and hacking purposes. This project is for educational purposes only. I should note that the [site](http://www.binarytides.com/tcp-connect-port-scanner-c-code-linux-sockets/) I used as reference honestly both has ugly code and I don&#39;t think the code works that well, but helped a lot with explaining to me how packets work at least for a SYN scan. 

A overview of a SYN scan is simple enough:
``
client ----- sends -----&gt; SYN ----- to -----&gt; server
``
``
server ----- sends ----&gt; SYN+ACK ----- to ------&gt; client
``
Simple? I think so. 

Anyways, the [code](https://gitlab.s-3.tech/v02alentine/portscanner) is simple enough to compile and use. I&#39;ve as usual added comments to help those who wish to look at my code to understand how it works-ish...

I&#39;m gonna be working on different types of scans like FIN scan and others in the future. 

Welp that&#39;s it for now, cheers!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 16:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Linux</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/a-simple-open-source-portscanner/3285.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>A Simple Open Source Portscanner</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Red_Joker]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello NullSec, Joker back with another tool that I wrote today. As the title says this is a portscanner that I’ve decided to code to learn more about packets and how they work. This is a very simple program that basically does a SYN scan. Issue is that most systems would block this type of scan and therefore I recommend using nmap for testing and hacking purposes. This project is for educational purposes only. I should note that the <a href="http://www.binarytides.com/tcp-connect-port-scanner-c-code-linux-sockets/" rel="nofollow noopener">site</a> I used as reference honestly both has ugly code and I don’t think the code works that well, but helped a lot with explaining to me how packets work at least for a SYN scan.</p>
<p>A overview of a SYN scan is simple enough:<br>
<code>client ----- sends -----&gt; SYN ----- to -----&gt; server</code><br>
<code>server ----- sends ----&gt; SYN+ACK ----- to ------&gt; client</code><br>
Simple? I think so.</p>
<p>Anyways, the <a href="https://gitlab.s-3.tech/v02alentine/portscanner" rel="nofollow noopener">code</a> is simple enough to compile and use. I’ve as usual added comments to help those who wish to look at my code to understand how it works-ish…</p>
<p>I’m gonna be working on different types of scans like FIN scan and others in the future.</p>
<p>Welp that’s it for now, cheers!</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/a-simple-open-source-portscanner/3285/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/a-simple-open-source-portscanner/3285/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 16:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-3285-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/a-simple-open-source-portscanner/3285.rss">A Simple Open Source Portscanner</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
