<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>HTB premium or a hacking course</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499</link>
    <description>Hey guys! so, I have some money to spare, and I&#39;m kind of in a tough spot with where my self teachings have brought me, so I think its high time I get some sort of payed course to gain more information in hacking. I already have a library full of hacking books, but they taught me all I could learn from some of these, and some are more for reference anyway.

My question WOULD be (and to some extent still is) what courses you would all reccomend for the various levels and fields of hacking, but I&#39;m also curious about Hack the Box Premium. In Hack the Box, I&#39;ve been doing absolutely terrible, I got a single user (Which was an amazing feeling btw), but thats it. But I saw how Premium had the retired boxes, with official writeups, and so I&#39;m wondering if I can use these writeups on the retired boxes to learn about new tools and strategies, and just all around use it as a form of learning tool.

Essentially, What I&#39;m asking is:
1. What&#39;s the quality of the HTB retired machine writeups? How in depth are they. Do they explain what the tools do? could they be used to learn more about the field and continue me on my way to becoming an absolute pen testing wizard?
2. What are some good quality courses you would reccomend I put my money into? I&#39;m not a noob, but I&#39;m no where near being a pro, so whatever courses you can vouch for, begginner, advanced, or expert, Feel free to post them!
3. (optional, but since I&#39;m on the topic of learning) How did you guys learn more about the field?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 21:16:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>HTB premium or a hacking course</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 21:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15499-3</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499.rss">HTB premium or a hacking course</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>HTB premium or a hacking course</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi There,</p>
<p>Personally i advise doing a course if you find yourself with limited time or in a situation where you are easy distracted with other responsibilities.</p>
<p>To answer your questions:</p>
<ol>
<li>What’s the quality of the HTB retired machine writeups? How in depth are they. Do they explain what the tools do? could they be used to learn more about the field and continue me on my way to becoming an absolute pen testing wizard?</li>
</ol>
<p>The HTB walkthroughs are good quality, but that is all they are, walkthroughs. They sometime describe the when and the why but mostly they are a copy this and copy that and ta daa, you have the flag.  Ippsec videos are amazing as you get a lot more context about why he does a thing and goes through the output.  You can find a lot of these videos online but obviously need to get VIP to put it into practice.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>What are some good quality courses you would reccomend I put my money into? I’m not a noob, but I’m no where near being a pro, so whatever courses you can vouch for, begginner, advanced, or expert, Feel free to post them!</li>
</ol>
<p>I would put them in this order when i am asked these questions:</p>
<p>For people starting out,  Learn about the infrastructure you are trying to hack before pwning <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/smiley.png?v=9" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p>
<p>Security +<br>
CASP ( &gt; CEH in my opinion (I don’t rate it at all))</p>
<p>If you are more than an intermediate then these…</p>
<p>QSTM or Check team member courses<br>
OSCP<br>
OSCE</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>(optional, but since I’m on the topic of learning) How did you guys learn more about the field?</li>
</ol>
<p>I started out by reading books saw a bunch of cool movies as a child and it became a hobbie that started to pay the bills.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 21:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15499-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499.rss">HTB premium or a hacking course</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>HTB premium or a hacking course</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[AntonRobotron]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey guys! so, I have some money to spare, and I’m kind of in a tough spot with where my self teachings have brought me, so I think its high time I get some sort of payed course to gain more information in hacking. I already have a library full of hacking books, but they taught me all I could learn from some of these, and some are more for reference anyway.</p>
<p>My question WOULD be (and to some extent still is) what courses you would all reccomend for the various levels and fields of hacking, but I’m also curious about Hack the Box Premium. In Hack the Box, I’ve been doing absolutely terrible, I got a single user (Which was an amazing feeling btw), but thats it. But I saw how Premium had the retired boxes, with official writeups, and so I’m wondering if I can use these writeups on the retired boxes to learn about new tools and strategies, and just all around use it as a form of learning tool.</p>
<p>Essentially, What I’m asking is:</p>
<ol>
<li>What’s the quality of the HTB retired machine writeups? How in depth are they. Do they explain what the tools do? could they be used to learn more about the field and continue me on my way to becoming an absolute pen testing wizard?</li>
<li>What are some good quality courses you would reccomend I put my money into? I’m not a noob, but I’m no where near being a pro, so whatever courses you can vouch for, begginner, advanced, or expert, Feel free to post them!</li>
<li>(optional, but since I’m on the topic of learning) How did you guys learn more about the field?</li>
</ol>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 17:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-15499-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/htb-premium-or-a-hacking-course/15499.rss">HTB premium or a hacking course</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
