<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Social - 0x00sec - The Home of the Hacker</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/c/social/46</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Social&#39; category Many users often have infomation related to their work, their activity on 0x00sec, and other things that aren&#39;t strictly computer science/hacking related, however they are somewhat relevant. This category is to be used sparingly, and only if you really have something important/relevant to share.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:36:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/c/social/46.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Why the most skilled people in this field thinks that our world is a simulation?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Darkvault]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Is coding  a proof that our world is a simulation and our God is a coder. I’m  really  curious and this topic is boggling my mind for a long time with 3D bio printers scientist   are  already building living organs. Very strange that alot of  people  are not serious about this question .</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-25421</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421.rss">Why the most skilled people in this field thinks that our world is a simulation?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>I want to be a hacker ,coder but my parents are against it</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Darkvault]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Theyre  saying they’ll  not waste  a single penny if  that’s  the case  and they’re  saying that  stupid  people do all these nonsense  and they want me to  do something else  but I’m into this and it’s  Okey if no one takes care of me .Any quick way I can make a little living from any skills related to this field anyway  and if you’ve  gone through same situations would love to hear your experience. Sorry for my bad English</p>
            <p><small>35 posts - 14 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/i-want-to-be-a-hacker-coder-but-my-parents-are-against-it/25374">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/i-want-to-be-a-hacker-coder-but-my-parents-are-against-it/25374</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 16:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-25374</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/i-want-to-be-a-hacker-coder-but-my-parents-are-against-it/25374.rss">I want to be a hacker ,coder but my parents are against it</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>0x00sec Wallpapers - 4K</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[3vn2odzn]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>&gt; 0x00sec Wallpapers - 4K</strong></p>
<p>Hello, I designed wallpapers in different styles. I also made a vector drawing of the 0x00sec logo and uploaded it to the cloud. You can use <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/smiley.png?v=9" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p>
<p><strong>Link:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://mega.nz/folder/Q6R1kaDJ#jdfhKPR2ubqRMmoQYAr88Q" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://mega.nz/folder/Q6R1kaDJ#jdfhKPR2ubqRMmoQYAr88Q</a></p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 7 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/0x00sec-wallpapers-4k/24878">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/0x00sec-wallpapers-4k/24878</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-24878</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/0x00sec-wallpapers-4k/24878.rss">0x00sec Wallpapers - 4K</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>If you Want to get good at Malware Development</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[digitalXmage]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This is just for the people which lack passion, and maybe have a skewed view of Malware, And hacking. This has just been my experience, And You have to delve into this stuff <strong>with the right mindset I feel</strong>. I’m no crazy Hacker, Or malware developer, But <strong>I’m learning</strong>. And I have learnt A lot. And Have Learnt A lot about Trojans and ELF binary files(A never ending fun endeavor)</p>
<p>It’s Very simple actually. You need to have the urge to learn more about how a computer works, and really enjoy learning the low information of how a computer works, It will gravitate to you writing low level applications, learning more about the operating system, the Linux API, especially C, and also assembler are both important and provide different ways of learning about computers. And writing Assembly is really great. And then combining the both in writing Both C and embedded/Inline assembler, <strong>It’s Like C is the Knife, And Assembly is the Gun. Combine With Data structures and Algorithm knowledge, I think are all powerful tools. For Creating efficient programs</strong></p>
<p>Assembler is great, It gets rid of all the levels of abstraction of the computer that A lot of languages have(Not bad, But not useful if you want to learn how a computer works), and you WILL learn how a computer works. How memory works, How the CPU works etc. And C is great When you learn the concepts in assembler, Will help your C programming.</p>
<p>Read Books, You can pirate books from this website: <a href="https://www.pdfdrive.com/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">pdfdrive</a></p>
<p>Books are way better than tutorials, because unlike tutorials, Authors are paid lots of money to write these computer textbooks, It’s their job, they’re are gonna make sure they invest the time to research and learn and write that textbook to the best of their ability. And what’s great Even books a decade ago are still useful, Because Low level never really changes and For whatever legacy stuff you learn, Emulators , Virtual machines are great for that.) And The best ones Are written by University professors IMO, But there are many great authors Who are just great programmers and share the knowledge. (Not to Say tutorials are bad, Use, and learn from both).</p>
<p>And also theoretical knowledge and Practical knowledge is important, so it’s good to read up on the theory and apply the theory into practice through projects. For instance I’ve been learning a lot about the ELF Binary in Linux, As well as delving into embedded programming for micro controllers.</p>
<p>This knowledge of the system will help with malware development, and If you already have a strong interest in low level programming, Then you’ll learn a lot, if you’re determined enough to learn.</p>
<p>What I’m saying is you gotta trust the process, You have to enjoy every part a long the way,Each step in the learning you need to <strong>enjoy and write applications that you are proud off</strong>. If you don’t enjoy it, you won’t be good at it. At all.</p>
<p>This has been my current roadmap(journey so far):</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Learn C and Linux API and write fun user space Terminal applications. (Did loads of projects before going to step 2, Still do). Get Better at C, memory management, Getting Good at debugging (GDB)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Learn and read up on Computer Theory, learn  a CPU instruction set(arm assembler), Bytes, bit shifting, how arithmetic work,Logical Operations ,CPU, CPU registers, Memory etc. etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Learn and Read up on computer Malware, And Learn to Read other people’s code and learning from other people’s source code, Learn the theory and Creating projects Using that Learnt Knowledge. <strong>(Incredibly important skill in an Area of learning advanced topics with not much practical resources online)</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Currently Learning embedded micro controller programming, To learn more about computers and writing programs on bare metal(No operating system) etc etc.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This is What I’ve done so far. If it helps people who are unsure about What it takes to learn Hacking , and This stuff to the source code, binary level. And honestly <strong>You gotta enjoy the process more than the outcome</strong>, especially in this Area. Most of the stuff you learn, especially at the beginning, Will be minimal and always be caught by anti virus measures. But you should still be proud when you do something as significant such as embedded a basic payload into an Elf binary and printing some text to the screen.</p>
<p><strong>Enjoy the process More than the Result.</strong> As What Seems insignificant to others, Is A big step for myself, In learning and understanding a new concept, which may of taken months of learning, and Writing a lot of lines of code for some small result.</p>
<p>As well of having a strong interest in Low level programming, Regardless Of hacking and writing Malware.</p>
<p>I just feel A good mindset is important,  and A bit of self reflection, Which has helped me at least.</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 13:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-23466</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466.rss">If you Want to get good at Malware Development</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How to avoid BURNOUT?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[MSqueaks]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi. I’m MSqueaks.</p>
<p>Anyone have advice on avoiding Burnout ?</p>
<p>I am a network engineer tech, I work in a live nocc environment. It’s high stress, face paced and a lot of networking. I took this job as a stepping stone to work my way into infosec and build experience. The nocc has a high turn over rate, my team is increasingly getting smaller and I am the only female on my team in a company full of gatekeepers. I got lucky with this job because I did not have any practical experience. I had just graduated with two AS degrees, one in networking systems architecture and the other in cybersecurity.</p>
<p>I generally work 9-12 hour days, then try to spend my limited free time towards Research &amp; Development but since the beginning of the year I have started to Burnout. It’s not that I lost my drive, motivation or passion. I just can’t do it. At this point, I burnout daily and I am having a hard time staying constant with studying for certifications or R&amp;D in general. Any advice ?</p>
            <p><small>23 posts - 9 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-avoid-burnout/22767">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-avoid-burnout/22767</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 01:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-22767</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/how-to-avoid-burnout/22767.rss">How to avoid BURNOUT?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>+[Nullsec Zine] A call to all users and staff</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Danus]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Hear yee  Hear yee</h1>
<p>After long talk and consideration, the 0x00sec boardroom as decided to roll off a trial attempt to create the first nullsec zine, or nullsec magazine if you will.</p>
<p>Obliviously this means all the active 0x00sec staff would participate in such event but we decided to open the possibility for 0x00sec users to join on the fun.</p>
<h2>Why on earth would I want to do that</h2>
<ol>
<li>This would greatly benefit your career and would allow you to publish and leverage on fame and glory.</li>
<li>This would push your skill to its boundary and yourself outside your comfort zone, thus improving your skill set.</li>
<li>It would greatly benefit the community and the discord server.</li>
</ol>
<h2>What do I need to do to get in?</h2>
<p>If you are active on the discord &amp; forums and have an idea, that you think is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Creative</li>
<li>Applicable for you to research and to write about in the span of 2-3 months</li>
<li>Is not outdated or overdone 300 times by other blog posts on the internet</li>
<li>Requires effort, hard work and would push yourself outside your domain of comfort</li>
</ul>
<p>You can send me a private message on discord or on the forums and your idea will be considered, if it would be accepted you would be invited to the zine channel on discord.</p>
<h2>When is this trial project due?</h2>
<p>Currently we are considering a public release of 2-3 months after the design and project roll out.</p>
<h2>Do I need to bring something with me?</h2>
<ul>
<li>Free time, at least 10 spare hours a week</li>
<li>A good idea</li>
<li>Commitment to your idea, work, craft and community</li>
<li>A dark sense of humor could help</li>
</ul>
<h2>That’s it?</h2>
<p>That is it, good luck.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/nullsec-zine-a-call-to-all-users-and-staff/21534">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/nullsec-zine-a-call-to-all-users-and-staff/21534</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 14:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-21534</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/nullsec-zine-a-call-to-all-users-and-staff/21534.rss">+[Nullsec Zine] A call to all users and staff</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The basics to master the skill of ethical hacking?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[KaIi]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Can anyone show me some good youtube videos or online resources that help with pentesting and Ip sniffing tools? and essentialy all the basics to becomean ethical hacker</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/the-basics-to-master-the-skill-of-ethical-hacking/20750">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/the-basics-to-master-the-skill-of-ethical-hacking/20750</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-20750</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/the-basics-to-master-the-skill-of-ethical-hacking/20750.rss">The basics to master the skill of ethical hacking?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What are y’all’s opinions on programming books?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[bagel]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve never used a book for programming, I’ve always learned by mapping out what I want a program to do and then doing research for each step of the program. So I’m curious, do you prefer learning by book or by using the internet?</p>
            <p><small>28 posts - 24 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-are-y-all-s-opinions-on-programming-books/20337">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-are-y-all-s-opinions-on-programming-books/20337</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 01:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-20337</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-are-y-all-s-opinions-on-programming-books/20337.rss">What are y’all’s opinions on programming books?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Introduction: 4554551N-533K3R</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[4554551N-533K3R]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h3>What do you go by / What are your common aliases?</h3>
<p>4554551N-533K3R<br>
Ph@nt0m5tr1k3r</p>
<h3>What are your skill sets?</h3>
<p>Coding: C, C++, Python, Golang, Assembly, Java, Perl, PHP, Rust<br>
Reverse Engineering<br>
Exploit Development<br>
Pen Testing/Hacking<br>
Security Architecture<br>
GRC</p>
<h3>What are you interested in?</h3>
<p>All of the above.  I am on a never ending quest to increase my knowledge and refine my skills and tool sets.</p>
<h3>Are you an Info. Sec./Comp. Sci. professional or just a hobbyist?</h3>
<p>Info Sec Professional</p>
<h3>What do you hope to gain from this community?</h3>
<p>Some new ideas and methodologies.  Knowledge to help me refine my skills and build on my existing knowledge.</p>
<h3>What do you hope to contribute to this community?</h3>
<p>I hope to share some of my skills and methodologies with community in hopes of helping others reach a higher level.</p>
<h3>How’d you find us?</h3>
<p>Stumbled across the site while doing some research</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/introduction-4554551n-533k3r/20221">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/introduction-4554551n-533k3r/20221</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 04:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-20221</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/introduction-4554551n-533k3r/20221.rss">Introduction: 4554551N-533K3R</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Life Update Regarding To My Last Post From A Couple Of Months Ago</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[d3m0crxcy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey friends of 0x00sec, the last time I was on this website was back in January. I was in a very, very dark place, and I decided to reach out and make a call-for-help post. If you seen it, it was really depressing… But, about 2 1/2 months have passed, and so many things have changed for me. Let’s go in order, shall we?</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>I have had a really bad past of self-harm that lasted for about 4 years. I officially gave it up back in August 2019, but over those 2 1/2 months that have gone by, I kept on self-loathing, and almost relapsed into the terrible habit. Luckily enough, I didn’t do it. I’m very thankful.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I found Jesus. I been going to church with my parents for about a year now, but back then, I was not involved into religion or God in general and had nothing to do with it. Then around early February this year, something kind of punched my in the face and told me to try it, that it won’t kill me. That kept creeping into my mind for about 2 weeks. So on February 16, the church were playing beautiful song, and I felt my heart pounding. Something told me to go to the altar, and I did. I don’t think I cried that hard in my life. I was just crying, praying, repenting and truly felt the presence of God. It was so, so great, and I felt at peace with myself. It feels so good to call myself a Christian now.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I got accepted into the college I wanted to go into for cybersecurity! I been waiting for a response for months, and to know I got accepted made me feel ecstatic! I can’t wait to go into the dream major I have been wanting!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I’ve learned people can truly love. Right before I was gonna make this post, I took a look at my last post and saw that 4.9 thousand people saw it. To know that many people had the nerve to even read it warmed my heart, and I was crying. So whoever bothered to look at it, reach out, comment and let me know things get better, <em>thank you</em>. My heart is so full.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>0x00sec, you guys have become a little family for me. I am super duper grateful. I appreciate all of you. Depression is still into my system, but I am taking it day by day. I been taking my meds for it, but also praying that I can make it through another day. It’s not as bad as it used to be! I feel very positive right now.</p>
<p>With so much love, (and please stay safe during this chaotic time with the coronavirus!),<br>
<em>-d3m0crxcy</em></p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/life-update-regarding-to-my-last-post-from-a-couple-of-months-ago/19972">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/life-update-regarding-to-my-last-post-from-a-couple-of-months-ago/19972</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 01:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-19972</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/life-update-regarding-to-my-last-post-from-a-couple-of-months-ago/19972.rss">Life Update Regarding To My Last Post From A Couple Of Months Ago</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Being Unsocial (Help regarding balancing personal life)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[landi58]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi,<br>
I am a research engineer at a company (Not a coding job, but it’s related to analyzing patents of Computer science and electronics field. so it’s a technical job). I have great interest in coding but due to my low CGPA in Btech (Computer Science), I am unable to get job in coding field. I am like I don’t live without coding. I spent almost 12 hours of day in my job (job 9 hours +  travelling) so  as soon as i came back home, i open my lapi and start coding. As my job is purely non-coding job, they don’t allow me to even open a coding related website in office on their sytem. So i try to give as much time to coding at home. Due to this, my personal life is going affected. My mom (my family only has me and my mom) said that i not give her enough time and don’t talk to her (or listen to her) much. Further, she said that she will leave me and go home back if my behaviour will be like that (like if i not change my this schedule). But  i have to give more and more time to coding so i am getting detached to her. Further, the topics on which she wants to talk to me are bulshits (like talking about neightbours, etc. which are not of my interest). I apply to many coding companies (S/W development companies) but as i am working for 2+ years in non-coding, they don’t even schedule my interview. But i not leave coding as i already mentioned that i cannot live without coding.</p>
<p>Can anyone please give me some suggestions to change my schedule or behaviour or any thing that i can do to make everyone happy.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/being-unsocial-help-regarding-balancing-personal-life/19077">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/being-unsocial-help-regarding-balancing-personal-life/19077</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 14:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-19077</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/being-unsocial-help-regarding-balancing-personal-life/19077.rss">Being Unsocial (Help regarding balancing personal life)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Happy Australia Day!</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Crqshes]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>To all my fellow Australians hope your all having a great Australia day! <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/australia.png?v=9" title=":australia:" class="emoji" alt=":australia:"></p>
<p><em>(If you aren’t Australian still have a good day <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slightly_smiling_face.png?v=9" title=":slightly_smiling_face:" class="emoji" alt=":slightly_smiling_face:">)</em></p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-australia-day/18812">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-australia-day/18812</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 09:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-18812</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-australia-day/18812.rss">Happy Australia Day!</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Not Anything Hacking Related, But I&#39;m In a Dark Place</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[d3m0crxcy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The title is self explanatory. I don’t use social media besides this website, and I feel like I’ve met so many kind people on here. I guess this is my call for help.</p>
<p>Last year, around March, a lot of stuff went down hill. Let’s just say I made a lot of mistakes, and it broke my moms heart. I got sent to my dads during that time from March-June, and I’ll be honest, depression really got the best of me. I was miserable every single day, and it got so bad to the point where I wanted to kill myself. As you can see, I didn’t.</p>
<p>I was talking to my mom about some things today, and then somehow I was opening up to how I felt from March-June. She knows that I wanted to end it all, I’ve spoken about it 3 times to her.</p>
<p>“Remember what I told you a while back while we were going to your Pastor’s moms funeral? And how I told you I wanted to…you get the gist?” I asked. We were both already kinda upset at each other.</p>
<p>She said my name, and added, “Don’t try to make me feel bad about it. I’m glad you went up to your dads and faced the stuff you faced. You stupid teenagers are gonna kill yourselves whether I stop you or not. I’m not gonna hold you and say it’s ok when it’s not. It’s an awful spirit. I’m still gonna move on with my life. I’m not gonna mourn and be brought down if you killed yourself.”</p>
<p>I just…my heart is literally shattered. I decided to let things go and practice Elton John’s “Rocketman” on piano, since I am performing it next Friday. At the ending when it repeats “and I think it’s gonna be a long, long time” over and over again, I kinda lost it. I was sobbing really, really badly. <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/confused.png?v=9" title=":confused:" class="emoji" alt=":confused:"></p>
<p>I have no words, actually. I’m opening up to my mom about something so serious, and throughout the 3 times I’ve talked to her about it, not once has she ever held me and told me things would be okay. All I got was a heaven/hell speech, and that it was my fault that all this stuff happened…</p>
<p>Friends of 0x00sec, can I please get some advice?</p>
            <p><small>39 posts - 18 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/not-anything-hacking-related-but-im-in-a-dark-place/18542">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/not-anything-hacking-related-but-im-in-a-dark-place/18542</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 03:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-18542</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/not-anything-hacking-related-but-im-in-a-dark-place/18542.rss">Not Anything Hacking Related, But I&#39;m In a Dark Place</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Happy New Year, everybody</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[d3m0crxcy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey guys. It’s been a while since I been on this website, I been so busy with my work and exams. Thankfully, it’s all done. I hope everyone is enjoying the new year so far, even though it just started. What are your NY resolutions? I can say that mine are:</p>
<p>-give up social media<br>
-stop cussing<br>
-be more loving<br>
-leave the past behind me<br>
-give up weed</p>
<p>Some sound smart, some sound dumb, I know. But personally, I feel like it will all benefit me in the end. I also have some news, I applied for the college I want to go for a few days ago, and I hope I get a response soon. I want to go for cybersecurity/computer science, and I really hope I get in. If I do, I’ll end up only going for 2 years for my AA degree. I been studying a lot lately for it. I know the second semester only ended in December, but I ended will all A’s. I feel so good.</p>
<p>Ok, ok - enough about me. Let’s talk more about you; what are your resolutions for the New Year? Do you plan to stay consistent?</p>
<p>Stay safe, guys.<br>
Cheers.</p>
<ul>
<li>d3m0crxcy</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>16 posts - 9 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-new-year-everybody/18390">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-new-year-everybody/18390</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-18390</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/happy-new-year-everybody/18390.rss">Happy New Year, everybody</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Rules or Otherwise Unfavorable Behavior?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[9lives304]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m not here to ruffle any feathers, be blackballed, banned, tar and feathered, shunned, obfuscated, castrated, or otherwise 0x00sec socially persecuted…<br>
(Takes a deep breath)<br>
After regurgitating all of that wit just for y’all, I wanted to see if you have a Marketplace page for selling/buying Software and/or Services that may or may not be of questionable legality?  I ask this formally in advance as to not upset the hierarchy by a 1st day 0x00sec ‘Noob’.<br>
-9lives304</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 14:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-18368</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368.rss">Rules or Otherwise Unfavorable Behavior?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Con, anyone? [padding]</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[tamas_dxw]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I was just wondering if anyone comes to 44con this week or Bsides Cymru later this month?</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/con-anyone-padding/16152">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/con-anyone-padding/16152</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 21:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-16152</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/con-anyone-padding/16152.rss">Con, anyone? [padding]</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Not Dead Just Busy</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narcodex]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello,</p>
<p>I am not dead or left the community, just been very busy getting stuff done. I hope you all are having a good summer <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/not-dead-just-busy/15487">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/not-dead-just-busy/15487</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 20:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-15487</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/not-dead-just-busy/15487.rss">Not Dead Just Busy</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[W4K3Y]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I went to Defcon 2 years ago and had some interesting mixed feelings about the event.</p>
<p>I’m not looking to slag off the event or my time there and equally not to try and convince others to go, I’m just keen to find out if I did the event in the correct way or didn’t fully embrace it.</p>
<p>Rather than writing a review that you can easily google let me provide my pros and cons.</p>
<p>Pros:</p>
<p>Thousands of hackers/sec peeps in one place.<br>
Interesting talks like the 101 track.<br>
Cool swag-  all of the goodies and hoodies I could ever want. (Cash only).<br>
Cool venders from music to tech and swag (cash and card).<br>
Meet bloggers that I follow online (mubix)<br>
It’s in Vegas… there is so much to see and do!!</p>
<p>Cons:</p>
<p>It should be called que con… there was about 20 thousand people there.</p>
<p>The talks were good but you can’t get to all the ones you want to due to que’s everywhere. I met someone on the second day who said he don’t go to any and just watched them on youtube…</p>
<p>Vegas, It’s an expensive trip! 10 dollars per bottle of Budweiser! Plus hotel, plus flights I must have spent over £2k (GBP).</p>
<p>So the interesting people… I didn’t meet anyone unfriendly but due to the amount of people I actually felt a bit on my own, I had little idea what I was meant to be doing.  Again I was told everyone feels this way the first time…</p>
<p>This year the event is over three locations… I feel like I would be lost even more now.</p>
<p>So have you guys been, what do you think of the event?</p>
<p>Other than BSIDES  what events would you recommend?</p>
            <p><small>25 posts - 9 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 10:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-15099</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/what-do-you-all-really-think-of-defcon/15099.rss">What do you all “really” think of Defcon?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>0x00sec Helped Me Graduate College and Become a Professional Red Teamer!</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rain]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi All,</p>
<p>Almost <a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/introduction-rain/2859">2 years ago today</a> I stumbled across this website, halfway through a CS undergrad and hoping that security would be for me, because software development probably wasn’t (isn’t?). At this point in time, I wouldn’t even qualify as a script kiddie. But dammit if hacking wasn’t way cooler than anything I was learning in university (bubble sort and linked lists, anyone?). I grew a lot in the last 2 years, and I owe a lot of that to this community. I would have never gotten OSCP certified, or this position if I didn’t have the incredible support everyone has shown me. Seriously, I think I might have failed my computer architecture class if it wasn’t for some timely advice from one of you who shall remain nameless*. I even managed to build a modestly functional hacking tool while I was at it all!</p>
<p>What I’m trying to say is that this place is really special, and for anyone who comes across this place that wants to learn information security: You absolutely can. Even with minimal prior experience, you can change your career or start your first one with enough luck and the right support. Some members of the newer classes at what is now my alma mater reached out to me, and asked how they could get started in security. I told them that they only need two things: A strong internal drive to learn and work hard, and to find a community of friends to study and work with. A community like this one.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>Rain</p>
<p>*If I start naming people who helped me I’d have to try to name everyone in order to be fair, and then I’ll end up with a list of every regular member except one whose name I forgot and we’ll both feel bad about it as a result.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/0x00sec-helped-me-graduate-college-and-become-a-professional-red-teamer/14415">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/0x00sec-helped-me-graduate-college-and-become-a-professional-red-teamer/14415</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 03:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-14415</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/0x00sec-helped-me-graduate-college-and-become-a-professional-red-teamer/14415.rss">0x00sec Helped Me Graduate College and Become a Professional Red Teamer!</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>My thoughts on SHELL AFFECT Tutoring</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Leeky]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I just wanted to write a quick review about SHELL AFFECTS tutoring after going through it with <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/cry0l1t3">@Cry0l1t3</a> and having learned quite a bit.<br>
I hope this will help people judge for them self whether it’s for them or not and also maybe also the business as it totally deserves more attention!</p>
<p>Having not much experience in the field of Web Exploitation Cry0l1t3 offered me one of his tutorings and suggested to work through a hackthebox challenge in it as I’ve never done any of them before.<br>
After I set up a Kali Machine for it he connected to my computer with a screen sharing service so we can work together within the VM where I logged into a VPN connection he provided so I was able to access the box he prepared.</p>
<p>At first he let me do what I thought would be a good start at enumerating the system to see what I already knew and then showed me some more advanced approaches while explaining why they were better and what I might have missed with mine.<br>
Next he taught me some general methodology to keep in mind, things I should avoid doing and what was possible to do with the initial information we gathered especially because I wasn’t familiar with how DNS Servers work and what one can do with them.<br>
Cry0l1t3 took over and taught me about some general tools for working with the server and how to extract information out of it, after which he gave me about 5 minutes to further read into what information the DNS protocol can provide and how to use some tools to interact with them to lead me into finding information relevant for the challenges myself.<br>
The questions that came up for were answered by him afterwards and using the newly gathered information we found a hidden admin login page which I guessed needed some SQL Injection to go through. I tried some injections myself but after none of them showed any response Cry0l1t3 guided me to figuring out what I did wrong and how the vulnerable code probably looks like.<br>
The next step was a page that allowed shell command injection which I used to inject a reverse-shell and connect back the me, while my approach worked in itself Cry0l1t3 showed me some resources<br>
that listed more efficient methods of doing it and also some tricks on how to interact with it way more clean from my console.</p>
<p>Having a shell was enough to find the user.txt file but to get the root file privilege escalation was necessary which I had absolutely no knowledge or experience about.<br>
So the rest of the tutoring was mainly being guided through it and getting recommended resources that listed commands and things to try out and read later.<br>
After some more explanation of what information was necessary and how to get it, how the available services worked, what might be usable to get higher privileges and also hints on what folders to look intoI finally found the part of the box that was exploitable and used it to read out the root.txt!</p>
<p>The whole experience was a lot of fun, very interesting and I learned (as you might have read here) quite a lot about using DNS Servers, better ways of creating reverse shells and privilege escalation in general!<br>
Also the resources I was given to (and the approaches of how to find further) were really interesting to read and especially the cheat sheet lists I was shown will hopefully be really useful in the future as well.</p>
<p>I really recommend it, even more to everyone interesting learning about a new topic or those that feel like they need some help to advance further, I’m sure everyone can learn going through it.</p>
<p>Thank you <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/cry0l1t3">@Cry0l1t3</a> for the help and good luck to your business, I really hope this helps to make more people consider reaching out to you ! <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/my-thoughts-on-shell-affect-tutoring/13490">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/my-thoughts-on-shell-affect-tutoring/13490</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 21:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-13490</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/my-thoughts-on-shell-affect-tutoring/13490.rss">My thoughts on SHELL AFFECT Tutoring</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Where is your 0x00sec sticker?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[fxbg]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>show it off bro.</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/e/e87c552d1b74404cf40d6ce68b985ef96f9eb2a3.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/xaF9AVmIvnYlqzhyzTNimkQEvWr.jpeg?dl=1" title="" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/e/e87c552d1b74404cf40d6ce68b985ef96f9eb2a3.jpeg" alt="" data-base62-sha1="xaF9AVmIvnYlqzhyzTNimkQEvWr" width="690" height="388" data-small-upload="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/e/e87c552d1b74404cf40d6ce68b985ef96f9eb2a3_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/where-is-your-0x00sec-sticker/13332">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/where-is-your-0x00sec-sticker/13332</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 20:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-13332</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/where-is-your-0x00sec-sticker/13332.rss">Where is your 0x00sec sticker?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Apt 34 tools For test communication only, not for illegal use</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[zhihuiyuze]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>It is very new in China, but I don’t know it abroad.</strong><br>
There is a name called Lab Dookhtegan, which shares this data on the Telegram channel, and then others share it with me.</p>
<p>I am learning English, just say the list.</p>
<ol>
<li>Glimpse (a new version of Trojan based on PowerShell, named Pald Alto Networks called BondUpdater)</li>
</ol>
<p>2.PoisonFrog (old version of BondUpdater)</p>
<p>3.HyperShell (called Palo Alto Networks network shell called TwoFace)</p>
<p>4.HighShell (another web shell)</p>
<p>5.Fox Panel (fishing kit)</p>
<p>6.Webmask (DNS tunnel, the main tool behind DNSpionage)</p>
<p>链接: <a href="https://pan.baidu.com/s/1gCBituEbCNOVgnYn3O2h_Q" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://pan.baidu.com/s/1gCBituEbCNOVgnYn3O2h_Q</a> 提取码: rskf</p>
<p>Link: <a href="https://pan.baidu.com/s/1gCBituEbCNOVgnYn3O2h_Q" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://pan.baidu.com/s/1gCBituEbCNOVgnYn3O2h_Q</a> Extraction code: rskf<br>
<img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/3/361bc5c8e9eb783f4cc8d1039ff1fc832b120370.png" alt="TIM%E6%88%AA%E5%9B%BE20190419230125" data-base62-sha1="7IFhJ4s9gGtVmRItAMWGYbnsLXW" width="690" height="485"></p>
<p><strong>Sorry, I seem to forget that this disk needs an account to download. This is a download address without an account.</strong><br>
<strong><a href="https://share.weiyun.com/5WBEzvG" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://share.weiyun.com/5WBEzvG</a></strong></p>
<p>For test communication only, not for illegal use.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/apt-34-tools-for-test-communication-only-not-for-illegal-use/13102">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/apt-34-tools-for-test-communication-only-not-for-illegal-use/13102</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 15:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-13102</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/apt-34-tools-for-test-communication-only-not-for-illegal-use/13102.rss">Apt 34 tools For test communication only, not for illegal use</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Knowing Null: DTM - Developing That Malware</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skidd0]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Hiya!</h1>
<p>Yes, it’s time for another exciting interview with one of 0x00sec’s notable and notorious members! Last time, you all voted for <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/dtm">@dtm</a> so, let’s jump into it. Remember to stick around after to vote for next KN, and feel free to post follow up questions in the comments below!</p>
<p><strong>Hello! Thanks for doing this. First, can you give us some background on who you are and what you do inside the info-sec sphere?</strong></p>
<p><code>Yeah, no problem. I'm dtm, mechatronics engineer student turned comp sci. I used to have interests in the world of science but could never really get along well with mathematics so, one day, when I had enough of doing 3-4 pages of calculus, I had enough and jumped ship. I've always kinda had a (skid) thing for hacking stuff so when I learned how to program in uni I noticed that this could be the entry point where I could actually start the long journey to 1337ness. As for what I do in infosec, malware always fascinated me so I started learn how they worked, looked up source codes on VX, discovered the Windows API and went on trying to code my own. And since my first proper programming language was C, I had also been taught the low level side of how computer programs worked and it introduced me to reverse engineering in assembly. Combine those two and I went onwards into malware analysis.</code></p>
<p><code>These days I am looking to work on my offensive abilities. Currently learned basic Linux and Windows exploitation development, reversing some pwnables back into C for code auditing, and penetration testing in the near future.</code></p>
<p><strong>So it sounds like this was a hobby interest. How did you you transition into a professional career?</strong></p>
<p><code>Yes, it was a hobby until I went into comp sci and realized that I could do it *and* get paid hah. I'm not employed in an infosec career but I am looking. Got an interview real soon at a pentesting consulting company so wish me luck!</code></p>
<p><strong>Absolutely, good luck! Do you have any advice for others looking to get into malware analysis? Any favorite resources?</strong></p>
<p><code>I'd say that malware analysis is just like any other kind of reverse engineering and in being so, it has a higher skill floor that's required compared to other areas. Already knowing how to develop malware was a plus for me because it helped me identify similar functionality/patterns in the code structure. I'd say dig deep into fundamentals such as how programs work, assembly language, operating systems, the general reverse engineering content.</code></p>
<p><code>Resources are abundant on Google and trust me when I say this because that's literally all I've been doing for the past 4 years, just hoard it all, everything that you can get your hands on, and then study it. Find forums, research papers, source code, GitHub, Twitter, YouTube has great channels (MalwareAnalysisForHedgehogs, OALabs). Then go out and find some malware, wild or not, and analyze them.</code></p>
<p><strong>Besides math, are there any big challenges you’ve run into and possibly overcome?</strong></p>
<p><code>Besides the obvious challenges every day when I study infosec, I do have issues when it comes to social interaction. It's not that I don't like it, I actually enjoy socializing, but I think I've become *too* comfortable with being alone which kinda led me to isolate myself and shy away from looking to meet others and make any meaningful relationships. Over the past year I've just told myself to suck it up and participate in my uni's security club which was nice. Doing the security courses has also helped with that and I've since then made a new group of friends (woo me!). Still a work in progress but I'll take what I've got so far.</code></p>
<p><strong>I’m sure more than a few of our members can relate. I know I can. Let’s move on to some fun, personal stuff. What’s your home setup like? OS? Distro?</strong></p>
<p><code>Windows 10, on both laptops! I did use Ubuntu for the majority of last year but it didn't work well since this laptop is a bit dated and using Windows VMs + other things like browsers with a 10+ tabs hit my system pretty badly. Whenever I had a Windows VM open as well as downloading a 1GB+ file from Mega, my computer would thrash. So I've converted back to Windows because that's where I do my work and it's most optimal for me. I would use Windows 7 but it's a bit old and support for it is ending soon.</code></p>
<p><strong>You already mentioned C, but are there any other languages you like to use? And go-to software?</strong></p>
<p><code>I kinda dabble with C++ but, to be honest, I don't really actually use nor like it. I use Python for some quick exploit development. PowerShell is a bit rare, don't really know it that well. Hardly use x86 Intel assembly to write but it comes in handy for developing specific malware functionality as well as solving some CTF challenges. I've been studying Rust for the past month and it's pretty good so far so I'll switch to using that as default hopefully.</code></p>
<p><code>Browser: Firefox, C/C++ Windows development: Microsoft Visual Studio, Other languages/development: VS Code, Text editor: Sublime Text, Disassembler: IDA Pro, Debugger: x64dbg/Windbg, Windows command line tool: Cmder/PowerShell</code></p>
<p><strong>Got any fun gadgets or cool hardware?</strong></p>
<p><code>I'd like to say yes but I'm not that interested in hardware. Basic lock picks are really all I have after I got into that phase. I'm a software kinda person.</code></p>
<p><strong>Ah, a common hacker hobby. Before we move on to our last section, do you have any hobbies or interested outside infosec?</strong></p>
<p><code>Besides the basic stuff like listening to music 24/7 and watching movies, I would like to say cruising around on my penny board but it seems like friends don't have time for that anymore. I actually started escape rooming recently and it's very fun and challenging. Got a 100% win rate (2/2) for that so far. Can't break the streak now.</code></p>
<p><strong>Come out to CO sometime and we can cruise! Alright, our last section focuses on the 0x00sec community. First, how’d you find this place?</strong></p>
<p><code>I was originally on Null Byte but when the riots happened, pry0cc and friends founded this place. I am one of said friends.</code></p>
<p><strong>As one of the first members, how’s it been watching the community grow?</strong></p>
<p><code>It's exciting to see it expand and get exposure on a variety of different places like other forums, Twitter, Reddit, even friends over at my uni's security club know of it. At first I was skeptical but I think we've made it. I'm super proud of it and happy. I like to check the user count every so often. I think we were at 3000 at the beginning of last year and right now it's... 5715!</code></p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for up-and-coming hackers here at 0x00sec?</strong></p>
<p><code>Though I don't really consider myself a "hacker," nor do I claim to know how to become one, I do have some things to say. There's no secret formula to it unless you have some natural talent for it. Either way, it's no different than becoming anything else. You read, understand, practice, repeat. Start from the boring basics and theory, everyone has to go through it but once you hit the top of the roller coaster, it's all worth it. As I said before, hoard all the resources you can and read it all. I see a lot of people complain that resources are old, so what? That's where it all started, the fundamentals. We didn't come to build rockets flying into space from nothing. So learn it anyway, it's great if you're a beginner, and it might be worth something. Maybe you'll discover a new technique or learn something you didn't know. Don't be discouraged by all the new things happening, fancy exploitation protection mechanisms, next-gen, machine learning AV, etc. You'll get there eventually, you just gotta grind like everybody else. When you think you've understood a concept I'd recommend trying to teach it to others. If you can teach it, then you know you've learned it. Lastly, venture out of your comfort zone and push boundaries. You won't get anywhere sitting comfortably in the corner.</code></p>
<p><strong>Great stuff there, man. Anything else you’d like to say to the community?</strong></p>
<p><code>I'd like to thank the founders of this place for providing me a platform where I can push out educational content. pry0cc, especially, for toughening it out over the many years to manage this place with fraq. ricksanchez, the absolute God-tier warden, for keeping this super clean and tidy. Every other contributor to the forums deserve praise as well. Every time someone pushes out great resources I get a little bit excited because I know 0x00sec takes one step closer to recognition in the infosec community and becoming something even greater than ourselves. Super proud of everyone, thank you all!</code></p>
<p><strong>Alright, last question before I let you go. What HEX color is your “hat”?</strong></p>
<p><code>#696969</code></p>
<p><strong><em>Nice</em>. Thanks so much dtm!</strong></p>
<p><code>Thank you too for these interviews!</code></p>
<h1>Vote Time!</h1>
<p>You know what to do!</p>
<p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-dtm-developing-that-malware/11747/1">Click to view the poll.</a></p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-dtm-developing-that-malware/11747">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-dtm-developing-that-malware/11747</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 22:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-11747</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-dtm-developing-that-malware/11747.rss">Knowing Null: DTM - Developing That Malware</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Sites that are shitty</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[f0ur]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I have been spending a lot of time on the World Wide Web and I have stumbled upon a few ugly websites. The most ugly of them so far is <a href="http://malware.wikia.com/wiki/Main_Page" rel="nofollow noopener">Malware Wiki</a>. This thread is mainly about us sharing and laughing and cringing at how ugly these sites are, both at the UI and at the source code level.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/sites-that-are-shitty/10989">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/sites-that-are-shitty/10989</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 21:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-10989</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/sites-that-are-shitty/10989.rss">Sites that are shitty</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skidd0]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Welcome Back!</h1>
<p>Here with us today is the one and only <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/maderas">@maderas</a> !</p>
<p>Be sure to comment any further questions you have and to vote for our next guest in the Poll at the bottom.</p>
<p>Thanks for stopping by!</p>
<h3>Professional Career and Advice</h3>
<p><strong>1. For starters, can you tell us a bit about yourself and your current role/job/work?</strong></p>
<p>I am a guy who believes that InfoSec/Hacking is my best chance to make the world a better place and leave/make an impact that outlives me.</p>
<p>I’m obsessed with making an impact upon the world; I believe that this art (hacking, by which I also mean Red Teaming/Penetration Testing) presents me with an opportunity to make this world a better place.</p>
<p>I think that to achieve all of the latter, I must endeavor to share all that I learn/experience to help this game evolve.</p>
<p>As the bar rises, those who work toward being the best they can be evolve as well.</p>
<p>I believe that if you are afraid to share everything you know, then you are not working hard enough.</p>
<p>Much of this experience originates from my career. Since January of 2011 I’ve worked as a Penetration Tester/Red Team Operator.</p>
<p>From the beginning, I have focused my skill set on real world, adversarial tactics. This involves a ton of extra study /prep on my part, as I need to track down the work/C2 of BlackHats in the wild study/train until I can emulate their tactics.**</p>
<p>For the last few years (and ever on into the future if I can help it) I’ve endeavored to only work in sectors where I believe I can make an impact that is meaningful to the world at large.</p>
<p>In the past, I’ve worked as the Cybersecurity Penetration Test and Vulnerability Assessment Lab for Schneider Electric and as Senior Red Team Operator/Penetration Tester for National Grid.</p>
<p>Currently, I am between gigs and doing volunteer work for Tutanota (pentesting their next e-mail platform) and running the <span class="hashtag">#CyberpunkisNow</span> project via Twitter, which seeks to create a dialogue between people around the world as to how technology continues to permeate our civilization.</p>
<p>I also release original InfoSec content by my Twitter account, which has grown rapidly and is now reaching millions of screens after only 3 months</p>
<p><strong>2. How did you first get into the field? (What was your first hack?)</strong></p>
<p>As long as I can remember, I wanted to be a hacker. I saw a cable news story about The L0pht when I was 12; as a son of Massachusetts, I realized that this was happening in my backyard. I could do this…</p>
<p>As for my first hack, when I was working a customer service gig I used to hack around on the Intranet. The buildings HVAC systems had default creds &amp; the Intranet itself was horribly insecure. I used to bring a live distro of Knoppix STD into work and practice there…nothing really malicious, just exploration.</p>
<p><strong>3. Can you give a rough map from your beginnings to where you are now?</strong></p>
<p>As far back as 2006-2007 I was screwing around with Knoppix STD in my former employer’s Intranet (with their permission) after work/on breaks (I was also maintaining AV/AM and that kind of stuff though it wasn’t my or anyone’s job).</p>
<p>By 2009 /2010 I was using Google’s bug bounty program as an excuse to practice vs. their networks/infrastructure; in December 2010/January 2011 I started doing consultant work and officially entered the world of professional InfoSec (where I have been professionally ever since in some form).</p>
<p><strong>4. What is one of the biggest struggles you overcame? And what’s been the biggest lesson you’ve learned in your career?</strong></p>
<p>My biggest struggle was also my biggest lesson: learning that in most big businesses, most of your managers/fellow employees arent going to care much about InfoSec. It will almost always take a back seat to profitability.</p>
<p>You have to realize that you yourself are there to help ensure the profitability/prosperity of your employer. Solutions are almost always going to be way more important to them then problems.</p>
<p><strong>5. Any advice for someone trying to land in a similar role/job?</strong></p>
<p>Understand the actual basics of Computer Science/Networking/It. You should endeavor to be able to exploit a system/network with the minimal resources possible.</p>
<p>I focused on living of the land from the very beginning of my career/training; it requires that you invest in actually learning things like Windows AD administration &amp; not cutting corners in you training/study, but it is a priceless skill set to have.</p>
<p>Learn defensive skills; spending some time as a Network Analyst is invaluable. Again, the solutions are almost always worth more to the customer/client/employer then the problems.</p>
<p>Make friends with IT &amp; System/Network Administrators if you are working an in-house position. Buy them coffee, talk to them often; there is usually a mutual interest in your and their interests that can result in an incredible skills/knowledge exchange.</p>
<p>You should learn to value all of the skill sets/experience of all the technology employees around you and endeavor to establish relationships based on mutual respect and skills/knowledge exchange.</p>
<p>If one of these employees is a greybeard Unix guru, they will provide insights into Linux/Unix Administration that are priceless (and almost all those I met could/would talk with me for hours, which was incredible).</p>
<p>We all suffer imposter syndrome; not knowing something is ok as long as you endeavor to learn it.</p>
<p>And ICMP/ping doesn’t have a dedicated port; managers running technical interviews love this question.</p>
<h3>Fun, personal stuff</h3>
<p><strong>6. Windows, Mac, or Linux What do you run?</strong></p>
<p>I run Linux; usually Devuan (Debian without System-D), Qubes or On the job, I am OS agnostic; whatever gets the job done. If possible, I will try to suggest/demonstrate the value of open source, but I am not going to be an obnoxious neckbeard about it.</p>
<p><strong>7. Programming language(s) of choice?</strong></p>
<p>Python 2.7, bits and pieces of many other languages. Mainly enough to change/alter code in exploits/tools to get it to do what I need and recognize vulns like deserialization.</p>
<p><strong>8. Do you use a mechanical keyboard? Is it ortholinear?</strong></p>
<p>No; I use plain old HP keyboards; I’ve seen some of the mechanical keyboards that have programmable tabs for scripts and stuff and would like to own one some day to build my Master Rig.</p>
<p><strong>9. Do you have any other hobbies or interests outside of infosec?</strong></p>
<p>Martial Arts; I’ve had 13 professional fights since 2005 in MMA/Muay Thai/Kickboxing. I’ve competed in kyokushin full contact tournaments as well; I’ve been training in some form of combative since I was 5 (my father was an amateur boxer).</p>
<p>I love reading; I read voraciously. I love film; anime…learning.</p>
<p>I am a huge proponent of self improvement, but not necessarily through self improvement gurus or teachings. I like the classics, like the Tao, Hagakure, The Book Of Rings…and challenging myself.</p>
<p>Challenging myself to know/exceed my limitations probably satisfies my definition of self improvement perfectly.</p>
<p><strong>10. Any other fun gadgets or hardware at home/the office?</strong></p>
<p>I’m a huge proponent of the Nexus 7 for Red Teaming/general computing given its power vs cost and ARM architecture; I will have material posted here about ti in 2019.</p>
<h3>Final Stuff</h3>
<p><strong>11. How’d you find 0x00sec?</strong></p>
<p>The NullByte exodus; I used to number that amongst sources I checked out weekly. I lurked this place forever before joining.</p>
<p><strong>12. Any other fun fact or detail you’d like to share with the community?</strong></p>
<p>I admire all of your work; I have infrastructure I’ve built out to keep an eye on things of interest. I don’t know if everyone here knows how rare/beautiful the level of courtesy/talent is here.</p>
<p><strong>13. Do you have any advice for new, up-and-coming hackers?</strong></p>
<p>Don’t cut corners; realize tools are just a means of helping to express skills/knowledge that there is no shortcut to ascertain. Your tooling no more makes you a hacker then buying a brush makes you a painter.</p>
<p><strong>14. Is there anything you’d like to say to the 0x00sec community?</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for providing a home for me; I went it alone for a long time and realized the upper levels of ability lay in congress with peers. I was right; my skills have grown exponentially in the last 2 years.</p>
<p><strong>15. Can you give us a HEX for your hat “color”?</strong></p>
<p>No Hex needed. I’m Gray through and through. I have nothing against BlackHats; we aren’t opponents until a job or circumstance makes us so and then it is only temporary.</p>
<p>I’ve learned more from BlackHats/GrayHats then WhiteHat; most of it was knowledge I had to seek out/cultivate myself, but that is the best kind.</p>
<p>I am an ethical hacker not because it is a convenient term for marketing myself, or because a cert tells me what I am, but because my actions/work are governed by my ethics.</p>
<h2>Thanks for joining! Vote below for our next guest. See you then!</h2>
<p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584/1">Click to view the poll.</a></p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-10584</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/knowing-null-maderas-making-an-impact-in-infosec/10584.rss">Knowing Null: maderas - Making an Impact in InfoSec</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
