<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reverse Engineering, Do We Really Understand It?</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780</link>
    <description>Hello members of 0x00sec!

Many of you are familiar or atleast heard of reverse engineering and reverse code engineering. Today I&#39;m going to urge you to give it a deeper thought and hopefully change your view on it.

It is a field that is mostly misunderstood and misinterpreted. The question &quot;what is reverse engineering?&quot; has many answers, most of it are shallow and superficial unfortunately. Now I dare you to think about a different but related question: &quot;what is engineering?&quot;.

Most common and abstract way to answer that will be something similar to: &quot;application of the scientific **knowledge**&quot;. Now take a pause. Think. What is _knowledge_ exactly and how it differs from _information_? And more importantly... Where does this knowledge **come from?**

When you answer those questions what you will see is that _reverse engineering_ is actually at the core of _engineering_. Reverse engineering **is** engineering. They complement eachother, one is not possible without the other.

Many people, in the past, have looked at the sky, watched the birds flying and dreamed of flying just like them. But those who **asked how** we can fly like birds, are the reason we have the field of _aeronautical engineering_ today.

Next time you hear someone saying that reverse code engineering is about reading assembly code and making abstract representations of it, please don&#39;t hesitate to spread this word. **Sadly**, lots of LOTS of words and concepts, each carrying its own history, are being emptied, stripped away from its philosophy and meaning and eventually being industrialized. You have already seen this. **Hacking**, remember? You know how it ends. Please don&#39;t let it happen.

What do you think?

#### Community Assigned Level:
[poll type=regular]
* Newbie
* Wannabe
* Hacker
* Wizard
* Guru
[/poll]</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 13:23:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Reverse Engineering</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Reverse Engineering, Do We Really Understand It?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 08:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-11780-3</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780.rss">Reverse Engineering, Do We Really Understand It?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reverse Engineering, Do We Really Understand It?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[EternalEclipse]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Everyone can have their own definition, mine is “Taking things apart to understand how they work”.<br>
I don’t feel strongly about the subject, it feels more like semantics. Plus, I don’t care about public opinion, especially in regards to science and technology.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 13:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-11780-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780.rss">Reverse Engineering, Do We Really Understand It?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reverse Engineering, Do We Really Understand It?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[hunter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello members of 0x00sec!</p>
<p>Many of you are familiar or atleast heard of reverse engineering and reverse code engineering. Today I’m going to urge you to give it a deeper thought and hopefully change your view on it.</p>
<p>It is a field that is mostly misunderstood and misinterpreted. The question “what is reverse engineering?” has many answers, most of it are shallow and superficial unfortunately. Now I dare you to think about a different but related question: “what is engineering?”.</p>
<p>Most common and abstract way to answer that will be something similar to: “application of the scientific <strong>knowledge</strong>”. Now take a pause. Think. What is <em>knowledge</em> exactly and how it differs from <em>information</em>? And more importantly… Where does this knowledge <strong>come from?</strong></p>
<p>When you answer those questions what you will see is that <em>reverse engineering</em> is actually at the core of <em>engineering</em>. Reverse engineering <strong>is</strong> engineering. They complement eachother, one is not possible without the other.</p>
<p>Many people, in the past, have looked at the sky, watched the birds flying and dreamed of flying just like them. But those who <strong>asked how</strong> we can fly like birds, are the reason we have the field of <em>aeronautical engineering</em> today.</p>
<p>Next time you hear someone saying that reverse code engineering is about reading assembly code and making abstract representations of it, please don’t hesitate to spread this word. <strong>Sadly</strong>, lots of LOTS of words and concepts, each carrying its own history, are being emptied, stripped away from its philosophy and meaning and eventually being industrialized. You have already seen this. <strong>Hacking</strong>, remember? You know how it ends. Please don’t let it happen.</p>
<p>What do you think?</p>
<h4>Community Assigned Level:</h4>
<p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780/1">Click to view the poll.</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 08:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-11780-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/reverse-engineering-do-we-really-understand-it/11780.rss">Reverse Engineering, Do We Really Understand It?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
