<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Time to part ways!</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/time-to-part-ways/1491</link>
    <description>It is said that once in a while a person has to reinvent himself (I follow Zen philosophy). I believe it&#39;s my time to answer myself to the questions I&#39;ve been pondering upon for quite some time now. So I&#39;ve decided to go on a break, facing the uncertainty of life to refuel the mind. 

Home is not a place but a feeling and I feel home in here seeing all these lovely enthusiasts. I couldn&#39;t contribute much but I wish this place will grow into something majestic and a harbor to everyone who seek knowledge. 

&quot;Parting is such sweet sorrow that I shall say goodnight till it be morrow.&quot;

Regards,

Cal0X</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 13:04:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Social</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/time-to-part-ways/1491.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Time to part ways!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kowalski]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>You’ll be surely missed for the time you’re gone. Good Luck!</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/time-to-part-ways/1491/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/time-to-part-ways/1491/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 13:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-1491-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/time-to-part-ways/1491.rss">Time to part ways!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Time to part ways!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cal0X]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>It is said that once in a while a person has to reinvent himself (I follow Zen philosophy). I believe it’s my time to answer myself to the questions I’ve been pondering upon for quite some time now. So I’ve decided to go on a break, facing the uncertainty of life to refuel the mind.</p>
<p>Home is not a place but a feeling and I feel home in here seeing all these lovely enthusiasts. I couldn’t contribute much but I wish this place will grow into something majestic and a harbor to everyone who seek knowledge.</p>
<p>“Parting is such sweet sorrow that I shall say goodnight till it be morrow.”</p>
<p>Regards,</p>
<p>Cal0X</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/time-to-part-ways/1491/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/time-to-part-ways/1491/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 09:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-1491-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/time-to-part-ways/1491.rss">Time to part ways!</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
