<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Databases - 0x00sec - The Home of the Hacker</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/c/databases/62</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Databases&#39; category </description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 21:45:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/c/databases/62.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Finding firebase databases that are exposed to the internet</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[spuqe]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Databases</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h1><a name="p-60431-firebase-1" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-60431-firebase-1"></a>Firebase</h1>
<p>Short video of the tool to everyone who doesn’t want to read full post <img src="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=15" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"> <a href="https://youtu.be/YsaPEnOPe7k" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://youtu.be/YsaPEnOPe7k</a></p>
<p>Script can be found at: <a href="https://github.com/spuqe/firebase" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub - spuqe/firebase: Firebase database finder.</a></p>
<h1><a name="p-60431-how-does-it-work-2" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-60431-how-does-it-work-2"></a>How does it work?</h1>
<p>Firebase does that when u first time create a database it will ask with small and long text that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is an test database and your security rules are defined as public… Click x to not see this again</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The text is a lot longer and that’s why not many people even read it. The font is also very small so you easily just ignore it. The text will never appear again to your screen.</p>
<p>fun thing is that all test databases are public to the internet long as you have the URL.</p>
<p>This small script just basicly searches for firebase databases. It can scan tons of databases in couple minutes and we have already founded over 1k of databases public to the internet. We found them in couple hours using our wordlist that wont be shared so don’t even ask for it!</p>
<h1><a name="p-60431-does-google-know-about-this-script-3" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-60431-does-google-know-about-this-script-3"></a>Does google know about this script?</h1>
<p>yes they know about it damn well but their little patch didn’t really do anything. Now those “test” databases just automaticly get closed after 30 days and that really doesn’t change much when there’s tons of those made and used daily. You can still easily find tons of databases. This script was made before the patch (ofc what did u think lol) and i didn’t want to share it to many people before some kind of patch but seems like google didn’t  give a shit so i  feel like it’s just good to share it here!</p>
<h1><a name="p-60431-how-to-use-firebasepy-4" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-60431-how-to-use-firebasepy-4"></a>How to use? Firebase.py</h1>
<p>Define wich worldlist you want to use (you can define it at the source or line 17) Just run the script after adding words to wordlist.txt Add the words like this 1 2 3 4 or it will not work!</p>
<p>When the database is founded you can see the name at /database/ and type the database name to your url bar like this: <a href="https://databasename.firebaseio.com/.json" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://databasename.firebaseio.com/.json</a></p>
<h1><a name="p-60431-how-to-use-our-word-list-generator-5" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-60431-how-to-use-our-word-list-generator-5"></a>How to use our word list generator?</h1>
<p>First of all if u want  a lot results you should make the word list your self!</p>
<p>WSL is a word list generator</p>
<p>usage:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>scraper.py -h] [-chr CHARS] [-min MIN_LENGTH] [-max MAX_LENGTH] [-out OUTPUT] wgen.py -h, --help show this help message with all commands.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>for example</p>
<blockquote>
<p>python3 scraper.py -chr=abc -min=1 -max=4 -out=output/wordlist.txt</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Have fun!</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/finding-firebase-databases-that-are-exposed-to-the-internet/23026">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/finding-firebase-databases-that-are-exposed-to-the-internet/23026</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 21:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-23026</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/finding-firebase-databases-that-are-exposed-to-the-internet/23026.rss">Finding firebase databases that are exposed to the internet</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Hacking operating systems assessment</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nitrax]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Databases</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi fellas,</p>
<p>As part of my work, I did plenty of researches about hacking / pentesting operating systems in order to find which one could be the most suitable for my needs. Chose his operating system is crucial and avoids unpleasant surprises that could lead to an incredible wastage of time (tools incompatibility, etc). That is why I decided to share with you guys, the fruits of my investigation. I hope that it will be helpful to anyone that still hesitate between different OSs.</p>
<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>Hacking or penetration testing relies, partially, on a set of tools used to assess multiple aspects of an information system. Their installation can be quite tedious, and their compatibilities with different operating systems is an obstacle that users face during the installation phase. To overcome this issue, several projects were created to provide an efficient and reliable support such as Kali Linux, BlackBuntu, BackBox, BlackArch, Parrot security OS and Cyborg Awk.</p>
<p>For the sake of this experience, I assessed those systems according to the following criteria : their usability, performance, stability, their number of tools available and the quality of their content manager. To ensure objectivity and consistency of my research, each distribution has been evaluated on a Virtual Machine possessing four Giga Bytes of RAM and two control processor units. This configuration has been specially chosen to minimise the amount of resources available in order to stress the system with greedy instructions such as ARP poisoning, shell bomb, etc.</p>
<h2>Kali Linux</h2>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/2e2f682d3f991100d8927ec99c77a8bce06cfa51.png" width="440" height="296"></p>
<p>Kali Linux is a Linux distribution based on Jessie Debian, created and maintained by Offensive Security, an influential company in the penetration testing area. From a usability point of view, this system presents, through GNOME 3, a user-friendly interface to its user which seems familiar to anybody who already used any mainstream Linux distribution e.g. Ubuntu, Xubuntu, Debian, etc. Moreover, the tools are classified by domain and make easier to discover new software. Furthermore, because this system is presented as a reference for pentesters and highly maintained, it affords a colossal quantity of tools, covering every possible computer security aspect. Hosted and available from their repository, it allows to keep tools updated, which is mandatory for such activity.</p>
<p>However, Kali Linux has critical performance and stability issues. Indeed, it is based, for Network Interface Card compatibility reasons, on a modified version of Debian UNIX Kernel. Moreover, it is important to note that the previous version of Kali Linux was Backtrack5, which suffered from the same issue. Most of them have been fixed, but the essential problem remains.</p>
<p>To conclude, Kali Linux is a great pentesting operating system. However, its lack of stability reduces its efficiency. This distribution is well more focused to run on a live session which involves some problems for a long pentesting session. It is, certainly, possible to create a persistent environment but it requires external tools which are not provided during the installation phase. Despite those issues, Kali Linux is available on several platforms e.g. Raspberry Pi, Chromebooks, Odroid and tablet thanks to NetHunter. Moreover, the important community involved in this project allows resolving rapidly most of the reported issues that can occur when a release or a tool become obsolete.</p>
<h2>BlackBuntu</h2>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/1/161505aa47477d6a5798db6723bf8bb47d4b0c7e.png" width="440" height="330"></p>
<p>BlackBuntu is based on Xubuntu, a fork of Ubuntu which originally provides a XFCE interface which has been replaced by GNOME in order to improve the usability of the distribution. However, this system is awful to use. Indeed, tools are not installed properly on the machine and are just reachable in their distinct directory which makes impossible to run a tool from the home user. Moreover, the classification of those tools is not intuitive at all, and it is very complicated to detect the presence of specific software without using locate, or similar, command line. Furthermore, this project was abandoned by its founders and developers in 2014 therefore, rendering it out of date.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the performance and stability provided by BlackBuntu seems reasonable, excepted some termcaps inconstancy.</p>
<p>To conclude, this pentesting distribution had a great potential but became completely obsolete, due to the fact that it is not maintained anymore.</p>
<h2>Backbox</h2>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/402b4bebab896b7d865c1cfaa7f0cca0fdcaa869.png" width="440" height="297"></p>
<p>BackBox is based on Ubuntu and provides a nice and user-friendly interface. However, the menu has been completely revamped to give way to a set of submenus that have to be, consecutively clicked, as an LDAP directory software would provide, to display the associated tools, which is, in long term usage, quite irritating. Moreover, this system suffers for random crashes, reducing its stability and performance considerably. Indeed, it is not acceptable to have to reboot for such reason during a penetration testing when each second is valuable.</p>
<p>Regardless, BackBox provides a reasonable list of tools and have, as Kali Linux, its own repository which ensures the reliability of their system.</p>
<p>To conclude, despite the fact that BackBox provides fewer tools than Kali Linux, it seems to be a good pentesting OS and runs quite well on few resources.</p>
<h2>BlackArch</h2>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/2356ab6a4c053e59af65f0eb8b28ec36a6bddb28.png" width="440" height="331"></p>
<p>BlackArch is an operating system based on ArchLinux and well known for its lightness. Indeed, ArchLinux embeds just the necessary components required for its installation and its execution. Moreover, it comes without GUI which affords the possibility to create a customised working environment, depending on the tastes of anyone. Furthermore, BlackArch is distinguishable from others by its modularity. In fact, it is nothing more or less that just a layer that can be implemented over a traditional ArchLinux distribution, allowing users to convert their existing system into a complete penetration testing laboratory.</p>
<p>From a usability point of view, BlackArch is formidable. Indeed, every tool, thanks to FluxBox, is accessible through the right click, making it very easy to handle. By the same token, the amount of tools provided by this operating system is colossal, around one thousand and forty, and largely exceed those available on Kali Linux. Lastly, as the previously assessed systems, BlackArch has its own tools repository, avoiding any obsolescence.</p>
<p>However, by essence, ArchLinux is not the most reliable and stable operating system on the market. Indeed, users often play the role of Beta testers to assess and report incidences once the system is updated, which can lead, sometimes, to a downgrade. Consequently, without any deeper experiences in the Linux world, it will be almost impossible for a novice to handle this system.</p>
<p>To conclude, BlackArch is a very lightweight system which runs perfectly for whom to feel at ease with system architecture, partitioning processing and command line. It seems to be a good trade-off between a home-made distribution and a Kali Linux or a Parrot Security OS.</p>
<h2>Parrot Security OS</h2>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/7/7c4301b9e0f14f2daea7fb3d707ade5110156748.png" width="440" height="295"></p>
<p>Parrot Security OS is based on Debian and consequently, takes advantage of its reliability. Moreover, it presents to its user through a user-friendly and intuitive interface with a classified tools list, improving the usability of the distribution. As Kali Linux, it furnishes a vast number of tools, covering multiple aspects of computer security and keeps them up-to-date via their repository. Lastly, the batterie of tests shows that the system has a great performance and stability, incomparable with other similar pentesting distributions.</p>
<p>Finally, Parrot Security OS is quite similar to Kali Linux but well more stable and performant.  It is, in my opinion, the best user-friendly and pre-built OS for pentesting. Moreover, it provides the possibility to run in stealth or forensic mode which makes this OS highly flexible and could fit with any needs.</p>
<h2>Cyborg Hawk</h2>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/1/153cfd15a3ca364604af6d9b00a882bd9086cd7e.png" width="440" height="295"></p>
<p>Cyborg Hawk is based on Debian and seems to be inspired from Kali Linux. Indeed, it provides the same menu, user interface and tools than Kali with some additional fancy widgets such as the memory and CPU usage, the disk space available, etc.</p>
<p>However, those fantasies have a terrible impact on the performance. Indeed, by randomly moving a window, the CPU usage reaches the 60%, which emits doubts about its reliability.<br>
To conclude, Cyborg Hawk tries to distinguish itself via some fancy widgets whose aim is to put the user into the skin of a hacker but without really succeed to provide a reliable and stable environment.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Choose the best support is critical to ensure the quality and the reliability of your hacking / pentesting session. Each of the operating system assessed previously has its own regarding usability, stability and performance. However, the tools provided by those systems could be, for most of them, useless, according to your objectives and so, can potentially slow down the machine for non relevant reasons.</p>
<p>Consequently, I advise to whom want to possess an efficient and reliable machine, to set up his own with, only, the tools that are necessary to reach the settled goals. Moreover, install a tool from scratch improves the understanding of its behaviours and simplifies the learning phase. Lastly, it affords the possibility to have a minimalist and ergonomic interface without undesirable features that can impact on the performance.</p>
<h1>Are you interested by my personal setup ?</h1>
<p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/hacking-operating-systems-assessment/1323/1">Click to view the poll.</a></p>
<p>Best,<br>
Nitrax</p>
            <p><small>29 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/hacking-operating-systems-assessment/1323">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/hacking-operating-systems-assessment/1323</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 17:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-1323</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/hacking-operating-systems-assessment/1323.rss">Hacking operating systems assessment</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Foxcatcher! [Part 2] - Data Mining</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[n3xUs]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Databases</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome back! So in my previous post we talked about extracting the <code>places.sqlite</code> file from our target’s computer and there were a couple of things I forgot to mention.</p>
<p>First, <strong>what actually is a profile?</strong> Below is how Mozilla defines a <em>User Profile</em>:</p>
<p>##<span class="hashtag-raw">#Mozilla</span>’s Support <a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/profiles-where-firefox-stores-user-data" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Page</a> -</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All of the changes you make in Firefox, like your home page, what toolbars you use, extensions you have installed, saved passwords and your bookmarks, are all stored in a special folder, called a profile. Your profile folder is stored in a separate place from the Firefox program so that, if something ever goes wrong with Firefox, your information will still be there. It also means you can uninstall Firefox without losing your settings and you don’t have to reinstall Firefox to clear your information or troubleshoot a problem.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>^ This also means that if someone with malicious intent or not (like us) gets his hands on this file, he could gather all sorts of data about a user ^</em></p>
<p>Second, <strong>a user can have more than one profile.</strong> In my previous article, I told you that the name of our profile is a random combination of letters and numbers followed by a ‘<code>.default</code>’. This ‘<code>.default</code>’ is the actual name of our profile, so if you create a profile named ‘<code>0x00sec_test</code>’, your profile folder will be ‘<code>xxxxxxxxx.0x00sec_test</code>’ (I’ll showcase below).</p>
<p>The good thing about our script is that it will copy all the profiles present in the Profile Folder!</p>
<hr>
<p>With that being said, lets focus on today’s subject - <strong>Datamining the ‘<code>places.sqlite</code>’ file!</strong></p>
<p>##<span class="hashtag-raw">#What</span> is Data Mining?</p>
<p>Simply put, Data Mining is sorting through data to identify patterns and establish relationships.<br>
This could be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Looking for patterns where one event is connected to another event</li>
<li>Looking for patterns where one event leads to another later event</li>
<li>Looking for new patterns</li>
<li>Finding and visually documenting groups of facts not previously known</li>
<li>Discovering patterns in data that can lead to reasonable predictions about the future (predictive analytics)</li>
</ul>
<p>(source: <a href="http://searchsqlserver.techtarget.com/definition/data-mining" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">What is data mining? | Definition from TechTarget</a>)<br>
(useful link to further understand data mining - <a href="http://www.anderson.ucla.edu/faculty/jason.frand/teacher/technologies/palace/datamining.htm" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">http://www.anderson.ucla.edu/faculty/jason.frand/teacher/technologies/palace/datamining.htm</a>)</p>
<p>What we will be doing here is point number 4 - finding and visually documenting groups of facts not previously known - that is, gather information on a target’s browsing habits/prefrences/interests…</p>
<hr>
<p>First thing we’ll need is a DB Browser for SQLite, which you can find <a href="http://sqlitebrowser.org/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">here</a>.</p>
<p>For this project. I went ahead and created another user profile named ‘foxcatcher_test’ and just searched some random stuff for demonstration purposes (btw, forgive me for the lack of creativeness on my searches…)</p>
<p>Once we have our Browser installed, we have to open our ‘places.sqlite’ file with said Browser.<br>
(fyi, I’m totally not an expert on SQL and Databases, so if you have any suggestion/improvements/corrections, feel free to let me know).</p>
<p>This is the first window you’ll see:</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9b594ad03ce9cf4832a3343723a6af5b628e21a3.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/mahjzoX6p81kdCEFHpsT8p9sAgz.png?dl=1" title="sql1.png" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9b594ad03ce9cf4832a3343723a6af5b628e21a3.png" width="690" height="381"></a></div><p></p>
<p>I think that the most insteresting tables for us are:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>moz_bookmarks</code> - User boookmarks</li>
<li><code>moz_favicons</code> - <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Favicon" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Favicons</a> stored in cache</li>
<li><code>moz_inputhistory</code> - Search history</li>
<li><code>moz_places</code> - Websites visited</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ll be analysing the <code>moz_bookmarks</code> &amp; <code>moz_places</code> tables.</p>
<p>Let’s start with <code>moz_bookmarks</code>:</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/3/3941214128a005b5253354bc2686924d5eb2a971.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/8auKS07mQqBQlPifc3E98wtoTJv.png?dl=1" title="sql_bk.png" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/3/3941214128a005b5253354bc2686924d5eb2a971.png" width="690" height="385"></a></div><p></p>
<p>To search the database, you need to know some basic SQL Syntax. To query the DB, go to the last tab on the right side that reads ‘Execute SQL’. On the right lower corner, you see the <code>moz_bookmarks</code> table and it’s keys (the most important one is the ‘<code>title</code>’ key, which is the name of the bookmarked website, so this is the key we want). To query the DB to search this key for data, we type:</p>
<pre><code>SELECT title
FROM moz_bookmarks
</code></pre>
<p>And press on the ‘play’ button on top.</p>
<p>On the lower left corner, we can see the results from this query.<br>
Right off the bat, we see that the most common term is ‘manchester’, so maybe our target is living there or thinking to move there. We will have to dig further.</p>
<p>Let’s go into the <code>moz_places</code> table now to see if we can find something to better understand our target.</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9d1a7bea17e461eaba7f6f34c74912af383f204e.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/mpNHGHgWXUFABSKfA8Y7UMq9C3A.png?dl=1" title="sql_places.png" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9d1a7bea17e461eaba7f6f34c74912af383f204e.png" width="690" height="356"></a></div><p></p>
<p>As you can see, the <code>moz_places</code> table has a lot of keys. I believe the one of most interest to us are the ‘url’, ‘title’ and ‘visit_count’. So let’s query the DB for those keys!</p>
<pre><code>SELECT title, url, visit_count
FROM moz_places
order by visit_count desc
</code></pre>
<p>This query will give us the website’s title, it’s url and how many times it has been visited by the user (in the order that we specify, in this case title → url → visit_count), all in descending order (from the most visited, to the less).</p>
<p>Pretty neat, huh?</p>
<p>Now let’s see what our target is actually searching for…</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/2c1fcbdb29e5df70334a283bbe5f651fbf55bc26.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/6il8blXFDcxGdAiFwlsmIxYKzyK.png?dl=1" title="sq_places1.png" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/2c1fcbdb29e5df70334a283bbe5f651fbf55bc26.png" width="690" height="162"></a></div><p></p>
<p>Huh. We now know that our target is searching for elementary/primary schools in Manchester. This could mean that he/she may have an infant who is starting school soon. Also, we know that the only schools he/she was interested in was Roman Catholic ones, so we can say with some accuracy that that’s his/hers religion.</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9afff2f7eeb48c3357cf4a721670c82524b48c41.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/m7bTJcUW1EaX4k9ns6D5z7lr7lT.png?dl=1" title="sql_places2.png" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9afff2f7eeb48c3357cf4a721670c82524b48c41.png" width="690" height="156"></a></div><p></p>
<p>Oh, what’s this? Apparently, our target was searching for flights from NY to Manchester. Maybe he/she lives in New York and thinking of moving to Manchester. That would explain why our subject is searching for schools in the UK.</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/1/1be6c92b2794ce6583d7870ddb745da87f7d4c23.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/3YPlzPf7KGNXXzldoMW2NQUI4dd.png?dl=1" title="sql_places3.png" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/1/1be6c92b2794ce6583d7870ddb745da87f7d4c23.png" width="690" height="157"></a></div><p></p>
<p>Ok, with the data above, we can be pretty sure that he/she is moving to Manchester, since their searches focus more on jobs and schools. Also, we see that the subject was searching for Hairdressers in the area, maybe this could point to a gender. We know that hairdressers are usually attended by females, so let’s assume the gender ir female (hope I don’t trigger anyone, heh heh)(also, I’m tired of writing ‘he/she’).</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/da33fdc08b71377ad7441d846f7bb83b230af75e.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/v8jtIaghbPZ0Ra3fzHQR85y3lh4.png?dl=1" title="sql_places4.png" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/da33fdc08b71377ad7441d846f7bb83b230af75e.png" width="690" height="156"></a></div><p></p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/8/8acb3695101b979aa49003520b64671b7413afc2.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/jNPgWg9KslG6RuBbHcL1iDBrLTs.png?dl=1" title="places.png" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/8/8acb3695101b979aa49003520b64671b7413afc2.png" width="690" height="154"></a></div><p></p>
<p>From the screenshots above, we can also assume that she is looking to adopt a dog from a kennel and is mostly interested in small port dogs, like the jack russel annd jack terrier!</p>
<p>So, from what we gathered, we can build a (very) loose profile of our Target:</p>
<p>GENDER: Female<br>
AGE: Late 20’s/30’s??<br>
CHILDREN: At least one<br>
RELIGION: Roman Catholic<br>
ADDRESS: Somewhere in NY, looking to move to Manchester<br>
INTERESTS: Dogs; Particularly Jack Russels/Terrier (Small port dogs)</p>
<hr>
<p>And that brings us to the end of my post!<br>
Hope this gave you some idea of how data mining could work to gather info on a target and how you can build a profile on said target.</p>
<p>As always, thanks for reading!</p>
<p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/foxcatcher-part-3-how-to-prevent-data-theft/1319" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Part 3</a> - How to prevent data theft</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/foxcatcher-part-2-data-mining/1317">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/foxcatcher-part-2-data-mining/1317</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 22:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-1317</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/foxcatcher-part-2-data-mining/1317.rss">Foxcatcher! [Part 2] - Data Mining</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Pentesting: The truth behind the myth</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nitrax]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Databases</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi fellas,</p>
<p>Following my conversations with you guys on IRC about the job of pentester, I decided to introduce you the different facets of a pentesting and maybe enlighten gray areas that remain in this domain.</p>
<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong> : Once again, it will be a long reading <img src="/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<h1>Pentesting</h1>
<p>Companies spend millions of dollars into countermeasures in order to protect as much as possible their infrastructures. Those treatments can be separated into two types :</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Organisational treatments</strong>, which concern audit, reminder or security policies, focusing, mainly, on the establishment and maintenance of the information security at an organisational level.</li>
<li>
<strong>Technical treatments</strong>, referring to the implementation of backup or encryption technology whose aim is to ensure the security and availability of their services.</li>
</ul>
<p>However, even working with the best engineers or DevOps will not guarantee that the configured system will be flawless. As stated Wright C. from the SANS Institute in 2011, “absolute security does not exist and nor can it be achieved”. That is why pentesting and vulnerability assessment are mandatory. Moreover, such audit affords the possibility to be certified ISO27001 or CREST (Council of Registered Ethical Security Testers), certifications which are critical for the company reputation and have an indubitable impact on the competitive edge and profit.</p>
<h2>Definition</h2>
<p>Pentesting, or also known as penetration testing, consists of the assessment of a given scope, which can be an entire network or a web application, with the intention of detecting potential breaches that can be exploited to “break into” a system, in order to access confidential information or provoke damages. Techniques used by pentesters are quite similar to those used by hackers and are not restrained to technical tools. Indeed, pentesters can be allowed to assess the human vulnerability of the company, using social engineering to bypass the existing security.</p>
<p>“Three basic models are utilized by the Ethical hacker in order to [assess] the network. These models are the Black Box Model, the White Box Model and the Gray Box Model […]. Each model approaches the [assessment] from a different vantage point, all will have a different focus and therefore, a unique perspective that will be derived from the [standard evaluation]” (Hafele, 2004).</p>
<p><strong>White Box :</strong></p>
<p>In this configuration, the pentesters team possesses a complete documentation about the infrastructure, the security policies and any security system which have been implemented to avoid external access.</p>
<p>This type of pentesting allows to dive deeper and to detect specific flaws involved by the usage of an insecure module or a particular protocol. Thanks to that information, the team will be able to target and focus their attacks on the right place and save time by skipping the reconnaissance phase.</p>
<p><strong>Black Box :</strong></p>
<p>Black Box pentesting is the exact opposite of the White one. In this case, no information is disclosed to the team and the pentesters have to go through the entire procedure to detect flaws which can be exploited.</p>
<p>This context is well more realistic than previously and gives a better idea of the information system security.</p>
<p><strong>Gray Box :</strong></p>
<p>Gray box is more a mix of the previous configurations. Indeed, the employer can choose the information that he want to communicate with the pentesters in order to assess and test a particular aspect of their system. This context is often chosen when the company intends to certify a given scope for further requirements.</p>
<p>Once done, pentesters have to provide a complete report, showing every flaw detected and treatments that have to be implemented to thwart them.</p>
<p>To conclude, a pentesting “can uncover aspects of security policy that are lacking […], provide feedback on the most at risk routes into a company or application […] and penetration testing reports can be used to help train developers to make fewer mistakes.” (Pearson, 2014).</p>
<h2>Pentesting phases</h2>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/2e2b798866de182f77cf6c275bf27f89952dcc1d.png" width="440" height="167"></p>
<p>The schema above helps to have a better understanding of the pentesting methodology. However, it is necessary to describe each phase that makes up a penetration testing. Indeed, it follows six principal stages :</p>
<p><strong>Determining the scope</strong> is the primary and the most important phase during which the pentesters and the customer establish any aspects of the information system that has to be assessed.</p>
<p><strong>Reconnaissance or Recon phase</strong> consists of gathering as much as possible of information about the current infrastructure and technologies in place.</p>
<p><strong>Discovery phase</strong> is the study of information collected during the previous step and is crucial to determine weaknesses and flaws present within the scope.</p>
<p><strong>Attacking phase</strong> is the exploitation of the detected flaws, that can be achieved through a brute-force, social engineering or adapted payload (small executable that carries an exploit and allows to take control of a target or install backdoor).</p>
<p><strong>Taking control and pivoting</strong> represents the fact to use attacks to obtain a granted access to a system and spread out the infection to the entire network.</p>
<p><strong>Report phase</strong> is the final step which consists of collecting any evidence about flaws and breaches detected and providing treatments to undertake those risks.</p>
<p>It is important to note, that this procedure can change according to the situation. However, it reflects the overall idea of a penetration testing process.</p>
<h1>Ethics</h1>
<p>As stated earlier in this paper, penetration testers are hired to detect flaws and misconceptions of an internal network infrastructure, a web application or a software. However, it is important to differentiate them from hackers. Indeed, the pentesters perform their analysis according to the legality and the ethics. Indeed, “penetration testing vivifies ethics, forcing practitioners to think about the consequences of a variety of situations, ranging from agreeing the parameters of a test, to deciding which techniques should or should not be allowed during a test (Bishop, 2007)” (Faily, S. et al., 2015).</p>
<p>To guide them during their activity the SANS and the CERT published a set of rules whose aim is to determine what has to be respected to be compliant with the law and the ethics.</p>
<p>According to the CERT (Code of Ethics, 2016) pentesters must:</p>
<ul>
<li>Keep private and confidential information gained in their professional work.</li>
<li>Never knowingly use software or process that is obtained or retained either illegally or unethically.</li>
<li>Not to associate with malicious hackers nor engage in any malicious activities.</li>
<li>Ensure all penetration testing activities are authorized and within legal limits.</li>
<li>Ensure ethical conduct and professional care at all times on all professional assignments without prejudice.</li>
<li>Use the property of a client or employer only in ways properly authorized, and with the owner’s knowledge and consent.</li>
</ul>
<p>From an other side, the SANS (IT - Code of Ethics, 2004) is much more focused on the interpersonal skills and the need to be honest with his own capabilities, essential qualities to work in this domain, such as :</p>
<ul>
<li>I will strive for technical excellence in the IT profession by maintaining and enhancing my own knowledge and skills.</li>
<li>When possible I will demonstrate my performance capability with my skills via projects, leadership, and/or accredited educational programs […].</li>
<li>I will not hesitate to seek assistance or guidance when faced with a task beyond my abilities or experience. […] I will treat this as an opportunity to learn new techniques and approaches.</li>
<li>I will strive to be perceived as and be an honest and trustworthy employee.</li>
</ul>
<p>However, those guidances are more theoretical than practical and, unfortunately, little research has been done in this area, which “fail[s] to provide advice on how to deal with conflicts of ethical significance“ (Faily, S. et al., 2015), and the problematics associated with this activity remains unknown. The following text, extract from <em>Critical Review : Ethical Dilemmas and Dimensions in Penetration Testing</em> wrote by, …, myself <img src="/images/emoji/twitter/smile.png?v=9" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:">, clarify this subject.</p>
<p>Indeed, this research paper highlights the ethical dilemmas and dimension associated with penetration testing and the potential fallacies and biases involved with the position taken by the pentesters. Moreover, it demonstrates how the client’s trust can be gained and how they can assure the result of their works. The study of those challenges which face pentesters will definitely help to improve methods and tools used to penetration test a system.</p>
<p>In order to assess those problems eight professionals and certified pentesters, working in the UK, have been interviewed at their workplace for forty-five minutes each. For the sake of  this study, four principal areas of debate have been chosen: responsibilities, practices, ethics and assurance.</p>
<p>Those interviews allow one to highlight two mains dilemmas which are how to manage the penetration testing in order to satisfy the client and the staff without breaking the established trust between both parties and how to manage the testing phase by using a structured strategy or an unstructured one which allows more flexibility and more creativity. Thanks to those dilemmas two different positions have been identified, the individual / unstructured position (IU) and the whole / structured position (WS). Each of them has a different point of view about the value of ethics, the ethical appeal, the client and the practice focus.</p>
<p>Indeed, IUs are more likely to consider ethics as an interpersonal skill acquired by experiences and considers the ethical appeal common sense. Moreover, they tend to establish individual relationships with people within the company and due to the fact that they do not consider the organization as a whole, they are often subject to hostility from uneducated employees in terms of security. Finally, the focus of their practice is narrow with regards to knowledge of their tools, which assure the reliability of their report.</p>
<p>WS works in a different way. In fact, ethics and moral issue are discussed within the team by placing the associated risk in the right context in order to evaluate each facet of the dilemma. Furthermore, they consider the client organization more as a whole and pay attention to educating  employees about penetration tests and try to keep them in touch of any discovery. Lastly, the focus of their practice tries to avoid any automatic report and logs in order to assure the veracity of the final report and, consequently, to avoid any doubt that the client may have towards automatized tools.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/dc91ed4e661945404ce91e25d1c3a56025988be8.png" width="439" height="211"></p>
<p>To conclude, there exists different approaches that can be chosen by a pentester. However, each of them has their own fallacies and biases. Indeed, the IU can be influenced by his team members and that can affect his proper definition of ethics if his co-workers have a wrong perception of this area and the WS, by educating the client about penetration test and providing a fully personnel report, cannot be sure that every countermeasure indicated will be applied. In fact, the client could just use this result to obtain his accreditation, whereas a technical report does not allow this kind of misuse. Moreover, both  are exposed to the same dilemmas and must deal with them. Consequently, the choice of position is purely a question of point of view. Finally, the guidances exposed above are more an unofficial code that needs to be implicitly respected by pentesters, and companies have no guaranty about their integrity.</p>
<h1>Report</h1>
<p>The report is an essential part of a penetration testing and, as said Lam et al., “if you do not document it, it did not happen”. Indeed, this report describes the methodology, timeline and scope of the pentesting. Moreover, it highlights vulnerabilities and associated countermeasures than can be implemented to ensure the security of the information system. However, like ethics, little papers and researches have been published in this domain, and any norm has been established yet. As stated Alharbi Mansour A., “Writing a penetration testing report is an art that needs to be learned to make sure that the report has delivered the right message to the right people”.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the reporting process can be broken down into four stages :</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/d37aa76bb2f8b258213ddd4d66f205f9781cb268.png" width="440" height="271"></p>
<h2>report planning</h2>
<p>In a first place, pentesters have to define at least six entities :</p>
<p><em>Report objectives</em> : The objectives allow to determine the aim of the penetration testing precisely and consequently, the scope which has to be assessed.</p>
<p><em>Time</em> : Pentesters have to define the testing time with their client to allow the company to be prepared and able to react adequately to any issues involved in the penetration testing. Moreover, this agreement is mandatory for testers to be compliant with the law and act as a “Get out jail free Card” if something goes wrong.</p>
<p><em>Consider the target audience</em> : The content and the technical aspect used in a report will depend on the targeted audience. The consideration of this factor will ensure the readability and the understandability of the document and, in a case of incomprehension, can invalidate the entire operation.</p>
<p><em>Report classification</em> : Because pentesters deal with sensitive data, it is recommended to classify and control the report to avoid any leak at a lower level of clearance. This classification will be done according to the company security policy.</p>
<p><em>Report distribution</em> : According to the level of security of the report, it is advised to state the number of soft and hard copies that will be distributed once the document drafted and reviewed. Controlling its distribution is crucial to limit the risk of electronic or physical eavesdropping.</p>
<p><em>Information cleanup</em> : Once, submitted, any residual information present on the pentesters machines has to be deleted to avoid any problem. Indeed, “ethical responsibilities do not stop when the test is done, however. After the test is completed, [pentesters] should perform due diligence to ensure the confidentiality of the test results. Some penetration testing firms have been known to circulate test results to other companies as samples of their work. These results contain detailed steps on how to break into an e-finance website for a particular financial institution and collect sensitive customer data. [The] institution [was shocked] when it discovered these contents being distributed to its competitors! Therefore, [penetration testers] are under an ethical obligation to keep the details of the report confidential. Shred any hard copies of the report, and delete all soft copies using a wiping utility such as PGP or Axcrypt.” (Newman &amp; Whitker, 2006).</p>
<h2>Information collection</h2>
<p>Due to the amount of information gathered during the penetration testing, it is considered as a best practice to record constantly the data that will be useful for the report such as screenshots, outputs, logs, etc. For security and confidentiality concerns, pentesters had to use a secure platform to store and centralised those materials.</p>
<h2>Draft and final review</h2>
<p>Before taking into consideration the layout and the proofreading, pentesters have to write a rough draft that will represent at least 60% of the final report. Later, in order to ensure the quality and the relevance of this document, a person, according to the type of pentesting, will be assigned to its review. The reviewer can be, in the case of white boxing, an employee of the established company with strong knowledge about the infrastructure and the current security or an other pentester if and only if the penetration testing is on black box configuration.</p>
<h2>Layout</h2>
<p>To improve the readability and the impact of the report, it has to follow a sober and classical layout, consisting on :</p>
<ul>
<li>Cover Page</li>
<li>Document properties and Version control, showing the document modifications, the author, the date of creation, etc</li>
<li>Table of content and table of tables and figures</li>
<li>Executive summary, describing the methodology used, the scope, the objectives, the timeline, the summary of findings and a summary of recommendations</li>
<li>Glossary, to define technical terms</li>
<li>Appendices, used for further details about outputs or logs but the content of the report should be completely independent of this section</li>
</ul>
<h2>Vulnerabilities and risks classification</h2>
<p>One of the essential parts of the report is the vulnerabilities and risks classification whose aim is to summarise the detected flaws and provide a baseline for the chief security officer in charge of the company security.</p>
<p>Those should, ideally, be represented by some graphs, similar to those below, classifying and grouping vulnerabilities according to their severity.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/4e18d088e231c6a89e4e0440132608705ed777b3.png" width="690" height="182"></p>
<p>For the sake of the report applicability, it is mandatory to analyse each risk by taking account of their threat, vulnerability and impact on the information system.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/c/c40012e71c4f1dab930d37edd38e943751c7d675.png" width="440" height="142"></p>
<p>Thanks to the table above, pentesters are now able to calculate the risk rating and start the classification. However, it is important to take into consideration their likelihood in order to adjust the baseline provided to the customer.</p>
<p><img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/5/5d62125a9a8e1e541e2f92058df4e0e9dc7d3a94.png" width="690" height="150"></p>
<p>Each vulnerability must be assessed and its risk score compared to the previously calculated risk rating, allowing to separate benign breaches from the critical one. Moreover, each flaw has to be described, rated, the exploit used has to be explained, and at least one treatment has to be provided in order to, according to its risk level, mitigate, prevent or acknowledge the vulnerability.</p>
<p>To conclude, the report is vital for any pentesting activity and shows the methodology and procedures used to achieve the objectives established previously. Moreover, by describing, classifying and highlighting each vulnerability, it provides a complete baseline to the company whose aim is to guide them in their security process.</p>
<h1>Personal feedback</h1>
<p>Pentesting is a real vocation and requires modesty, hard working and an insatiable thirst for knowledge. Indeed, you have to continuously maintain you up to date with the lastest CVEs and technologies in used by companies to be efficient at any time. Furthermore, the amount of knowledge required is colossal e.g Network infrastructure, protocols (MACAW, ALOHA, TCP/IP, OSI, etc.), architecture system, programming skills, etc. Moreover, you have to be at ease with your redaction skills and pass 20 hours on a report should not afraid you ! It is, from my point of view, a job very rewarding and interesting where each day will enrich your base of knowledge (almost :P). So, if you have the envy and the opportunity to work as a pentester, don’t hesitate you will not regret it !</p>
<h1>FAQ</h1>
<p><strong><em>Which tools do you use ?</em></strong></p>
<p>Mainly your brain <img src="/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"> Cause you have to deeply understand how the inner things work to be able to detect any potential breaches that can be present in a wrong configuration, implementation , … (I would like to thanks every admin sys that make my work so enjoyable &lt;3). Additionaly, we use several tools to help us during the discovery phase such as Metasploit, SQLmap, ZAP, Wapiti, Nessus, Burp suite, SSLscan, Qualys, Nmap, SIPvicious, VIPROY, etc. (non exhaustive list).</p>
<p><strong><em>How many time the report takes ?</em></strong></p>
<p>The report takes a third of the period associate to the mission. Basically, we write the report during the testing phase to avoid a shit load of work at the end of the contract.</p>
<p><strong><em>Do you use social engineering ?</em></strong></p>
<p>Unfortunately, nop. This is, generally, not allowed by the customer. Indeed, it can affect  the targeted employee, … To resolve the human issue, an internal organizational assessment is done in parallel.</p>
<p><strong><em>How much are you paid ?</em></strong></p>
<p>It depends of your country, for a junior :</p>
<p>France : 40K / year<br>
UK : 65K / year<br>
US : 70K / year<br>
Germany : 35K / year</p>
<p><strong><em>Does it boring ?</em></strong></p>
<p>Sometimes when the mission consists on assessing static website …</p>
<p><strong><em>Do certifications are certifications mandatory?</em></strong></p>
<p>Being certificated will definitely help you to get a job. However, if you know how to sell yourself and if you have a good background (being active on a forum, perform a technology watch, participate in CTFs or challenges) you will be ok.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading and I hope you enjoyed this article and that it helped you to have a better overview of a pentesting and the job of a pentester.</p>
<p>Best,<br>
Nitrax</p>
<p>P.S : Feel free to ask me questions !</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/pentesting-the-truth-behind-the-myth/1277">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/pentesting-the-truth-behind-the-myth/1277</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 14:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-1277</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/pentesting-the-truth-behind-the-myth/1277.rss">Pentesting: The truth behind the myth</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the Databases category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IoTh1nkN0t]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Databases</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>(Replace this first paragraph with a brief description of your new category. This guidance will appear in the category selection area, so try to keep it below 200 characters. <strong>Until you edit this description or create topics, this category won’t appear on the categories page.</strong>)</p>
<p>Use the following paragraphs for a longer description, or to establish category guidelines or rules:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Why should people use this category? What is it for?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How exactly is this different than the other categories we already have?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What should topics in this category generally contain?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do we need this category? Can we merge with another category, or subcategory?</p>
</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/about-the-databases-category/1011">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/about-the-databases-category/1011</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 15:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-1011</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/about-the-databases-category/1011.rss">About the Databases category</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Decrypting files/hacking database?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[appie35]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Databases</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>yo people<br>
i have a question about how web shops databases works. so all our information get saved on a db but where is db saved in a server ? and where in this world are they saved is there any tool with.  you can scan it like if you want to hack somthing you gone scan for vulnaribilty’s  but with a database i there any spacial tool for it ?  like what if some one had a debt on a  webshop and he hacked the db’s is it possible to delete everything or encrypt anything.  thats my question about database’s.</p>
<p>thanks in advance for your help.</p>
            <p><small>14 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/decrypting-files-hacking-database/443">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/decrypting-files-hacking-database/443</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 13:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-443</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/decrypting-files-hacking-database/443.rss">Decrypting files/hacking database?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>MTA Database Certification</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sea]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Databases</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey there mates, it’s Jack Sea from Null - Byte! I heard a lot of you came to this site so I decided to drop on by and write a few posts. This first one covers a nifty cert I picked up recently from the Microsoft Technical Associate line.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Why is this important to me?</strong> Well, you might not be interested in database administration, but if you plan on becoming an ethical hacker or security guru, you need to understand how they work and how to secure them.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>So what is on the exam?</strong> Honestly the exam was 95% multiple choice, with around 38 questions. 2-3 questions asked you to re-order code so that is worked properly, which is incredibly simple if you know just the basics of SQL. A lot of questions asked about functions of the database such as views, user groups, and even one question about injections. (This was also on the MTA: Security cert)</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>How can I study for this exam?</strong> Well first off, you need to learn SQL. Microsoft has a practice database called “AdventureWorks2012” which you can download and install, along with an ebook that walks you through the fundamentals of database design. From the fundamental principle of what is a table all the way to normalization, this 200 page ebook gives you plenty of exercises and practice. 100% of the material I learned from it was found on the actual cert exam.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>What am I going to do next?</strong> This was my quick intro to 0x00sec, I hope to post more soon. If you’re interested in DBA or anything like that, I’ll happily share my knowledge and create SQL tutorials, SQL injections, and something that Null-byte didn’t have – the administration of databases.</p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/mta-database-certification/71">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/mta-database-certification/71</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 02:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-topic-71</guid>
          <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/mta-database-certification/71.rss">MTA Database Certification</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
