<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Service Announcement: Download links</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/public-service-announcement-download-links/5150</link>
    <description># Don&#39;t Download From Untrusted Links!

_If it&#39;s not from the people who wrote it, it&#39;s untrusted._

I know this sounds like super basic stuff but we&#39;ve had to delete/unlist a few posts recently where people (I&#39;m talking about you, @the_heat_man) are posting sketchy links to download tools instead of pointing people to official channels.

Please, please, please do not use these. Do not trust these links. Download only from official sources.

That is all. Carry on.

### Addendum
Because *SOMEBODY* thinks I&#39;m implying something that I&#39;m not: we are not telling you to get your warez from official vendors for said product. We are telling you that you shouldn&#39;t be downloading warez from this or any infosec forum. Not only is it illegal (I&#39;m required to remind you of that, do with it what you will) but you&#39;ll be hard-pressed to find a &quot;clean&quot; keygen or crack that doesn&#39;t have something else slipped in with it. 

If you wouldn&#39;t take drugs from a rando at a party, you shouldn&#39;t download warez from forums like this either.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 02:42:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Site Feedback</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/public-service-announcement-download-links/5150.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Public Service Announcement: Download links</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[fraq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/public-service-announcement-download-links/5150/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/public-service-announcement-download-links/5150/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 02:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-5150-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/public-service-announcement-download-links/5150.rss">Public Service Announcement: Download links</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Public Service Announcement: Download links</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[fraq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Don’t Download From Untrusted Links!</h1>
<p><em>If it’s not from the people who wrote it, it’s untrusted.</em></p>
<p>I know this sounds like super basic stuff but we’ve had to delete/unlist a few posts recently where people (I’m talking about you, <a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/the_heat_man">@the_heat_man</a>) are posting sketchy links to download tools instead of pointing people to official channels.</p>
<p>Please, please, please do not use these. Do not trust these links. Download only from official sources.</p>
<p>That is all. Carry on.</p>
<h3>Addendum</h3>
<p>Because <em>SOMEBODY</em> thinks I’m implying something that I’m not: we are not telling you to get your warez from official vendors for said product. We are telling you that you shouldn’t be downloading warez from this or any infosec forum. Not only is it illegal (I’m required to remind you of that, do with it what you will) but you’ll be hard-pressed to find a “clean” keygen or crack that doesn’t have something else slipped in with it.</p>
<p>If you wouldn’t take drugs from a rando at a party, you shouldn’t download warez from forums like this either.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/public-service-announcement-download-links/5150/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/public-service-announcement-download-links/5150/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 02:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-5150-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/public-service-announcement-download-links/5150.rss">Public Service Announcement: Download links</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
