<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Greetings to all</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620</link>
    <description>Good afternon,
I **learned** today that this is a place where the tutorials (so _I deduce even the opinion_) are censored. It happens some hours ago with my post &quot;Reverse shell over ICMP (with a disassebler digression and a final mistery)&quot; that @_py has unlisted without a motivation. I have spent time in other forum in my life and this is the first time that I see something like that. Generally if you write something stupid or unfitting you are exposed to the &quot;public shame&quot;. Here there is a different policy, a policy that I don&#39;t think has nothing to share with the hacker culture, then with me. I hope the things will change, in the meanwhile I will find another place to write my stupid and unfitting tutorial. It&#39;s really a pity because here I read a lot of interesting stuff and I believe there is a lot of skilled guys, but I can&#39;t stand this behavior from the people that run this site.
I wish you a good day.
Zinzloun</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 15:33:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Uncategorized</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Greetings to all</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 18:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-1620-4</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620.rss">Greetings to all</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Greetings to all</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[zinzloun]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I really don’t undestand what are you talking about, maybe I miss something, forgive me but english is not my native tongue. Anyway nothing personal, keep it as you prefer. Have a nice day.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 15:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-1620-3</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620.rss">Greetings to all</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Greetings to all</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[_py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Right. Since you don’t get it and you want an explanation in public, I’ll give it to you. I wanted to keep it low-key but you asked for it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 15:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-1620-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620.rss">Greetings to all</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Greetings to all</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[zinzloun]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Good afternon,<br>
I <strong>learned</strong> today that this is a place where the tutorials (so <em>I deduce even the opinion</em>) are censored. It happens some hours ago with my post “Reverse shell over ICMP (with a disassebler digression and a final mistery)” that <a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/_py">@_py</a> has unlisted without a motivation. I have spent time in other forum in my life and this is the first time that I see something like that. Generally if you write something stupid or unfitting you are exposed to the “public shame”. Here there is a different policy, a policy that I don’t think has nothing to share with the hacker culture, then with me. I hope the things will change, in the meanwhile I will find another place to write my stupid and unfitting tutorial. It’s really a pity because here I read a lot of interesting stuff and I believe there is a lot of skilled guys, but I can’t stand this behavior from the people that run this site.<br>
I wish you a good day.<br>
Zinzloun</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 15:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-1620-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/greetings-to-all/1620.rss">Greetings to all</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
