<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529</link>
    <description>#macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address#

This is going to be a really quick and simple tutorial. I&#39;ve decided to post this because a while ago, I was having trouble using this program, so this is for anyone who&#39;s having trouble using it right now.

The MAC Address (Media Access Control Address) is a unique identifier which identifies your computer in a network. There are numerous reasons why you would want to change/spoof you MAC Address. Just to name a few:

* Privacy: This hides your machine&#39;s manufacturer (i.e Asustek; Acer; etc...), which can appear when someone scans your network;

* Bypass MAC Address filtering (Some networks limit acess based on MAC Addresses);

* Allows you to &quot;evade&quot; Forensics (It&#39;ll be more difficult to track you);

For this tutorial, I&#39;ll be using `macchanger` (This is a command line tool). If you&#39;re more comfortable using a GUI tool, you can try `macchanger-gtk`.

You can install either one by typing:

`sudo apt-get install macchanger` or `sudo apt-get install macchanger-gtk` , respectively.

Now we need to take down our network adapter in order to successfuly change our MAC Address, so once you finish the installation, write in the terminal (This step is vital, if you fail to do so, you won&#39;t be able to change the MAC Address):

`sudo ifconfig &lt;network_interface&gt; down`

And to change the MAC Address type:

`macchanger -r &lt;network_interface&gt;`  The -r flag generates a random MAC Address. There are other flags that allow you to choose a MAC ADdress of your liking.

All we have to do now is bring our network adapter back up...

`sudo ifconfig &lt;network_interface&gt; up`

If you want to texplore the other options the program has to offer, simply type macchanger --help to see all flags and options available.

We reached the end of the tutorial. Hope you enjoyed reading it, and as always, feel free to comment below!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 09:02:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Networking</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/28</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-28</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ivlb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>IMHO, you can’t have two same MACs or IPs on the network, because you would get all types of switching problems (MACs) or collisions (IPs).</p>
<p>But, what you could do (only in case of wifi) is to deauth the victim and take it’s place on the network. Then the victim gets all the errors and connectivity problems, but if it’s ‘just a user’, they will ‘just think the net sucks’.<br>
In this case, IP assignment is irrelevant, because the network most probably uses dynamic addressing, so the client addresses change relatively regularly.</p>
<p>In the case that network access is not controlled by some form of MAC filtering, but by a Captive Portal (usn/psw), you can hijack a login cookie and use it to register on the network. Catch here is cookie validation in the CaptivePortal, but in a lot of cases you’ll see a cheap implementation of CP, or a CP which runs on defaults.<br>
On the same line of thought, you could also sniff for credentials.</p>
<p>And in the thread there were mentions of other auth systems used in wifi implementations - if the network is using a directory based SSO solution (AD+RADIUS (Kerberos), SAMBA+Kerberos), you’ll have to obtain the creds from inside the network.</p>
<p>Those were my 2 cents, feedback welcome…</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 09:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-27</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cx2H]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>You guys are funny. Thanks<br>
<img src="//0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/1X/bfaa65eae533b431712adf2d5b24e15c58df5d24.jpg" width="300" height="188"></p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 22:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-26</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[zSec]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/oaktree">@oaktree</a><br>
To answer you questions from my experiences I made:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>No, you don’t get the same IP adress, a normal router would recognize this and throw a duplicated IP error. Furthermore you will get strange symptoms when two systems on the same subnet have the same IP address, cause the packets are not forwarded correctly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What I noticed when I spoofed a MAC address was, that it will deauthenticate the other user who was connected at the first place, maybe because their hotspot router thought "oh the client with this known MAC address updated with a new IP (maybe it has something to do with the TTL as well?). When the other actual user will now connect again, I got deauthenticated.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This might be not for every hotspot / router but it is what I experienced.<br>
If I have the time I’m going to try this on my own network and then I’m going to do a tcpdump with Wireshark. Then it should be more clear what is happening.<br>
But again, some routers may behave different.</p>
<p>That’s just what I experienced. I may be totally wrong though. If somebody knows more, please let me know.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 20:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-25</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[_py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There is no way  2 machines will be working properly if both of them are online and they are using the same MAC address. It just doesn’t make any sense. The attack I’ve accomplished at least is by hijacking the ARP cache and when the target machine is offline, then use its MAC address. Check out the command <code>arp -a</code>. This attack is also known as ARP Poisoning.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 20:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-24</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[oaktree]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>My deal is this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Two computers are both online on the same network.</li>
<li>One computer is the rightful owner of some MAC address. This computer was connected to the network first.</li>
<li>Then I come along and change my MAC address to be the same as the other computer’s.</li>
</ul>
<p>My questions:</p>
<ol>
<li>Do I get the same IP as the other guy if I do this, since the MAC is the same?</li>
<li>How do I know if the packets are routed to the right machine?</li>
</ol>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 20:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-23</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[_py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/pry0cc">@pry0cc</a> I’m not saying it’s impossible but you are not that descriptive with how exactly you do it. Using a tool without knowing what’s going on under the hood is a bit skiddy. Keep in mind MAC addresses are one of a kind (in 99% of the cases). In serious networks, MAC spoofing is nearly impossible.</p>
<aside class="onebox wikipedia">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_802.1X" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">en.wikipedia.org</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/b/b44cb7ef0bdceaf8038188f83692334a33d07354.png" class="thumbnail" width="" height="">

<h3><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_802.1X" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">IEEE 802.1X</a></h3>

<p>IEEE 802.1X is an IEEE Standard for port-based Network Access Control (PNAC). It is part of the IEEE 802.1 group of networking protocols.  It provides an authentication mechanism to devices wishing to attach to a LAN or WLAN.
 IEEE 802.1X defines the encapsulation of the Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP) over IEEE 802, which is known as "EAP over LAN" or EAPOL. EAPOL was originally designed for IEEE 802.3 Ethernet in 802.1X-2001, but was clarified to suit other IEEE 802 LAN technologies su...</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 19:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-22</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[indubitably]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Sorry, been doing a lot of studying as of late and was a little tired in the early hours last night, let me further explain the setup.  In said community, theres a wifi hotspot, well from what i can see a bunch of them, it starts as an open network, that proxies you to a login page.  If you are not a member, you can sign up for short free trial, which as far as i can tell is only filtered by mac address, so ive been doing that.  From what I’ve been able to tell, when you are an actual customer, you get a modem, which i believe to be a cisco one, and then it looks to create their own personal wifi and essid but from what I can tell , ( bare with me as im learning xD) its still piggy backing on the same connection the opn connections are coming from.</p>
<p>Im going to do more dabbling today, but a point in the right direction would be awesome <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Last night after reading, i used airodump-ng and looked for these personal hotspots with devices on them, spoofed a devices mac and seen what happened, which wasnt much of course cause i still needed the routers WPA2 passphrase.</p>
<p>Another thing ive noticed is that the airodump scan returns results like such:</p>
<p>companywifi —   this is the open wifi<br>
eddieswifi –   this is wpa2<br>
randomwifi — this is wpa2</p>
<p>the odd thing is that these little clusters all carry the SAME mac addresses except for maybe 1 or 2 varying numbers/letters.  Im sure these are all connected because of their signal power.</p>
<p>I’ve done a few amount of reaver attacks on the wps enabled ones to no avail, as well as bully.</p>
<p>And unfortunately have not cracked the wpa2 yet,</p>
<p>Sorry for the long post but this setup is intriguing the hell out of me xD.</p>
<p>Oh, also, from what i can see the base router/s that is pumping out the hotspots are WEP based, but due to the size of this company, did not wanna dabble with that just quite yet.</p>
<p>Thanks,<br>
doobs</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 19:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-21</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I think you may have misunderstood the concept. You can simply spoof your Mac address, I’ve done it before. I don’t know what exactly happens under the hood, but it works.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 19:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-20</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hmm. Well it still works? Surely the switch/router has no way of determining between each device? I’m guessing that they continue working, or something sketchy happens with ARP.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 19:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-19</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[_py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m in a rush at the moment but <a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/oaktree">@oaktree</a> tagged me so I will try to give some insight from what I know at least(not much). I haven’t read the whole convo but it seems like <a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/oaktree">@oaktree</a> is confused on how 2 machines can have the same MAC address. <a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/pry0cc">@pry0cc</a> I don’t know how this MAC spoofing technique works exactly but theoritically speaking you can’t just hijack a MAC address of a machine that is connected to that so called “purchased” hotspot and surf the web. Most routers nowadays are Layer 3 switches. Meaning, they learn MAC addresses as well, they don’t route traffic only. After they learn  the MAC address there is this so called address cache, where the MAC is being saved for a certain time. The only possible and logical manoeuvre to me seems like to hijack the cache/CAM table where the MAC addresses are stored and then use that MAC address when the machine you wan’t to spoof from is offline. If it’s online, there will be issues. Moreover <a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/oaktree">@oaktree</a>, your IP is dynamic in most cases. Meaning, it changes once in a while and there is no mapping between MAC and IP when you boot up your machine. I hope I didn’t misunderstand the issue. If anyone has more to add, please do.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/18</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 19:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-18</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[oaktree]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>My point is: If you have the same MAC, then the router/DHCP will give you the same IP as the machine off of which you are spoofing. Right? I mean, a TCP stream would be alright if the connection is constant, but if you’re just shooting UDP’s then what happens?</p>
<p><span class="mention">@airth</span>: care to chime in?</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/17</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 18:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-17</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Perhaps. But your machine wouldn’t acknowledge their traffic and vice versa since it isn’t waiting for it, it hasn’t opened a TCP connection. Perhaps UDP?</p>
<p><span class="mention">@unh0lys0da</span> knows more about low level networking than me.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/16</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 18:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-16</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[oaktree]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Well, is there not packet splicing taking place since identical MACs would confuse the router/switch/whatever ?</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/15</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 18:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-15</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[n3xUs]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/cx2h">@Cx2H</a>, to answer your questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Regarding the -r flag, the reason I chose that flag was because I was thinking about if someone were to scan to scan your network and see your manufacturer (let’s say it’s Toshiba), they could use an exploit that’s it’s well know for Toshiba machines, so by hiding the original manufacturer (Usually it’s lested as “Unkown Vendor”), you are a little bit more protected.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Regarding the other subjects, even though it happened to me, I didn’t notice it. I’ll definetily look into and see what I can find. If I do find anything relevant, I’ll post it here (sorry for not giving any solution right now).</p>
</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/14</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 17:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-14</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Absolutely. But we don’t care, cause we do what we want. XD</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/13</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 16:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-13</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>That would be for WPA2 secured networks. We are talking about hotspots which are already open, but require auth via login through a web-gui. Generally these kind of networks charge.</p>
<p>This means you can join the network (since it is open), do an IP scan (if client isolation isn’t set), and just try and get lucky spoofing the Mac addresses. Generally these systems only use Mac addresses as a filter, but some more advanced systems use fingerprinting via canvas, however this can be tempermental and is generally not widely used.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/12</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 16:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-12</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[oaktree]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There’re a few things:</p>
<p>You can use <code>netdiscover</code>, <code>arp-scan</code>, or <code>nmap</code> to seek out another MAC. Finding out which MACs are able to access the internet can be simple brute force. If anything, you could write a program to parse the <code>netdiscover</code> result and then apply changes until you can get, let’s say, an HTTP 200 from <a href="http://google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://google.com/</a>.</p>
<p>In the same program, you can utilize <code>macchanger</code> or even just <code>sudo ifconfig &lt;interface&gt; hwaddr xx:xx:xx:xx:xx:xx</code>.</p>
<p>So, this’ll work for things like Airport WiFi; however, there’s one downside: the person who rightfully owns that MAC could be disrupted because of ARP and IP, right?</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/11</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 16:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-11</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[zSec]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yep, that’s a pretty good way to get free WiFi. Did that some times too, works like a charm.<br>
Most of these Wifi’s you can connect to at first (because there is no password for the WiFi itself). But afterwards you are prompted in a browser to enter the credentials to access the internet.<br>
So you can easily do an nmap scan, look which clients are connected and take one of their MAC address.</p>
<p>Another way to use these Wifi’s without changing the MAC would be something like dns2tcp. That should work as well. Sadly I don’t have experience with dns2tcp yet…</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/10</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 16:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-10</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[oaktree]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’d add that this only works if the MAC address is the only factor used in determining network privileges.</p>
<p>Some networks will have a specific WiFi password mapped to each whitelisted MAC address. Whether it is random or some hash, I have not yet figured out.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 16:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-9</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If you can find a device that uses premium on the network, then you can do it. It seems that Mac spoofing already works on the network, so you could try doing a network scan and finding it, and then spoofing the Mac.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/8</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 14:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-8</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cx2H]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>It’s OK but thanks again.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 11:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-7</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[n3xUs]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey <a class="mention" href="https://0x00sec.org/u/cx2h">@Cx2H</a> , just to let you know that I’m a little busy atm but I will try to answer your questions later today!</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 11:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-6</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[indubitably]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi pry0cc, glad to be part of the new community.  Quick question, does what your mentioning work by just spoofing a mac using the hotspot already?  For example, if a hotspot provides internet access that requires login and pw, would that be needed? Ive been maintaining access by spoofing my mac and using the hotspots free trial time, but it is getting old having to do this over and over again.  Your method really interests me as a solution to this.  Thanks</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/5</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 09:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-5</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pry0cc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I use NM but have no problem. I did have an issue where it would be overridden, but the solution is to disconnect to the network before putting your network device down. And then allow it to automatically reconnect.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 08:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-529-4</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/macchanger-spoofing-your-mac-address/529.rss">Macchanger - Spoofing your MAC Address</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
