<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools I should use when hacking?</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367</link>
    <description>   Hello,  I really enjoy computers I&#39;ve been learning quite a lot of python but i read a lot of stories about how these people like unlocked doors and etc and another one where some guy ran a windows vuln on his network had to restart everything i have a Chromebook and Kali installed i really want to learn more about pen testing  i really enjoy it! any tools i should use when pen testing Im so confused i&#39;m jumbled up here and there, everywhere</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 13:10:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Tools I should use when hacking?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 13:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-14367-4</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367.rss">Tools I should use when hacking?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tools I should use when hacking?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[c0wm1lk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If you want to get an idea of how hacking works and understand the tools that you use then you should check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UClcE-kVhqyiHCcjYwcpfj9w" rel="nofollow noopener">LiveOverflow</a> on YouTube, especially his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iyAyN3GFM7A&amp;list=PLhixgUqwRTjxglIswKp9mpkfPNfHkzyeN" rel="nofollow noopener">Binary Exploitation</a> playlist.</p>
<p>However if you don’t care about it and are just exploring the possibilities of using Kali’s toolset, then you can check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCa6eh7gCkpPo5XXUDfygQQA" rel="nofollow noopener">IppSec</a> on YouTube who uses Kali’s tools to hack into virtual machines (boxes) set up to be hacked.</p>
<p>You can also learn more about Kali itself by reading the <a href="https://www.kali.org/download-kali-linux-revealed-book/" rel="nofollow noopener">Kali Revealed</a> book.</p>
<p>However, while it’s fun to explore hacking and all the things you can do with these amazing tools, you should definitely learn how these things work to get a real grip on hacking and then you can also develop your own tools. If you start hacking people illegally without understanding how their tools work then you turn into a script kiddie. And since script kiddies don’t know how the tools they use work, they don’t know how to get rid of their tracks.</p>
<p>I’m giving you this warning so you don’t go into illegal hacking without first understanding your tools first. And I hope that once you understand them, you get to respect them and never turn to black hat hacking.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 13:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-14367-3</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367.rss">Tools I should use when hacking?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tools I should use when hacking?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[cuckkoo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>you might wanna consider know what pentesting is and get to the basics of it first!!<br>
tools work only as good as the user.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 19:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-14367-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367.rss">Tools I should use when hacking?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tools I should use when hacking?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Idubbz_I_m_fake]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello,  I really enjoy computers I’ve been learning quite a lot of python but i read a lot of stories about how these people like unlocked doors and etc and another one where some guy ran a windows vuln on his network had to restart everything i have a Chromebook and Kali installed i really want to learn more about pen testing  i really enjoy it! any tools i should use when pen testing Im so confused i’m jumbled up here and there, everywhere</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 08:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-14367-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/tools-i-should-use-when-hacking/14367.rss">Tools I should use when hacking?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
