<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>DevSecOps in robotics, the intersection of quality and security</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/devsecops-in-robotics-the-intersection-of-quality-and-security/20046</link>
    <description>A bit theoretical but here&#39;s an attempt to get some of your inputs on the devsecops cycle (particularized for robotics):

We&#39;ve recently been touching into *how to add security to the development and operations cycle of roboticists* (DevSecOps). The main objective of our work is to answer the following question:  &lt;ins&gt;how do we integrate both security and quality in the robotics development cycle?&lt;/ins&gt;

We launched a [blog post](https://news.aliasrobotics.com/secdevops/) summarizing our work so far. The technical report is also available [here](https://arxiv.org/pdf/2003.10402.pdf). Briefly, this first release provides a discussion (from a theoretical perspective, future efforts will extend it) on the current state, depicts a flow for secure development in robotics and puts together a series of recommendations and common practices from literature.

![devsecops_diagram(2)|353x500](upload://wA3rID8cgf0Zv27iacHkd5bLyIZ.png) 

To fully implement this DevSecOps cycle, while developing, we are currently collecting input and evaluating different tools (some of which we pointed out a while ago [here](https://github.com/ros-infrastructure/rep/pull/218#discussion_r370583550)). We&#39;d appreciate community input in the following aspects:

- What&#39;s your view on the intersection of quality and security? (see section 3 of [our technical report](https://arxiv.org/pdf/2003.10402.pdf) for more background on our view, disagreements specially encouraged)
- Which tools do you use (or would you) for static analysis? and for dynamic analysis?
- Which tools and practices do you employ to manage flaws and priorize them?
- Which monitoring tools do you use in your robotic applications? and which ones for analysis of data?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:08:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hardware</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/devsecops-in-robotics-the-intersection-of-quality-and-security/20046.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>DevSecOps in robotics, the intersection of quality and security</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 121 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/devsecops-in-robotics-the-intersection-of-quality-and-security/20046/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/devsecops-in-robotics-the-intersection-of-quality-and-security/20046/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 04:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-20046-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/devsecops-in-robotics-the-intersection-of-quality-and-security/20046.rss">DevSecOps in robotics, the intersection of quality and security</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>DevSecOps in robotics, the intersection of quality and security</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[alias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A bit theoretical but here’s an attempt to get some of your inputs on the devsecops cycle (particularized for robotics):</p>
<p>We’ve recently been touching into <em>how to add security to the development and operations cycle of roboticists</em> (DevSecOps). The main objective of our work is to answer the following question:  <ins>how do we integrate both security and quality in the robotics development cycle?</ins></p>
<p>We launched a <a href="https://news.aliasrobotics.com/secdevops/" rel="nofollow noopener">blog post</a> summarizing our work so far. The technical report is also available <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2003.10402.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>. Briefly, this first release provides a discussion (from a theoretical perspective, future efforts will extend it) on the current state, depicts a flow for secure development in robotics and puts together a series of recommendations and common practices from literature.</p>
<p><span alt="devsecops_diagram(2)" data-base62-sha1="wA3rID8cgf0Zv27iacHkd5bLyIZ" class="broken-image" title="This image is broken"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-unlink svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#unlink"></use></svg></span></p>
<p>To fully implement this DevSecOps cycle, while developing, we are currently collecting input and evaluating different tools (some of which we pointed out a while ago <a href="https://github.com/ros-infrastructure/rep/pull/218#discussion_r370583550" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>). We’d appreciate community input in the following aspects:</p>
<ul>
<li>What’s your view on the intersection of quality and security? (see section 3 of <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2003.10402.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">our technical report</a> for more background on our view, disagreements specially encouraged)</li>
<li>Which tools do you use (or would you) for static analysis? and for dynamic analysis?</li>
<li>Which tools and practices do you employ to manage flaws and priorize them?</li>
<li>Which monitoring tools do you use in your robotic applications? and which ones for analysis of data?</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/devsecops-in-robotics-the-intersection-of-quality-and-security/20046/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/devsecops-in-robotics-the-intersection-of-quality-and-security/20046/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-20046-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/devsecops-in-robotics-the-intersection-of-quality-and-security/20046.rss">DevSecOps in robotics, the intersection of quality and security</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
