<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Best RAT for Linux?</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978</link>
    <description>Windows has Quasar, a high quality open source RAT. Is there anything that good freely available for Linux?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 23:13:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Best RAT for Linux?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 23:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-25978-4</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978.rss">Best RAT for Linux?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best RAT for Linux?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[seisvelas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Wow, thanks for the thorough response!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>things like these are well known and can be removed or Easily detected if actually tried in a serious situation</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Detected by what? In my experience, few Linux desktop users run clam or sophos or anything like that.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 23:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-25978-3</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978.rss">Best RAT for Linux?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best RAT for Linux?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Satoshin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I am assuming you are talking about Malware that can affect Linux system so excuse me if i get this reply out of topic, Linux doesn’t have That many viruses, If you want Good Linux malware that is more sufficient to your own standards and is effective today then you will have to buy it from a source or just create a simple BASH based malware and build off of there. But if you want malware for Linux That dumb people or just people that are plain idiots will not notice here are a few That are very useful and are open source:<br>
(Keep in mind that rootkits are very common on Linux, and there are a few that can’t be detected. So Rootkits are more a Linux thing than RATS)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Arbitrium (Very Powerful And fully Undetectable RAT That can Have access to Linux, Windows, Android)<br>
<a href="https://github.com/BenChaliah/Arbitrium-RAT" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub - BenChaliah/Arbitrium-RAT: Arbitrium is a cross-platform, fully undetectable remote access trojan, to control Android, Windows and Linux and doesn't require any firewall exceptions or port forwarding rules</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Stitch (Cross-platform RAT You can build custom payloads for windows, Mac OS X and Linux too )<br>
<a href="https://github.com/nathanlopez/Stitch" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub - nathanlopez/Stitch: Python Remote Administration Tool (RAT)</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Pupy (Very common RAT and its cross platform between Linux, windows and mac)<br>
<a href="https://github.com/n1nj4sec/pupy" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub - n1nj4sec/pupy: Pupy is an opensource, cross-platform (Windows, Linux, OSX, Android) remote administration and post-exploitation tool mainly written in python</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reptile (Linux Based Rootkit That Can grant you the whole system )<br>
<a href="https://github.com/f0rb1dd3n/Reptile" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub - f0rb1dd3n/Reptile: LKM Linux rootkit</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>N00bRat (Open source RAT toolkit for Posix/Linux This is your basic rat if you just wanna get a Nice taste and not be taken over by abunch of extra stuff.)<br>
<a href="https://github.com/abhishekkr/n00bRAT" class="inline-onebox" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">GitHub - abhishekkr/n00bRAT: Remote Administration Toolkit (or Trojan) for POSiX (Linux/Unix) system working as a Web Service</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>These are your best bet. The reason why i said to write your own RAT if you have experience or know Programming is because, things like these are well known and can be removed or Easily detected if actually tried in a serious situation and it wouldn’t be that hard to notice either since these tools do give out different requests from all shapes and sizes. Just monitor your network and check for outbound request then try and find the source of recently changed files. hense why linux viruses are not really useful in a serious situation, at the end of the day its all just fun.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 09:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-25978-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978.rss">Best RAT for Linux?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best RAT for Linux?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[seisvelas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Windows has Quasar, a high quality open source RAT. Is there anything that good freely available for Linux?</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 06:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-25978-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/best-rat-for-linux/25978.rss">Best RAT for Linux?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
