<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Post Coherency and Adherence to Good English</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english/503</link>
    <description># Post Coherency and Adherence to Good English

Hey, everyone! I thought I&#39;d take just a little time to talk about how posts should be written.

----
#Formatting

Formatting should follow something like posts by @dtm or me (@oaktree).

* [Example 1 by dtm](https://0x00sec.org/t/pe-file-infection/401) 
* [Example 2 by me](https://0x00sec.org/t/graph-algorithms-part-1-0-dijkstras-shortest-path-concept/419)

I would advise that you learn some basic Markdown syntax before posting. Alternatively, the editor comes with some clickables that&#39;ll drop in the formatting for you. (See the __B__ and _I_ buttons?)

----

# Grammar

Not everyone has perfect grammar, and that&#39;s alright. However, all contributors should keep in mind that part of making a thorough, readable, and understandable post is maintaining good grammar practices and using English properly.

I&#39;m not saying that you should _never_ end a sentence with a preposition on here, but make your writing understandable.

----

# Word Choice

Another part of writing good posts is word choice. You shouldn&#39;t be too repetitive or redundant. Avoid recursive definitions when trying to describe something. An example of a recursive definition is:

&gt; Suing is when you sue somebody.

Also, posters should avoid repeating words too often:

&gt; Now that we have done this, now we will do this.

Did you notice the repetitions of &quot;now&quot; and &quot;this&quot;?

&gt; Now that we have done this, let&#39;s do something else.

Oh, wow! That&#39;s so much better. All you really have to do is think a little bit longer before you type.

----

# Proof-Reading

___Always read over what you&#39;ve written.___

Things to look for include:

* __Spelling, Grammar, Capitalization, and Punctuation__
* __Language Semantics__: Does what you wrote convey the meaning you intended?
* __Formatting__: Can a reader follow this? Are my paragraphs too long? Make sure you split things up into paragraphs. For procedures, use ordered lists.
* __Spelling, Grammar, Capitalization, and Punctuation__: Yes, I put this one twice. It&#39;s important! Even if you&#39;re not a native English speaker, you have access to spellcheck and [Google](https://google.com/)!

----
# Conclusion

This post was just a little advice relating to _how_ articles should be written. If you&#39;ve noticed, I may have edited a post of yours and cited &quot;spelling, grammar, and formatting&quot; as the reason. I usually will not do this, but if I feel like the post is just below &quot;understandable,&quot; I&#39;ll make a few changes to it.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 21:51:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>0x00sec Announcements</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english/503.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Post Coherency and Adherence to Good English</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[oaktree]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english/503/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english/503/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 21:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-503-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english/503.rss">Post Coherency and Adherence to Good English</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Post Coherency and Adherence to Good English</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[oaktree]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <h1><a name="p-2412-post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english-1" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-2412-post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english-1"></a>Post Coherency and Adherence to Good English</h1>
<p>Hey, everyone! I thought I’d take just a little time to talk about how posts should be written.</p>
<hr>
<p><a class="hashtag-cooked" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/tag/formatting" data-type="tag" data-slug="formatting" data-id="123" data-style-type="icon" data-icon="tag"><span class="hashtag-icon-placeholder"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-square-full svg-icon svg-node"><use href="#square-full"></use></svg></span><span>formatting</span></a></p>
<p>Formatting should follow something like posts by <a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/dtm">@dtm</a> or me (<a class="mention" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/u/oaktree">@oaktree</a>).</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/pe-file-infection/401" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Example 1 by dtm</a></li>
<li><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/graph-algorithms-part-1-0-dijkstras-shortest-path-concept/419" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Example 2 by me</a></li>
</ul>
<p>I would advise that you learn some basic Markdown syntax before posting. Alternatively, the editor comes with some clickables that’ll drop in the formatting for you. (See the <strong>B</strong> and <em>I</em> buttons?)</p>
<hr>
<h1><a name="p-2412-grammar-2" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-2412-grammar-2"></a>Grammar</h1>
<p>Not everyone has perfect grammar, and that’s alright. However, all contributors should keep in mind that part of making a thorough, readable, and understandable post is maintaining good grammar practices and using English properly.</p>
<p>I’m not saying that you should <em>never</em> end a sentence with a preposition on here, but make your writing understandable.</p>
<hr>
<h1><a name="p-2412-word-choice-3" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-2412-word-choice-3"></a>Word Choice</h1>
<p>Another part of writing good posts is word choice. You shouldn’t be too repetitive or redundant. Avoid recursive definitions when trying to describe something. An example of a recursive definition is:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Suing is when you sue somebody.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Also, posters should avoid repeating words too often:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Now that we have done this, now we will do this.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Did you notice the repetitions of “now” and “this”?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Now that we have done this, let’s do something else.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Oh, wow! That’s so much better. All you really have to do is think a little bit longer before you type.</p>
<hr>
<h1><a name="p-2412-proof-reading-4" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-2412-proof-reading-4"></a>Proof-Reading</h1>
<p><em><strong>Always read over what you’ve written.</strong></em></p>
<p>Things to look for include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Spelling, Grammar, Capitalization, and Punctuation</strong></li>
<li><strong>Language Semantics</strong>: Does what you wrote convey the meaning you intended?</li>
<li><strong>Formatting</strong>: Can a reader follow this? Are my paragraphs too long? Make sure you split things up into paragraphs. For procedures, use ordered lists.</li>
<li><strong>Spelling, Grammar, Capitalization, and Punctuation</strong>: Yes, I put this one twice. It’s important! Even if you’re not a native English speaker, you have access to spellcheck and <a href="https://google.com/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Google</a>!</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1><a name="p-2412-conclusion-5" class="anchor" href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk#p-2412-conclusion-5"></a>Conclusion</h1>
<p>This post was just a little advice relating to <em>how</em> articles should be written. If you’ve noticed, I may have edited a post of yours and cited “spelling, grammar, and formatting” as the reason. I usually will not do this, but if I feel like the post is just below “understandable,” I’ll make a few changes to it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english/503/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english/503/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 21:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-503-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/post-coherency-and-adherence-to-good-english/503.rss">Post Coherency and Adherence to Good English</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
