<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644</link>
    <description>Hello fellas, this is my first thread where I will show you T50 one powerful tool that can send lot of packets (tested on my own server and hitting fine).

*  First you can download T50 [ here](https://sourceforge.net/projects/t50/).

* If you want to run a stress test, run `t50 (IP) -flood -S(this is protocol)(optional --turbo)` in a terminal. Also, there are many other options you can find if you use the `--help` flag.

* T50 has really good performance. If you want to stress-test severs that are not connected on LAN, you have to port forward.

* The reason why I want to share is because I tried with many other tools but they do not compare with T50.

* Don&#39;t forget to use it only for educational purposes, because there&#39;s a lot of people who are running it just for fun and even _without_ proxychain.

* I forgot to mention something: Many people think `ufonet` is a better choice if you want to have free botnet, but I don&#39;t think this is true. Since it seems to good to be true, I believe it might infect your machine (even if you use a VM), so you probably will become one of those zombies. :)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 09:59:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Networking</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 30 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-644-4</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644.rss">T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[iamfarooqh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for sharing this great piece of information spylegion. Could you please share us some example commands to run DoS scenarios covering the popular protocols like TCP, UDP and ICMP.  For the TCP ports, I would like to specifically flood some well-known ports like 22 and 443.</p>
<p>Also, I would like to understand how t50 could simulate DDoS. Do we have to run t50 in multiple instances of terminal? Or there is any additional setting that I missed to notice?</p>
<p>If you’ve made a video to demonstrate the capabilities of this tool, Please share us the link to benefit from.</p>
<p>Thanks for your help!</p>
<p>Best<br>
Farooq</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 08:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-644-3</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644.rss">T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0x00pf]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for sharing.</p>
<p>I took a quick look to the code and it is surprisingly easy to follow. I suggest to anybody interested on low level networking (packet crafting) to take a look.</p>
<p>I have to say, that it does not look like a DoS and definitely not a DDoS tool. It fills more like a networking diagnosis tool as <code>iperf</code> and as the authors say.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 17:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-644-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644.rss">T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[spylegion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello fellas, this is my first thread where I will show you T50 one powerful tool that can send lot of packets (tested on my own server and hitting fine).</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>First you can download T50 <a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/t50/" rel="nofollow noopener"> here</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you want to run a stress test, run <code>t50 (IP) -flood -S(this is protocol)(optional --turbo)</code> in a terminal. Also, there are many other options you can find if you use the <code>--help</code> flag.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>T50 has really good performance. If you want to stress-test severs that are not connected on LAN, you have to port forward.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The reason why I want to share is because I tried with many other tools but they do not compare with T50.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Don’t forget to use it only for educational purposes, because there’s a lot of people who are running it just for fun and even <em>without</em> proxychain.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I forgot to mention something: Many people think <code>ufonet</code> is a better choice if you want to have free botnet, but I don’t think this is true. Since it seems to good to be true, I believe it might infect your machine (even if you use a VM), so you probably will become one of those zombies. <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 13:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-644-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/t50-ddos-dos-tool/644.rss">T50 Ddos/DoS Tool</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
