<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Keyboard layout</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330</link>
    <description>
Hi everyone,
I&#39;m KlyntarX *I&#39;m not really into telling my real name* I&#39;m 13 years old and I really like learning *You can say I&#39;m a huge nerd* I came to Sweden for studies and I got myself a new keyboard. Back in my country, I had a 135 wpm where the keyboard layout was the regular QWERTY keyboard layout. This question is not related to hacking or penetration testing or anything I just want to ask How can I improve my typing speed if I have to change the layout? Can you guys tell me the most effective way to improve my typing speed to the same level as before? I know there is like 1 million YouTube videos that cover this topic but I don&#39;t really think that&#39;s the most effective way to keep a consistent typing speed.

by KlyntarX</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 16:56:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Beginner Guides</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Computer Keyboard layout</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed after 121 days. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 07:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-37330-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330.rss">Computer Keyboard layout</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Computer Keyboard layout</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[KlyntarX]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone,<br>
I’m KlyntarX <em>I’m not really into telling my real name</em> I’m 13 years old and I really like learning <em>You can say I’m a huge nerd</em> I came to Sweden for studies and I got myself a new keyboard. Back in my country, I had a 135 wpm where the keyboard layout was the regular QWERTY keyboard layout. This question is not related to hacking or penetration testing or anything I just want to ask How can I improve my typing speed if I have to change the layout? Can you guys tell me the most effective way to improve my typing speed to the same level as before? I know there is like 1 million YouTube videos that cover this topic but I don’t really think that’s the most effective way to keep a consistent typing speed.</p>
<p>by KlyntarX</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 15:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-37330-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/computer-keyboard-layout/37330.rss">Computer Keyboard layout</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
