<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>A couple of helpful github links</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/a-couple-of-helpful-github-links/1848</link>
    <description>While perusing through twitter for the latest security news as per usual, I came across two github links that I believe may be helpful to some people.

1.)  [Mimipenguin](https://github.com/huntergregal/mimipenguin):  A tool to dump the login password from the current linux desktop user. Adapted after the idea behind the popular Windows tool mimikatz.

2.) [libfuzzer-workshop](https://github.com/Dor1s/libfuzzer-workshop):  Repository for materials of &quot;Modern fuzzing of C/C++ Projects&quot; workshop.

I&#39;ve not yet had a chance to check out either of these projects in full due to time constraints for a school project, but I figured you guys and gals would like them. If you do try them (or just one of them), please do comment as to what you think about them!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 05:08:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Social</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/a-couple-of-helpful-github-links/1848.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>A couple of helpful github links</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[VVid0w]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>While perusing through twitter for the latest security news as per usual, I came across two github links that I believe may be helpful to some people.</p>
<p>1.)  <a href="https://github.com/huntergregal/mimipenguin" rel="nofollow noopener">Mimipenguin</a>:  A tool to dump the login password from the current linux desktop user. Adapted after the idea behind the popular Windows tool mimikatz.</p>
<p>2.) <a href="https://github.com/Dor1s/libfuzzer-workshop" rel="nofollow noopener">libfuzzer-workshop</a>:  Repository for materials of “Modern fuzzing of C/C++ Projects” workshop.</p>
<p>I’ve not yet had a chance to check out either of these projects in full due to time constraints for a school project, but I figured you guys and gals would like them. If you do try them (or just one of them), please do comment as to what you think about them!</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/a-couple-of-helpful-github-links/1848/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/a-couple-of-helpful-github-links/1848/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 05:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-1848-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/a-couple-of-helpful-github-links/1848.rss">A couple of helpful github links</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
