<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Career Transition</title>
    <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699</link>
    <description>Has anyone here made a transition from a different role in infosec into pentesting or red team work?

I currently do security systems engineering (I help build COTS/FOSS tools/SOC apparatus) and am working towards my OSCP in my limited spare time. I have an interest in giving the offensive side a shot after I can pass the OSCP exam, but I would be going from a relatively lucrative position to a complete know-nothing noob. I&#39;ve learned that I do better when I work with a team of people that I can speak to and bounce questions off of. However, I don&#39;t have any idea how I would get my foot in the door even if I were able to find an entry point without taking too much of a salary cut. It kind of seems that I&#39;m possibly at the point in my career where I&#39;m better off just doing CTFs for fun.

I&#39;d appreciate any guidance you may have in how to approach this.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 15:49:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Career Transition</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 15:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-21699-3</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699.rss">Career Transition</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Career Transition</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0xcrypto]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="LostInTheSowce" data-post="1" data-topic="21699">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/user_avatar/d.clarkee.co.uk/lostinthesowce/48/11940_2.png" class="avatar"> LostInTheSowce:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>currently do security systems engineering (I help build COTS/FOSS tools/SOC apparatus) and am working towards my OSCP in my</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I used to hack around randomly on the internet without knowing what I am doing  when I was a kid. Sooner I found linux, tinkered a lot, installed many distros. But then, I needed money so I hosted two websites and went for an interview for a web developer. Sooner became a backend developer. I was at peak and was expected to work on a project that would have been a micro service. The architecture client had asked for was quite impressive. Completing that project would have given my career a big boost as  its quite a big thing indeed. Now lockdown in my country due to COVID-19 has forced me to leave the job. Now that I have some time, I am thinking about becoming a penetration tester. Right now I am trying to catch up with the industry and possibly do some bug bounty hunting to fill up the blank CV.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 15:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-21699-2</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699.rss">Career Transition</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Career Transition</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[LostInTheSowce]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Has anyone here made a transition from a different role in infosec into pentesting or red team work?</p>
<p>I currently do security systems engineering (I help build COTS/FOSS tools/SOC apparatus) and am working towards my OSCP in my limited spare time. I have an interest in giving the offensive side a shot after I can pass the OSCP exam, but I would be going from a relatively lucrative position to a complete know-nothing noob. I’ve learned that I do better when I work with a team of people that I can speak to and bounce questions off of. However, I don’t have any idea how I would get my foot in the door even if I were able to find an entry point without taking too much of a salary cut. It kind of seems that I’m possibly at the point in my career where I’m better off just doing CTFs for fun.</p>
<p>I’d appreciate any guidance you may have in how to approach this.</p>
          <p><a href="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 12:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">d.clarkee.co.uk-post-21699-1</guid>
        <source url="https://d.clarkee.co.uk/t/career-transition/21699.rss">Career Transition</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
