<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Social - 0x00sec - The Home of the Hacker</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/c/social/46</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Social&#39; category Many users often have infomation related to their work, their activity on 0x00sec, and other things that aren&#39;t strictly computer science/hacking related, however they are somewhat relevant. This category is to be used sparingly, and only if you really have something important/relevant to share.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 20:00:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/c/social/46.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>How to get the Blackarch full version without the tools or make the slim desktop look more like the full one</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[KlyntarX]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So I was wondering, I had the slim version of Blackarch because I felt 2000 tools would be pointless but I also like the full iso look more than the one in the Slim one so is there a way to get the important tools to a version of blackarch with the same look as the full version? or is there a way to turn the slim version look more like the full one so if you don’t get what I mean I just want the important tools in a VM and the desktop should look like the full one<br>
<img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/1/f/1fa3feb15143725c61fc9d46bab911f1882d063d.png" alt="image" data-base62-sha1="4vU9Rhpf0GOf1wykx6bSRc19P7T" width="300" height="168"><br>
<strong>↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓↓</strong><br>
</p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/6/a/6a7df4a3f7ff592fa0b3257c62212ae961a448f2.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/fc4taO8ZHEsIqWUa8zDXwiIvZku.jpeg?dl=1" title="image" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/6/a/6a7df4a3f7ff592fa0b3257c62212ae961a448f2_2_300x168.jpeg" alt="image" data-base62-sha1="fc4taO8ZHEsIqWUa8zDXwiIvZku" width="300" height="168" srcset="https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/6/a/6a7df4a3f7ff592fa0b3257c62212ae961a448f2_2_300x168.jpeg, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/6/a/6a7df4a3f7ff592fa0b3257c62212ae961a448f2_2_450x252.jpeg 1.5x, https://0x00sec.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/6/a/6a7df4a3f7ff592fa0b3257c62212ae961a448f2_2_600x336.jpeg 2x" data-dominant-color="0A0B0F"></a></div><p></p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-get-the-blackarch-full-version-without-the-tools-or-make-the-slim-desktop-look-more-like-the-full-one/37051">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-get-the-blackarch-full-version-without-the-tools-or-make-the-slim-desktop-look-more-like-the-full-one/37051</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 20:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-37051</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-get-the-blackarch-full-version-without-the-tools-or-make-the-slim-desktop-look-more-like-the-full-one/37051.rss">How to get the Blackarch full version without the tools or make the slim desktop look more like the full one</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Question on your need to be known</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[PrAxis]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Do any of you keep your hacking/security activities completely cut off from the other parts of your life?  ie could you be a “hacker” and never tell anyone?</p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/question-on-your-need-to-be-known/34563">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/question-on-your-need-to-be-known/34563</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 17:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-34563</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/question-on-your-need-to-be-known/34563.rss">Question on your need to be known</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Book Thread - What&#39;s-a-reading?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kedislav]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey! I was digging around and found the latest book thread was back in '16, so I took it upon myself to make a new one. I personally am an avid reader and I think sharing interesting reads is important for both motivation and learning.</p>
<p><strong>To keep this organized:</strong><br>
Be sure to tag the books you recommend so we can all benefit from the replies, tags are as follows;</p>
<ul>
<li>
<em>(General)</em> - for works that impart more generalized knowledge, or don’t fall into any one category.</li>
<li>
<em>(Fiction)</em> - for works depicting fictional stories about hacking, programming or related.</li>
<li>
<em>(Real/Doc)</em> - for books about real hacking, cybercrime cases and/or investigations into the hacking world.</li>
<li>
<em>(Philosophy)</em> - for books that delve into the philosophic side of hacking, like ethics and related.</li>
<li>
<em>(Techspeak)</em> - for technical works that are more guides to follow than leisure reading.</li>
<li>
<em>(Paper)</em> - for highly technical academic papers on topics related.</li>
</ul>
<p>Ideally link your books to a place people can get them, even more ideal if you include identifiers in your description (like the ISBN). For papers, extra points if you include a DOI, but any link where we can read it will do (reminder that papers behind paywalls only benefit the publisher, not the author, and actively hurt scientific learning).</p>
<p>If there are tags missing or some categories are weirdly/badly defined, please suggest them to me through DM so I can edit the post and add/edit them.</p>
<hr>
<p>For my recommendations I have a few;</p>
<ul>
<li>
<em>(Fiction)</em> <a href="https://craphound.com/category/attacksurface/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Attack/Surface</a> by Cory Doctorow | ISBN-13 9781250757517</li>
</ul>
<p>It is the third book of a series called “Little Brother”, but I didn’t read the first two and I still found it incredibly interesting, as well as realistic. The book follows Masha as she falls into this dichotomy of both working for the bad guys while helping the good guys evade them. As you could imagine, it is an unsustainable dilemma. One thing I like most is that <a href="https://github.com/pavelanni" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Pavel Anni</a> took the time to write the <a href="https://pavelanni.github.io/attack-surface-tech/attack-surface-tech.html" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Mashapedia (n.a)</a>, a chapter-by-chapter breakdown of the real world technologies depicted in the book, making it a great introduction to the tech we use and the jargon we speak for people looking to start in the world of hacking and IT.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<em>(Real/Doc)</em> <a href="https://thisishowtheytellmetheworldends.com/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">This is How They Tell Me the World Ends: The Cyberweapons Arms Race</a> by Nicole Perlroth | ISBN-13 9781635576054</li>
</ul>
<p>Truly fantastic investigative journalism into the cryptic world of cyberweapons and the 0-day market. It really puts into perspective how much power hackers wield in this highly connected world, and it proposes the problem of the “IoT wave” and how hackers, if said wave is completed, can weaponize it. The book was published before Russia’s aggressive invasion started, and it really helps put the conflict into perspective, as Perlroth dives into how cyber-aggression had escalated years prior. Very interesting book.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<em>(General)</em> <a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/jargon/html/index.html" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">The Jargon File</a> by Eric S. Raymond</li>
</ul>
<p>This is a file more than it is a book, mainly because it has many versions throughout the years. For the uninitiated, the Jargon file is a glossary of slang and terms different programmer and hacking subcultures use. You <em>could find it in book form</em>, but do not be careless; those might be old versions. I do not think of this as necessary reading, more like for-fun reading. It clarifies terminology as well as give insight into what and how hackers have been interacting with each other throughout the years and as technology evolves.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<em>(Philosophy)</em> <a href="https://0x00sec.org">Coding Democracy: How Hackers are Disrupting Power, Surveillance, and Authoritarianism</a> by Maureen Webb | ISBN-13  9780262043557</li>
</ul>
<p>I think the title describes it well enough that my words are a bit unnecessary, but a quick review doesn’t hurt anybody. This book is an in-depth analysis of how hacker culture has allowed democracy to move forward smoothly.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<em>(Techspeak / Philosophy)</em> <a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/writings/taoup/html/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">The Art of Unix Programming</a> by Eric S. Raymond | ISBN-13 9780131429017</li>
</ul>
<p>Maybe you’ll say <em>“Ked, recommending Raymond again?”</em> and I’d respond <em>“Exactly”</em>. The Art of Unix Programming is an great book, as it details the Unix philosophy and its evolution to where it is today, as well as Unix and Unix-based OS’s. It is a great read, very long and arduous, but there is much to gain from reading a book like this. Again, not necessary reading, but good to have under the belt.</p>
<p><strong>Those are my recommendations (for now), Papers and other academic material am still reading so didn’t note them down. Am curious to read what you recommend!</strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Note:</strong> I know there is the awesome lists on github with books for hackers, but I believe there is much to be gained from asking people directly and seeing what they’re reading.</em></p>
            <p><small>9 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/book-thread-whats-a-reading/32146">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/book-thread-whats-a-reading/32146</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 14:21:52 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-32146</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/book-thread-whats-a-reading/32146.rss">Book Thread - What&#39;s-a-reading?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Transformation and obstruction (Looking for the way out)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Positive_Vibes]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If u have read my “funny dumbass story”<br>
Well here’s the deal<br>
I’ve repaired my laptop<br>
Building stuffs, kinda hard I won’t lie, especially mobile apps especially when you’re the only one doing it.<br>
About the hacking group I wanted to open<br>
We’ve done a few hacks, but same old shi gets boring, especially when people you do things with aren’t as dedicated as you are.<br>
I hope to find highly talented people, I guess those better than I am and if I do and I’m sure theirs no country firewall and internet barrier, I’ll reinstall Linux in my pc.<br>
Right now I’m in a situation where I’m not sure if I should move forward or backwards.<br>
I love the previous advices I got on previous post and I hope to get better one here.</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/transformation-and-obstruction-looking-for-the-way-out/31961">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/transformation-and-obstruction-looking-for-the-way-out/31961</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 20:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-31961</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/transformation-and-obstruction-looking-for-the-way-out/31961.rss">Transformation and obstruction (Looking for the way out)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>A funny dumbass story of me 😢</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Positive_Vibes]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>My story is pretty freaky. It all started with the resolve of wanting to do something great. I managed to pop up with a cool idea of creating a competitive online game based on offensive and defensive security, where players build their tools in-game and has a global chat where all players communicate. So I went about the preparations, structured the whole plan and it looked perfect on paper and along my researches I discovered an app builder (cos the game is mostly a widget game) that my laptop could handle, actually it’s not an app builder but a way I could use figma for frontend and airtable for backend and combine it to create a hybrid app, along the way when I was just starting out in designs, my laptop started getting freaky till the extent the screen went blank, I didn’t even wanna think of repairing it cos I know I ain’t gonna get no funds for that from my parents. So I started another research and finally discovered another app builder I could handle with my mobile phone and I could use codemagic to export it to an apk (that’s how I thought it worked) only for me to discover that and I can’t generate apk but directly export to playstore <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/expressionless.png?v=12" title=":expressionless:" class="emoji" alt=":expressionless:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"> and I didn’t wanna think about it cos I don’t even have the freaking fund to obtain the onetime playstore membership and my discovery was late cos I’ve done some designs already and this pained me the most, cos I discovered an investment platform that invests on teenage ideas with $100k so I really wanted this to work but life ain’t a bed of roses <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/sweat_smile.png?v=12" title=":sweat_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":sweat_smile:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"><img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/cry.png?v=12" title=":cry:" class="emoji" alt=":cry:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"> so I let it go, so I decided to build a web CTF platform but my device is just way to limited for this intense task, so right now I just managed to open a group for bounty hunters even tho I’m not with my laptop, I’m willing to give it a shot with my mobile phone using termux. Relying mostly on the only person with PC in our team (we’re just 4 tho) if you wanna join, slot is open. So I think the last adventure is where I’m currently in and sometimes it fews dumb to continue but I don’t know why I still continue. I guess "No room for improvisation in tech and internet</p>
            <p><small>11 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/a-funny-dumbass-story-of-me/31699">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/a-funny-dumbass-story-of-me/31699</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 10:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-31699</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/a-funny-dumbass-story-of-me/31699.rss">A funny dumbass story of me 😢</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Question about my idea for an anonymous setup</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[ralfster]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all -I’m a software dev by trade, advance-beginner hacker.</p>
<p>I spent a lot of time today reading through the Anonymity category here and tested out a few setups today. Bear in mind, what I’m about to ask could very well absolutely stupid no doubt, but I feel like this community could give pretty good insight into why this would be a bad or useless setup implementation:</p>
<p><strong>Host Machine</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Ubuntu or Deb installed on the physical hard drive</li>
<li>LVM Encrypted Hard Drive option during installation</li>
<li>LVM encrypted root and home directory after installation</li>
<li>Connection: VPN (vpn provider <span class="hashtag">#1</span>)</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>VirtualBox installed</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Virtual Machine</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Tails or Whonix linux distro installed on encrypted VirtualBox VDI Disk</li>
<li>LVM Encrypt root and home directory after installation</li>
<li>Connection: TOR → VPN (vpn provider <span class="hashtag">#2</span>)</li>
<li>VirtualBox installed</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Virtual Machine <span class="hashtag">#2</span></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Linux distro of choice running live via the ISO saved on the previous virtual machine or even on a USB</li>
<li>Connection: TOR</li>
</ul>
<p>My thinking was that the host will be running VPN#1, okay now your ISP might not flag you for TOR usage. And assuming you choose a theoretically ‘secure’ company, then VPN#1 wouldn’t care or have logs on tor usage.</p>
<p>So then with the first virtual machine, you’re connect through TOR. And on top of that, let’s say I’d connect to a VPN#2 (another ‘credible’ company). My thoughts was that since there’s many people that run TOR → VPN, surely other people on that ip from VPN#2 were connected to TOR as well, making the web that traces back to you so much more intricate.</p>
<p>Finally - Virtual machine <span class="hashtag">#2</span>. Well since it’s host machine is technically virtual machine <span class="hashtag">#1</span>, then that means machine <span class="hashtag">#2</span> certainly couldn’t have access to any of your main host machine’s physical hardware ID’s. And to put the cherry on top, say I connect to TOR yet again.</p>
<p>Again, I’m willing to get roasted on this if it means I learn a little more, lol.</p>
<p>Thanks in advance!</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/question-about-my-idea-for-an-anonymous-setup/30766">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/question-about-my-idea-for-an-anonymous-setup/30766</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 01:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-30766</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/question-about-my-idea-for-an-anonymous-setup/30766.rss">Question about my idea for an anonymous setup</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Cyberpunk Future</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[sp1der7]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Does anyone here believe that a future cyberpunk world will be possible in maybe a 100 Years or more. I’m referring to the world as being very highly technologically advanced in most or almost every country. Some countries already are at a very high technological stage such as China for example. Let me guys know what you think.</p>
            <p><small>9 posts - 7 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/cyberpunk-future/30127">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/cyberpunk-future/30127</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 21:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-30127</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/cyberpunk-future/30127.rss">Cyberpunk Future</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>My life is being controlled and wasted in this fraud university</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Darkvault]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m   wasting   my  life  in   a  fraud   university.  I can’t   get out  of  it   cause  my  parents  are  idiots  who  love  forceing  their  stuff on  other  people  just  anyone  experienced   with  it  tell  me  how  to  get  out   of  this  situation   I’m   ready  to  do  the  hardwork  whenever  I’ll   get  the  time .</p>
            <p><small>14 posts - 12 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/my-life-is-being-controlled-and-wasted-in-this-fraud-university/27660">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/my-life-is-being-controlled-and-wasted-in-this-fraud-university/27660</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 17:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-27660</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/my-life-is-being-controlled-and-wasted-in-this-fraud-university/27660.rss">My life is being controlled and wasted in this fraud university</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Im stupid, should i quit?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Reisen_1943]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I just want to have some advice.<br>
I spent time on doing reverse malware. I try flare-on too, but cant finish. highest quest i can do is level 10 - flare-on 2020.<br>
Am i a bad reverser, im not smart enough for this stuff ? should i quit ?</p>
            <p><small>19 posts - 12 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/im-stupid-should-i-quit/27205">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/im-stupid-should-i-quit/27205</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 13:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-27205</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/im-stupid-should-i-quit/27205.rss">Im stupid, should i quit?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Why the most skilled people in this field thinks that our world is a simulation?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Darkvault]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Is coding  a proof that our world is a simulation and our God is a coder. I’m  really  curious and this topic is boggling my mind for a long time with 3D bio printers scientist   are  already building living organs. Very strange that alot of  people  are not serious about this question .</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-25421</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/why-the-most-skilled-people-in-this-field-thinks-that-our-world-is-a-simulation/25421.rss">Why the most skilled people in this field thinks that our world is a simulation?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>I want to be a hacker/coder but my parents are against it</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Darkvault]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Theyre  saying they’ll  not waste  a single penny if  that’s  the case  and they’re  saying that  stupid  people do all these nonsense  and they want me to  do something else  but I’m into this and it’s  Okey if no one takes care of me .Any quick way I can make a little living from any skills related to this field anyway  and if you’ve  gone through same situations would love to hear your experience. Sorry for my bad English</p>
            <p><small>37 posts - 14 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/i-want-to-be-a-hacker-coder-but-my-parents-are-against-it/25374">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/i-want-to-be-a-hacker-coder-but-my-parents-are-against-it/25374</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 16:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-25374</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/i-want-to-be-a-hacker-coder-but-my-parents-are-against-it/25374.rss">I want to be a hacker/coder but my parents are against it</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>0x00sec Wallpapers - 4K</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[3vn2odzn]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>&gt; 0x00sec Wallpapers - 4K</strong></p>
<p>Hello, I designed wallpapers in different styles. I also made a vector drawing of the 0x00sec logo and uploaded it to the cloud. You can use <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/smiley.png?v=9" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p>
<p><strong>Link:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://mega.nz/folder/Q6R1kaDJ#jdfhKPR2ubqRMmoQYAr88Q" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://mega.nz/folder/Q6R1kaDJ#jdfhKPR2ubqRMmoQYAr88Q</a></p>
            <p><small>12 posts - 9 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/0x00sec-wallpapers-4k/24878">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/0x00sec-wallpapers-4k/24878</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-24878</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/0x00sec-wallpapers-4k/24878.rss">0x00sec Wallpapers - 4K</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>If you Want to get good at Malware Development</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[digitalXmage]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Inspiration</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This is just for the people which lack passion, and maybe have a skewed view of Malware, And hacking. This has just been my experience, And You have to delve into this stuff <strong>with the right mindset I feel</strong>. I’m no crazy Hacker, Or malware developer, But <strong>I’m learning</strong>. And I have learnt A lot. And Have Learnt A lot about Trojans and ELF binary files(A never ending fun endeavor)</p>
<p>It’s Very simple actually. You need to have the urge to learn more about how a computer works, and really enjoy learning the low information of how a computer works, It will gravitate to you writing low level applications, learning more about the operating system, the Linux API, especially C, and also assembler are both important and provide different ways of learning about computers. And writing Assembly is really great. And then combining the both in writing Both C and embedded/Inline assembler, <strong>It’s Like C is the Knife, And Assembly is the Gun. Combine With Data structures and Algorithm knowledge, I think are all powerful tools. For Creating efficient programs</strong></p>
<p>Assembler is great, It gets rid of all the levels of abstraction of the computer that A lot of languages have(Not bad, But not useful if you want to learn how a computer works), and you WILL learn how a computer works. How memory works, How the CPU works etc. And C is great When you learn the concepts in assembler, Will help your C programming.</p>
<p>Read Books, You can pirate books from this website: <a href="https://www.pdfdrive.com/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">pdfdrive</a></p>
<p>Books are way better than tutorials, because unlike tutorials, Authors are paid lots of money to write these computer textbooks, It’s their job, they’re are gonna make sure they invest the time to research and learn and write that textbook to the best of their ability. And what’s great Even books a decade ago are still useful, Because Low level never really changes and For whatever legacy stuff you learn, Emulators , Virtual machines are great for that.) And The best ones Are written by University professors IMO, But there are many great authors Who are just great programmers and share the knowledge. (Not to Say tutorials are bad, Use, and learn from both).</p>
<p>And also theoretical knowledge and Practical knowledge is important, so it’s good to read up on the theory and apply the theory into practice through projects. For instance I’ve been learning a lot about the ELF Binary in Linux, As well as delving into embedded programming for micro controllers.</p>
<p>This knowledge of the system will help with malware development, and If you already have a strong interest in low level programming, Then you’ll learn a lot, if you’re determined enough to learn.</p>
<p>What I’m saying is you gotta trust the process, You have to enjoy every part a long the way,Each step in the learning you need to <strong>enjoy and write applications that you are proud off</strong>. If you don’t enjoy it, you won’t be good at it. At all.</p>
<p>This has been my current roadmap(journey so far):</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Learn C and Linux API and write fun user space Terminal applications. (Did loads of projects before going to step 2, Still do). Get Better at C, memory management, Getting Good at debugging (GDB)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Learn and read up on Computer Theory, learn  a CPU instruction set(arm assembler), Bytes, bit shifting, how arithmetic work,Logical Operations ,CPU, CPU registers, Memory etc. etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Learn and Read up on computer Malware, And Learn to Read other people’s code and learning from other people’s source code, Learn the theory and Creating projects Using that Learnt Knowledge. <strong>(Incredibly important skill in an Area of learning advanced topics with not much practical resources online)</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Currently Learning embedded micro controller programming, To learn more about computers and writing programs on bare metal(No operating system) etc etc.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This is What I’ve done so far. If it helps people who are unsure about What it takes to learn Hacking , and This stuff to the source code, binary level. And honestly <strong>You gotta enjoy the process more than the outcome</strong>, especially in this Area. Most of the stuff you learn, especially at the beginning, Will be minimal and always be caught by anti virus measures. But you should still be proud when you do something as significant such as embedded a basic payload into an Elf binary and printing some text to the screen.</p>
<p><strong>Enjoy the process More than the Result.</strong> As What Seems insignificant to others, Is A big step for myself, In learning and understanding a new concept, which may of taken months of learning, and Writing a lot of lines of code for some small result.</p>
<p>As well of having a strong interest in Low level programming, Regardless Of hacking and writing Malware.</p>
<p>I just feel A good mindset is important,  and A bit of self reflection, Which has helped me at least.</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 13:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-23466</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/if-you-want-to-get-good-at-malware-development/23466.rss">If you Want to get good at Malware Development</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How to avoid BURNOUT?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[MSqueaks]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi. I’m MSqueaks.</p>
<p>Anyone have advice on avoiding Burnout ?</p>
<p>I am a network engineer tech, I work in a live nocc environment. It’s high stress, face paced and a lot of networking. I took this job as a stepping stone to work my way into infosec and build experience. The nocc has a high turn over rate, my team is increasingly getting smaller and I am the only female on my team in a company full of gatekeepers. I got lucky with this job because I did not have any practical experience. I had just graduated with two AS degrees, one in networking systems architecture and the other in cybersecurity.</p>
<p>I generally work 9-12 hour days, then try to spend my limited free time towards Research &amp; Development but since the beginning of the year I have started to Burnout. It’s not that I lost my drive, motivation or passion. I just can’t do it. At this point, I burnout daily and I am having a hard time staying constant with studying for certifications or R&amp;D in general. Any advice ?</p>
            <p><small>23 posts - 9 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-avoid-burnout/22767">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-avoid-burnout/22767</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 01:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-22767</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/how-to-avoid-burnout/22767.rss">How to avoid BURNOUT?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>+[Nullsec Zine] A call to all users and staff</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Danus]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Hear yee  Hear yee</h1>
<p>After long talk and consideration, the 0x00sec boardroom as decided to roll off a trial attempt to create the first nullsec zine, or nullsec magazine if you will.</p>
<p>Obliviously this means all the active 0x00sec staff would participate in such event but we decided to open the possibility for 0x00sec users to join on the fun.</p>
<h2>Why on earth would I want to do that</h2>
<ol>
<li>This would greatly benefit your career and would allow you to publish and leverage on fame and glory.</li>
<li>This would push your skill to its boundary and yourself outside your comfort zone, thus improving your skill set.</li>
<li>It would greatly benefit the community and the discord server.</li>
</ol>
<h2>What do I need to do to get in?</h2>
<p>If you are active on the discord &amp; forums and have an idea, that you think is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Creative</li>
<li>Applicable for you to research and to write about in the span of 2-3 months</li>
<li>Is not outdated or overdone 300 times by other blog posts on the internet</li>
<li>Requires effort, hard work and would push yourself outside your domain of comfort</li>
</ul>
<p>You can send me a private message on discord or on the forums and your idea will be considered, if it would be accepted you would be invited to the zine channel on discord.</p>
<h2>When is this trial project due?</h2>
<p>Currently we are considering a public release of 2-3 months after the design and project roll out.</p>
<h2>Do I need to bring something with me?</h2>
<ul>
<li>Free time, at least 10 spare hours a week</li>
<li>A good idea</li>
<li>Commitment to your idea, work, craft and community</li>
<li>A dark sense of humor could help</li>
</ul>
<h2>That’s it?</h2>
<p>That is it, good luck.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/nullsec-zine-a-call-to-all-users-and-staff/21534">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/nullsec-zine-a-call-to-all-users-and-staff/21534</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 14:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-21534</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/nullsec-zine-a-call-to-all-users-and-staff/21534.rss">+[Nullsec Zine] A call to all users and staff</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The basics to master the skill of ethical hacking?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[KaIi]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Can anyone show me some good youtube videos or online resources that help with pentesting and Ip sniffing tools? and essentialy all the basics to becomean ethical hacker</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/the-basics-to-master-the-skill-of-ethical-hacking/20750">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/the-basics-to-master-the-skill-of-ethical-hacking/20750</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-20750</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/the-basics-to-master-the-skill-of-ethical-hacking/20750.rss">The basics to master the skill of ethical hacking?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What are y’all’s opinions on programming books?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[bagel]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve never used a book for programming, I’ve always learned by mapping out what I want a program to do and then doing research for each step of the program. So I’m curious, do you prefer learning by book or by using the internet?</p>
            <p><small>27 posts - 24 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/what-are-y-all-s-opinions-on-programming-books/20337">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/what-are-y-all-s-opinions-on-programming-books/20337</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 01:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-20337</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/what-are-y-all-s-opinions-on-programming-books/20337.rss">What are y’all’s opinions on programming books?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Introduction: 4554551N-533K3R</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[4554551N-533K3R]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <h3>What do you go by / What are your common aliases?</h3>
<p>4554551N-533K3R<br>
Ph@nt0m5tr1k3r</p>
<h3>What are your skill sets?</h3>
<p>Coding: C, C++, Python, Golang, Assembly, Java, Perl, PHP, Rust<br>
Reverse Engineering<br>
Exploit Development<br>
Pen Testing/Hacking<br>
Security Architecture<br>
GRC</p>
<h3>What are you interested in?</h3>
<p>All of the above.  I am on a never ending quest to increase my knowledge and refine my skills and tool sets.</p>
<h3>Are you an Info. Sec./Comp. Sci. professional or just a hobbyist?</h3>
<p>Info Sec Professional</p>
<h3>What do you hope to gain from this community?</h3>
<p>Some new ideas and methodologies.  Knowledge to help me refine my skills and build on my existing knowledge.</p>
<h3>What do you hope to contribute to this community?</h3>
<p>I hope to share some of my skills and methodologies with community in hopes of helping others reach a higher level.</p>
<h3>How’d you find us?</h3>
<p>Stumbled across the site while doing some research</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/introduction-4554551n-533k3r/20221">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/introduction-4554551n-533k3r/20221</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 04:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-20221</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/introduction-4554551n-533k3r/20221.rss">Introduction: 4554551N-533K3R</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Life Update Regarding To My Last Post From A Couple Of Months Ago</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[d3m0crxcy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey friends of 0x00sec, the last time I was on this website was back in January. I was in a very, very dark place, and I decided to reach out and make a call-for-help post. If you seen it, it was really depressing… But, about 2 1/2 months have passed, and so many things have changed for me. Let’s go in order, shall we?</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>I have had a really bad past of self-harm that lasted for about 4 years. I officially gave it up back in August 2019, but over those 2 1/2 months that have gone by, I kept on self-loathing, and almost relapsed into the terrible habit. Luckily enough, I didn’t do it. I’m very thankful.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I found Jesus. I been going to church with my parents for about a year now, but back then, I was not involved into religion or God in general and had nothing to do with it. Then around early February this year, something kind of punched my in the face and told me to try it, that it won’t kill me. That kept creeping into my mind for about 2 weeks. So on February 16, the church were playing beautiful song, and I felt my heart pounding. Something told me to go to the altar, and I did. I don’t think I cried that hard in my life. I was just crying, praying, repenting and truly felt the presence of God. It was so, so great, and I felt at peace with myself. It feels so good to call myself a Christian now.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I got accepted into the college I wanted to go into for cybersecurity! I been waiting for a response for months, and to know I got accepted made me feel ecstatic! I can’t wait to go into the dream major I have been wanting!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I’ve learned people can truly love. Right before I was gonna make this post, I took a look at my last post and saw that 4.9 thousand people saw it. To know that many people had the nerve to even read it warmed my heart, and I was crying. So whoever bothered to look at it, reach out, comment and let me know things get better, <em>thank you</em>. My heart is so full.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>0x00sec, you guys have become a little family for me. I am super duper grateful. I appreciate all of you. Depression is still into my system, but I am taking it day by day. I been taking my meds for it, but also praying that I can make it through another day. It’s not as bad as it used to be! I feel very positive right now.</p>
<p>With so much love, (and please stay safe during this chaotic time with the coronavirus!),<br>
<em>-d3m0crxcy</em></p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/life-update-regarding-to-my-last-post-from-a-couple-of-months-ago/19972">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/life-update-regarding-to-my-last-post-from-a-couple-of-months-ago/19972</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 01:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-19972</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/life-update-regarding-to-my-last-post-from-a-couple-of-months-ago/19972.rss">Life Update Regarding To My Last Post From A Couple Of Months Ago</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Being Unsocial (Help regarding balancing personal life)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[landi58]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi,<br>
I am a research engineer at a company (Not a coding job, but it’s related to analyzing patents of Computer science and electronics field. so it’s a technical job). I have great interest in coding but due to my low CGPA in Btech (Computer Science), I am unable to get job in coding field. I am like I don’t live without coding. I spent almost 12 hours of day in my job (job 9 hours +  travelling) so  as soon as i came back home, i open my lapi and start coding. As my job is purely non-coding job, they don’t allow me to even open a coding related website in office on their sytem. So i try to give as much time to coding at home. Due to this, my personal life is going affected. My mom (my family only has me and my mom) said that i not give her enough time and don’t talk to her (or listen to her) much. Further, she said that she will leave me and go home back if my behaviour will be like that (like if i not change my this schedule). But  i have to give more and more time to coding so i am getting detached to her. Further, the topics on which she wants to talk to me are bulshits (like talking about neightbours, etc. which are not of my interest). I apply to many coding companies (S/W development companies) but as i am working for 2+ years in non-coding, they don’t even schedule my interview. But i not leave coding as i already mentioned that i cannot live without coding.</p>
<p>Can anyone please give me some suggestions to change my schedule or behaviour or any thing that i can do to make everyone happy.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/being-unsocial-help-regarding-balancing-personal-life/19077">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/being-unsocial-help-regarding-balancing-personal-life/19077</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 14:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-19077</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/being-unsocial-help-regarding-balancing-personal-life/19077.rss">Being Unsocial (Help regarding balancing personal life)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Happy Australia Day!</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Crqshes]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>To all my fellow Australians hope your all having a great Australia day! <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/australia.png?v=9" title=":australia:" class="emoji" alt=":australia:"></p>
<p><em>(If you aren’t Australian still have a good day <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/slightly_smiling_face.png?v=9" title=":slightly_smiling_face:" class="emoji" alt=":slightly_smiling_face:">)</em></p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/happy-australia-day/18812">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/happy-australia-day/18812</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 09:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-18812</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/happy-australia-day/18812.rss">Happy Australia Day!</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Not Anything Hacking Related, But I&#39;m In a Dark Place</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[d3m0crxcy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The title is self explanatory. I don’t use social media besides this website, and I feel like I’ve met so many kind people on here. I guess this is my call for help.</p>
<p>Last year, around March, a lot of stuff went down hill. Let’s just say I made a lot of mistakes, and it broke my moms heart. I got sent to my dads during that time from March-June, and I’ll be honest, depression really got the best of me. I was miserable every single day, and it got so bad to the point where I wanted to kill myself. As you can see, I didn’t.</p>
<p>I was talking to my mom about some things today, and then somehow I was opening up to how I felt from March-June. She knows that I wanted to end it all, I’ve spoken about it 3 times to her.</p>
<p>“Remember what I told you a while back while we were going to your Pastor’s moms funeral? And how I told you I wanted to…you get the gist?” I asked. We were both already kinda upset at each other.</p>
<p>She said my name, and added, “Don’t try to make me feel bad about it. I’m glad you went up to your dads and faced the stuff you faced. You stupid teenagers are gonna kill yourselves whether I stop you or not. I’m not gonna hold you and say it’s ok when it’s not. It’s an awful spirit. I’m still gonna move on with my life. I’m not gonna mourn and be brought down if you killed yourself.”</p>
<p>I just…my heart is literally shattered. I decided to let things go and practice Elton John’s “Rocketman” on piano, since I am performing it next Friday. At the ending when it repeats “and I think it’s gonna be a long, long time” over and over again, I kinda lost it. I was sobbing really, really badly. <img src="https://0x00sec.org/images/emoji/twitter/confused.png?v=9" title=":confused:" class="emoji" alt=":confused:"></p>
<p>I have no words, actually. I’m opening up to my mom about something so serious, and throughout the 3 times I’ve talked to her about it, not once has she ever held me and told me things would be okay. All I got was a heaven/hell speech, and that it was my fault that all this stuff happened…</p>
<p>Friends of 0x00sec, can I please get some advice?</p>
            <p><small>39 posts - 18 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/not-anything-hacking-related-but-im-in-a-dark-place/18542">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/not-anything-hacking-related-but-im-in-a-dark-place/18542</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 03:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-18542</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/not-anything-hacking-related-but-im-in-a-dark-place/18542.rss">Not Anything Hacking Related, But I&#39;m In a Dark Place</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Happy New Year, everybody</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[d3m0crxcy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey guys. It’s been a while since I been on this website, I been so busy with my work and exams. Thankfully, it’s all done. I hope everyone is enjoying the new year so far, even though it just started. What are your NY resolutions? I can say that mine are:</p>
<p>-give up social media<br>
-stop cussing<br>
-be more loving<br>
-leave the past behind me<br>
-give up weed</p>
<p>Some sound smart, some sound dumb, I know. But personally, I feel like it will all benefit me in the end. I also have some news, I applied for the college I want to go for a few days ago, and I hope I get a response soon. I want to go for cybersecurity/computer science, and I really hope I get in. If I do, I’ll end up only going for 2 years for my AA degree. I been studying a lot lately for it. I know the second semester only ended in December, but I ended will all A’s. I feel so good.</p>
<p>Ok, ok - enough about me. Let’s talk more about you; what are your resolutions for the New Year? Do you plan to stay consistent?</p>
<p>Stay safe, guys.<br>
Cheers.</p>
<ul>
<li>d3m0crxcy</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>16 posts - 9 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/happy-new-year-everybody/18390">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/happy-new-year-everybody/18390</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-18390</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/happy-new-year-everybody/18390.rss">Happy New Year, everybody</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Rules or Otherwise Unfavorable Behavior?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[9lives304]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Philosophy</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m not here to ruffle any feathers, be blackballed, banned, tar and feathered, shunned, obfuscated, castrated, or otherwise 0x00sec socially persecuted…<br>
(Takes a deep breath)<br>
After regurgitating all of that wit just for y’all, I wanted to see if you have a Marketplace page for selling/buying Software and/or Services that may or may not be of questionable legality?  I ask this formally in advance as to not upset the hierarchy by a 1st day 0x00sec ‘Noob’.<br>
-9lives304</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 14:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-18368</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/rules-or-otherwise-unfavorable-behavior/18368.rss">Rules or Otherwise Unfavorable Behavior?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Con, anyone? [padding]</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[tamas_dxw]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Social</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I was just wondering if anyone comes to 44con this week or Bsides Cymru later this month?</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/con-anyone-padding/16152">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/con-anyone-padding/16152</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 21:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>Yes</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-topic-16152</guid>
          <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/con-anyone-padding/16152.rss">Con, anyone? [padding]</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
