<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Making virtual machine go trough VPN connection</title>
    <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/making-virtual-machine-go-trough-vpn-connection/17535</link>
    <description>While I was doing some things on my virtual machine, *Malwarebytes* blocked some proxy connections on my host machine (PC) because of malware. Because I didn&#39;t want to get infected in any way, I though to make all network on that machine go trough VPN on my host machine. 

I have NordVPN and when I connected to it without changing any network settings on virtual machine, programs just couldn&#39;t work (proxy tools). So I though that I need to specify in virtual machine that it should go trough VPN connection.

I tried to set it to *Bridged adapter* - *VPN Tap adapter*, but still programs don&#39;t work.

Does anyone have idea how to propertly set it up so software that uses network actually works? Also, why software doesn&#39;t work when I just connect to VPN on my host machine?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 16:05:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://0x00sec.org/t/making-virtual-machine-go-trough-vpn-connection/17535.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Making virtual machine go trough VPN connection</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This topic was automatically closed 3 days after the last reply. New replies are no longer allowed.</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/making-virtual-machine-go-trough-vpn-connection/17535/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/making-virtual-machine-go-trough-vpn-connection/17535/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 16:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-17535-2</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/making-virtual-machine-go-trough-vpn-connection/17535.rss">Making virtual machine go trough VPN connection</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Making virtual machine go trough VPN connection</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0x00foeg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>While I was doing some things on my virtual machine, <em>Malwarebytes</em> blocked some proxy connections on my host machine (PC) because of malware. Because I didn’t want to get infected in any way, I though to make all network on that machine go trough VPN on my host machine.</p>
<p>I have NordVPN and when I connected to it without changing any network settings on virtual machine, programs just couldn’t work (proxy tools). So I though that I need to specify in virtual machine that it should go trough VPN connection.</p>
<p>I tried to set it to <em>Bridged adapter</em> - <em>VPN Tap adapter</em>, but still programs don’t work.</p>
<p>Does anyone have idea how to propertly set it up so software that uses network actually works? Also, why software doesn’t work when I just connect to VPN on my host machine?</p>
          <p><a href="https://0x00sec.org/t/making-virtual-machine-go-trough-vpn-connection/17535/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://0x00sec.org/t/making-virtual-machine-go-trough-vpn-connection/17535/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 16:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">0x00sec.org-post-17535-1</guid>
        <source url="https://0x00sec.org/t/making-virtual-machine-go-trough-vpn-connection/17535.rss">Making virtual machine go trough VPN connection</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
